<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Exploration and Countermeasures of University Education Management Model Based on Big Data Technology</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Feng</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<email>zf1009@zjiet.edu.cn</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Zhejiang Institute of Economics and Trade</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>310018</postCode>
									<settlement>Hangzhou</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Exploration and Countermeasures of University Education Management Model Based on Big Data Technology</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">7E8CFD3990D6BB5FD6F97F2362C8D478</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1088/1742-6596/1881/2/022099</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Big Data Technology</term>
					<term>Education Management Model</term>
					<term>Machine Learning Algorithm</term>
					<term>Student Education Management</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>In the context of the current rapid development of big data technology, my country's higher education management model has been greatly impacted. The reform of the student education management model in colleges and universities has both positive and negative aspects. This article makes relevant countermeasures to the transformation of college student education management mode in the era of big data, which is also one of the main research contents of this article. This article mainly discusses the teaching management mode of colleges and universities. It first introduces the changes and current situation of the education management mode, and then makes relevant countermeasures to analyze the current situation after the reform. Under this new situation, the development goals of college education management models have also changed, so a new higher-level development goal of college education management under the background of big data is outlined. This article applies the changes of big data in the education management model. The traditional education management model must be difficult to meet the actual needs of the development of the current big data era. Therefore, based on this, this article needs to combine the background of the rapid development of the current era, increase the frequency of communication between students and teachers, improve the professional quality of teachers themselves, actively innovate the theoretical needs of current education management, and establish a more professional education management team. Based on the above-mentioned problems, a combination of machine learning algorithms and electronic icon detection algorithms is proposed. Experimental research results show that there are many problems in the work of traditional university education management mode. The rise of big data has brought severe impact and challenges to it, and it also brought unprecedented opportunities to university education management.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Under the background of the new situation of big data, the realization of the education management function of colleges and universities requires not only advanced and professional management</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>R e t r a c t e d</head><p>The 2nd International Conference on Computing and Data Science (CONF-CDS 2021) Journal of Physics: Conference Series 1881 (2021) 022099 IOP Publishing doi:10.1088/1742-6596/1881/2/022099 2 methods and operating procedures, but also education managers who have modern management skills and are familiar with the laws of education. A professional team with theoretical knowledge and practical skills in education management <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2]</ref>. This article discusses that in the era of big data, university education managers have reflected the need for big data thinking ability in the process of educational management resource acquisition and education management; at the same time, in the educational management practice activities, education managers are also interested in informatization. Educational management models have shown different influences <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Therefore, in the transformation of the higher education management model in the era of big data, the interaction between the big data thinking practice of education managers and the information education management model is very meaningful <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>Each educated object will choose course learning based on its own knowledge reserve and cognition based on its own needs, breaking the limitations of time, location, environment, and way of listening to lessons under the traditional mode of learning. In the process of education and management, students make individual arrangements for learning and implement teaching in accordance with their aptitude. With the rapid rise of various new media or social software, the scope of learning is no longer limited to textbooks, and suitable high-quality educational resources are selected through the information sharing platform, so that education can truly be popularized <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6]</ref>. In the context of the era of big data, the school's traditional education management model has gradually changed. On the contrary, this big data management system cannot completely match the quality of school education <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref>.</p><p>Under the current background of the rapid development of big data, the traditional university student education management model needs to be transformed to a certain extent, combined with current information resources, to optimize itself, so that students can receive more high-quality education Resources <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">9]</ref>. And students can also formulate a corresponding reward system, which can also effectively improve the enthusiasm of teachers' work and promote the smooth development of teachers' work. This outdated education management model will cause certain restrictions on the quality of current university teaching, and even affect the enrollment of the school itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[10]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Method</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Algorithms in Education Management Mode</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>2.1.1</head><p>AdaBoost algorithm. First learn to get the initial processor:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">: → -1, +1 = ≠ = ∑ - (1) Calculate the coefficient of Tm(x): = 1 2 log 1 - % &amp; = ' &amp; , 1, … , ' &amp; , , … , ' &amp; , )<label>(2)</label></formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">' &amp; , = ' * + exp - , = 1,2, … , )</formula><p>After completing the above steps, construct a linear combination of classifiers:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">f x = ∑ +<label>(3)</label></formula><p>The final data cloud processing:</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">T x = sign f x = sing4∑ + 5 (4)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">SIFT Feature Point Generation</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>R e t r a c t e d</head><p>The The Gaussian scale kernel can define the scale space of the image using the convolution operation of the original image and a variable-scale two-dimensional Gaussian function:</p><p>6 , , 7 = 8 , , 97 * ; ,</p><p>Where: G(x, y, k, σ) is the Gaussian function with variable scale; I(x, y) is the original image; k is the amount of scale change.Different Gaussian difference kernels and image convolution are generally used to generate Gaussian difference space: % , , 7 = 8 , , &lt;7 -8 , , 7 * ; , = , , 97 -6 , , 7</p><p>For the detected feature points, calculate the neighborhood gradient histogram and determine its main direction. It should be noted that some feature points not only have main directions but also auxiliary directions, which are very important for the stability of subsequent matching.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Basic Principles of PCA</head><p>The mathematical principle of PCA is as follows: Suppose an n-dimensional vector w represents a mapping vector in the low-dimensional mapping space. After maximizing the data mapping, the variance formula can be obtained as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">max ? @ ∑ A -B (7) min ? CD E A FE &lt;, C, E A E = ;<label>(8)</label></formula><p>Where: tr is the trace of the matrix; A is the covariance matrix. The A expression is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">F = @ ∑ - -A<label>(9)</label></formula><p>PCA is the output, which can be represented by Y=W'X. The optimal W is the eigenvector corresponding to the first k largest eigenvalues of the data covariance matrix as a column vector, and the original dimension of X is reduced to k dimensions. .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">The Establishment of a Priori PCA Algorithm</head><p>First, through the Lagrangian multiplier method, the above data processing can be transformed into an equivalent unconstrained optimization problem:</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">max G H A ∑ H -I H A -1 -H A J -0<label>(10)</label></formula><p>To further optimize the maximum value of the above problem, the maximum projection direction in the orthogonal space is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">max G H A L H s. t. H A H = 1, H A J = 0, H A J = 0<label>(11)</label></formula><p>Generally speaking, a priori direction and a principal direction are searched for the largest projection direction in a space orthogonal to the above k vectors:</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">max G H A L H s. t. H A H = 1, H A J = 0, H A J = 0, = 1, … , 9 -1<label>(12)</label></formula><p>From the Lagrange multiplier method: </p><formula xml:id="formula_11">max G H A ∑ H -I O H A -1 -H A J -0 -P H A J -0 -⋯ -P O@ H A J O@ -0 (13) R e t</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Establishment of Educational Management Classification Model and Experimental Research Design</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">KNN Text Classification Model</head><p>Use text classification algorithms to classify documents. In 1968, Cover and Hart proposed the KNN algorithm. KNN is one of the classic classification methods. It has the advantages of simple implementation and high robustness. It adopts the calculation method of cosine similarity, so that the smaller the angle between the two vectors, the higher the similarity. The calculation formula of cosine similarity is as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">cos S = T•V WTW•WVW = ∑ X Y Z Y [ Y\] ^∑ X Y _ [ Y\] ^∑ Z Y _ [ Y\] (14)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Multi-Objective Constraint Model Establishment</head><p>The problem described in this article meets the following assumptions:</p><p>a) The user knows the type of the submitted task and its subtasks, and the type and time of resources required by the subtasks; b) Some subtasks of a mission need to be executed on the same satellite; c) Each subtask can be processed on any satellite in a subset of available resources; d) The execution order between subtasks can be serial, parallel or mixed mode;</p><p>The multi-objective constraint model of the resource allocation system is:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">Min af = max bcbd max bebf T ec g Min f B = PIN<label>(15)</label></formula><p>We first normalize the function to calculate the dimension and use the linear weighting idea to construct the multi-objective model into a single-objective model. Specifically expressed as:</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">Min f = w f l + w B f B l (16) m | = o p Y q r|p Y q r<label>(17)</label></formula><p>The estimated value can be obtained according to (18).</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">P X|C = ∏ v |m<label>(18)</label></formula><p>Finally, the sample point X is mapped to the category with the largest posterior probability, namely:</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">w = argmax b by m | = o p Y q r|p Y q z (19)</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Experimental Research Objects and Research Design</head><p>In order to be able to further analyze the education management technology of colleges and universities under big data technology, this paper first selected 70 students from the Institute of Economics and Trade to conduct a practical survey, and divided them into two classes using the method of comparison, with an average of 35 students in each class. In addition, the experiment, in order to be able to understand more precisely the way big data technology is used for college education management, analyzes the current situation of practical education management mode in colleges and universities, and summarizes the existing problems. Secondly, check the relevant literature to find out the current situation of the problem and the common problems and causes of domestic colleges and universities. This article takes the the Institute of Economics and Trade as an example, combines theoretical research with practical operations, and finds out the characteristics and shortcomings of current university practical education management under big data technology. This article adopts a research and analysis method that combines theory and actual cases. Based on the analysis of the thinking changes and work transformations brought by big data technology to the field of college student education management, the theory is applied to practice, the current situation of the problem is deeply analyzed, and the big data is explored. Under the background, the countermeasures of the reform in the field of college student education management, and discuss the practical changes of college education management cases after the use of big data theory, so as to truly integrate theory with practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>R e t r a c t e d</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">Results</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Validity Experiment of Adaboost Algorithm</head><p>The main purpose of this article is to first verify the efficiency of the Adaboost algorithm. The experiment in this article first derives data from the original experimental database. By selecting the the Institute of Economics and Trade as the research object, the effective number of their data is 120 and 125. Data The attributes of is distributed between 6 and 8. The types of these data are all 5, so as to record the process of Adaboost algorithm on the two data sets Ag and Dis, M. The experimental data are shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref>  In this paper, in order to be able to perform more refreshingly, except for the change in the data value of log B ) -log B ) { of the evaluation value M during the clustering process, it is represented by a line chart, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1</ref>:  From the above picture, we can see that the educational management theory started in 1960 and the educational management theory papers were released from the very beginning to more than 5,000. However, it is obvious that the number of papers from 2010 to 2015 has increased rapidly. This is also officially under the rise of the era of big data, many scholars have participated in the research of this educational management theory. After 2020, with the era of big data and the wide application of big data, the speed of development will increase.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Building a Big Data Experimental Education Management Platform</head><p>The big data education management platform is a teaching profession and institution specially set up in order to adapt to the changes of the times, and it has obtained the country, and the construction of a big data education management platform is of great benefit to the cultivation of high-tech talents. As an institution, the Big Data Institute's role is to play an integrated role, achieve complementary advantages, and achieve professional education, professional research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>The development of educational management theory has also developed rapidly. From the immaturity at the beginning of the 20th century to the more and more perfect development now, under the continuous progress of this society, education management the theory has been successfully transformed across the ages and meets the requirements of modern educational management theories. However, we must not be satisfied with the current needs. We must constantly change ourselves and discard all the past theories that cannot meet contemporary needs. Looking for some new methods and new educational theories. The new management theory will always be more complete and better than the old one. We increase the direction and want to develop a more efficient and standardized educational management theory.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The 2nd International Conference on Computing and Data Science (CONF-CDS 2021) Journal of Physics: Conference Series 1881 (2021) 022099</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. The trend diagram of the evaluation value M during the clustering process</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2.1990-2020 Educational Management Trends in Colleges and UniversitiesFrom the above picture, we can see that the educational management theory started in 1960 and the educational management theory papers were released from the very beginning to more than 5,000. However, it is obvious that the number of papers from 2010 to 2015 has increased rapidly. This is also officially under the rise of the era of big data, many scholars have participated in the research of this educational management theory. After 2020, with the era of big data and the wide application of big data, the speed of development will increase.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="1,37.50,454.29,520.00,336.41" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>2nd International Conference on Computing and Data Science (CONF-CDS 2021)</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>IOP Publishing</cell></row><row><cell>Journal of Physics: Conference Series</cell><cell>1881 (2021) 022099</cell><cell>doi:10.1088/1742-6596/1881/2/022099</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>r a c t e d</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="3">The 2nd International Conference on Computing and Data Science (CONF-CDS 2021)</cell><cell>IOP Publishing</cell></row><row><cell>Journal of Physics: Conference Series</cell><cell>1881 (2021) 022099</cell><cell cols="2">doi:10.1088/1742-6596/1881/2/022099</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>4</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>and Table 2. recording. Table of data sets Ag, Dis and M</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell></row><row><cell>Dis</cell><cell>5.56</cell><cell>6.31</cell><cell>8.21</cell><cell>12.31</cell><cell>12.03</cell><cell>12.12</cell><cell>19.32</cell><cell>39.21</cell></row><row><cell>Ag</cell><cell>0.71</cell><cell>0.675</cell><cell>1.13</cell><cell>1.27</cell><cell>1.52</cell><cell>1.65</cell><cell>1.73</cell><cell>1.82</cell></row><row><cell>M</cell><cell></cell><cell>11.23</cell><cell>17.25</cell><cell>23.17</cell><cell>23.29</cell><cell>12.59</cell><cell>19.67</cell><cell>21.53</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>List of Ag, Dis and M of the ZF data set</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>8</cell></row><row><cell>Dis</cell><cell cols="8">453.2 431.56 577.34 672.31 898.28 1159.23 1543.62 1907.24</cell></row><row><cell>Ag</cell><cell>73.22</cell><cell cols="7">65.78 155.27 152.68 155.35 171.53 157.79 240.53</cell></row><row><cell>M</cell><cell></cell><cell>1.245</cell><cell>3.775</cell><cell>5.729</cell><cell>4.890</cell><cell>5.675</cell><cell>6.251</cell><cell>6.213</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>R e t r a c t e d</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An effect of big data technology with ant colony optimization based routing in vehicular ad hoc networks: Towards smart cities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Lakshmanaprabu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S S</forename><surname>Rani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Cleaner Production</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="584" to="593" />
			<date type="published" when="1920">2019. APR.20</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Big data technology: developments in current research and emerging landscape</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Enterprise Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Framework of Fault Trace for Smart Substation Based on Big Data Mining Technology. Automation of Electric Power Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Lei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Qing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Hongyu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="91" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internet of Vehicles in Big Data Era</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE/CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">D2D Big Data: Content Deliveries over Wireless Device-to-Device Sharing in Large Scale Mobile Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V C M</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<publisher>IEEE Wireless Communications</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">NOMAD: The FAIR Concept for Big-Data-Driven Materials Science</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Draxl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Scheffler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A smart home energy management system using IoT and big data analytics approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Al-Ali A R</forename><surname>Zualkernan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rashid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>10000 20000 30000 40000 1990S 1995S 2000S 2005S 2010S 2015S 2020S Trend</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Consumer Electronics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="426" to="434" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>MRS Bulletin</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proposal of a Model of Disaster Medical Education for Practical Risk Management and Disaster Nursing: The SINCHI Education Model. Prehospital and disaster medicine: the official journal of the National Association of EMS Physicians and the World Association for Emergency and Disaster Medicine in association with the Acute Care Foundation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shinchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Matsunaga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Fukuyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Degree of Applying the Criteria of Excellence Management in the Light of the EFQM Excellence Model by the Leadership of King Khalid University from the Point of View of Faculty Members</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Almekhlafi</forename><surname>Abduh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sultan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal for Research in Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Towards Responsible Management Education: A Transformational Model</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of higher education and management model based on cognitive anthropology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M Y</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Systems Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="909" to="916" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. DEC</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
