<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Association of Generalized Granuloma Annulare with Autoantibodies</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Joji</forename><surname>Tada</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Akemi</forename><surname>Seno</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Masumi</forename><surname>Veda</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jira</forename><surname>Arata</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yo</forename><surname>Nagao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Division of Dermatology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Okayama Red Cross Hospi- tal</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700</postCode>
									<settlement>Aoe</settlement>
									<region>Okayama</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>M.D</roleName><forename type="first">Oji</forename><surname>Tada</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Dermatology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Okayama University Medical School</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>700</postCode>
									<settlement>Shikata</settlement>
									<region>Okayama</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Dermatology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Okayama University Medical School</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2-5-1, Shikata</addrLine>
									<postCode>700</postCode>
									<region>Okayama</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Association of Generalized Granuloma Annulare with Autoantibodies</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">C98AC65C2CD0ACBBF882F5E131E1F0B1</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received November 26, 1992; accepted for publication January 29, 1993.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:30+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>generalized granuloma annulare</term>
					<term>autoantibody</term>
					<term>antinuclear antibody</term>
					<term>immune complex</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Granuloma annulare is a degenerative disease of the skin histopathologically characterized by focal degeneration of collagen with a surrounding infiltrate of lymphoid cells, histiocytic cells, and multinucleated giant cells. Immunological abnormalities such as delayed-type hypersensitivity and vasculitic origin are suspected in the pathogenesis. We describe three patients with generalized granuloma annulare, in whom autoantibodies, including antinuclear antibody, antithyroid stimulating hormone receptor antibody, and immune complex, were detected.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>Immunological investigations suggest a role for delayed-type hypersensitivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref> or vascular injury <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5)</ref> in the pathogenesis of granuloma annulare. We recendy observed three patients with generalized granuloma annulare, in whom various kinds of autoantibodies were detected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Report of Cases</head><note type="other">Case 1</note><p>A 40-year-old woman had a slightly pruuuc, symmetrical rash of about 5 years duration. It had begun on the right arm and spread to her other arm, trunk, and both legs. Her past history was unremarkable.</p><p>On physical examination, widespread, skincolored or pink, papulonodular lesions were present on the neck, chest, shoulders, back, arms, and thighs (Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>). Some of these lesions had depressed centers and elevated annular borders. Slight en-Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>. Case 1, papulonodular eruptions, some of which have depressed centers and elevated annular borders, on the neck and chest largement of her thyroid gland was recognized. She had fine finger tremors. Routine laboratory results were within normal limits. Serum levels of triiodo-thyronine (normal: 0.75-1.70 ng/ml) and thyroxine (normal: 5.00-12.50 ,ug/dl) were 3.77 ng/ml and 20.70 ,ug/dl, respectively, which indicated hyperthyroidism. Anti-thyroid stimulating hormone receptor antibody was positive and antinuclear antibody was detected at a titer of 1140 with a speckled pattern. She had no antibodies to thyroglobulin, thyroid microsomes, or DNA A skin biopsy specimen taken from the shoulder Treatment with thiamazole improved hyperthyroidism. The skin eruption also disappeared gradually with.very high levels of topical corticosteroids.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Case 2</head><p>A 65-year-old man had a 5-year history of a generalized pruritic eruption, beginning on the dorsa of both hands and slowly spreading to involve the extremities and trunk. Glycosuria had been detected several years previously.</p><p>On physical examination, there were scattered, various-sized, hyperpigmented, dark-red plaques on the dorsa of hands and feet, arms, legs, and trunk. These lesions had atrophic centers and slightly elevated, irregular, ring-like or circinate borders (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2</ref>).</p><p>Routine laboratory values were within normal limits except for a mildly impaired glucose tolerance. Antinuclear antibodies were repeatedly detected at titers ranging from 1140 to 1120 with a speckled pattern. No other autoantibodies were found.</p><p>A biopsy specimen taken from the dorsal aspect of the left hand showed central collagen degeneration, with a surrounding infiltrate of lymphoid cells, histiocytes, and a few giant cells (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref>). Immunophenotyping of T-Iymphocyte populations in the inflammatory infiltrate of the specimen demon-   Very high levels of topical corticosteroids were effective. Blood glucose level was well controlled by diet.</p><p>Case 3 A 60-year-old woman was admitted to our hospital with a one-year history of non-pruritic eruptions, beginning on the thighs and spreading to the trunk and arms. She had gained more than 10 kg in weight in the last ten years and hyperlipidemia had been recently detected.</p><p>On physical examination, widespread skincolored to pink papular lesions were present on the upper arms, back, lateral chest, and thighs. They coalesced from the back to lateral chest, forming large erythematous plaques with an irregular border (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>). No annular lesions were found. She showed no signs or symptoms of autoimmune diseases including rheumatoid arthritis.</p><p>Laboratory tests, including blood cell counts, liver function tests and urinalysis showed no abnormal values. Total cholesterol was 284 mg/dl (normal: 110-267 mg/dl). CRP was 1.2 mg/dl (normal: &lt;0.3 mgldl) and serum level of rheumatoid factor was 70.5 IVlml (normal: &lt;18 IV/ml). Antinuclear antibodies were repeatedly detected at titers ranging from 111280 to 11640 with a speckled or homogeneous pattern. Circulating immune complex level was 3.1 ,ug/ml (normal: &lt;3.0 ,ug/ml). Ratio of CD4/CD8 of peripheral blood was 6.0 (normal: Several skin biopsy specimens were taken; they showed similar changes of minimal collagen degeneration with an infiltration of scattered mononuclear cells (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5</ref>). Immunohistochemically, infiltrated lymphocytes showed the phenotype of helper/inducer T-cells. A few giant cells were found. Immunofluorescence study of the specimen revealed no deposits of immunoglobulins or complements. The skin eruptions gradually disappeared in 6 months without any treatment In parallel with the improvement in cutaneous lesions, abnormal serological findings and deviated subpopulation of peripheral lymphocytes returned almost to their normal ranges.</p><p>Clinical, laboratory, and histopathological features of our patients are summarized in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Generalized granuloma annulare is an uncommon, cutaneous, granulomatous disease. Recently information about generalized granuloma annulare is increasing in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8)</ref>. Recent reports suggest that immunological alterations might play an important role in the pathogenesis of granuloma annulare.</p><p>In a study of 30 patients with localized granuloma annulare, circulating immune complexes have been found in 60% and antinuclear antibodies, in 30% at titers ranging from 1140 to 111280 <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9)</ref>. The higher prevalence of circulating immune complexes and antinuclear antibodies in patients with granuloma annulare over those in normal subjects may support a vasculitic origin of granuloma annulare <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9)</ref>. Another analysis of 100 patients with generalized granuloma annulare pointed out the high incidence of antinuclear antibodies, although the authors do not discuss the meaning of such antibodies in the pathogenesis of granuloma annulare <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref>. In these reports, the prevalence of associated autoimmune diseases was very low. This indicates that positive autoantibodies in patients with granuloma annulare may have a direct relationship with granuloma annulare itself rather than be the consequence of associated autoimmune diseases. Our three patients showed no signs or symptoms of autoimmune diseases such as lupus erythematosus or rheumatoid arthritis. In our third case, circulating immune complex and a high titer of antinuclear antibody were revealed. In adition, the other two patients showed positive antinuclear antibody. Furthermore, the first patient concomitantly had hyperthyroidism with anti-thyroid stimulating hormone receptor antibody. The association of generalized granuloma annulare with thyroiditis and anti-thyroglobulin antibody has been reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10)</ref>, although the relationship between dysfunction of thyroid gland and generalized granuloma annulare was obscure. The abnormal laboratory findings returned to their normal ranges after disappearance of skin lesions in the first and third cases. Two of our patients showed low titers of positive antinuclear antibodies. The role of positive antinuclear antibodies should be investigated in many more patients with granuloma annulare, as low titers of positive antinuclear antibodies in a normal population have been reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref>.</p><p>Umbert, Dabski, and Winkelmann <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6)</ref> believed that granuloma annulare is a type IV delayed hypersensitivity reaction to either locally or systemically acting stimuli from the results of histopathologic, immunopathologic, and ultrastructural studies of granuloma annulare. They proposed that sensitized lymphocytes in the dermis release some cytokines which cause macrophages and histiocytes to sequester in the dermis and release various lysosomal enzymes that partially degrade collagen fibers. <ref type="bibr">Kallioinen et al. (12)</ref> also speculate that cytokines are important mediators of tissue degeneration in granuloma annulare. T-cell subpopulations in granuloma annulare were predominantly identified as helper/inducer cells (2), and the number of 5100 positive dendritic cells within the epidermis and dermis was increased in granuloma annulare <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(13)</ref>. In two of our cases, immunohistochemistry showed the predominance of helper/inducer T-cells in the inflammatory infiltrates. Generalized granuloma annulare has also been described in acquired immunodeficiency syndrome, in which helper/inducer T-cells are much impaired <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14)</ref>.</p><p>The question of an association between generalized granuloma annulare and diabetes mellitus has been discussed extensively without definite conclusions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref>. Our second patient had impaired glucose tolerance and positive antinuclear antibody. Blood glucose values well-controlled by diet had no relationship to the clinical course of his granuloma annulare.</p><p>The two above mentioned hypotheses may be inconsistent in some respects. However, many immunological abnormalities in granuloma annulare are reported, such as elevated circulating immune complexes <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9)</ref>, positive antinuclear antibodies <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9)</ref>, and antithyroid antibodies <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10)</ref> as described in our three cases. These autoantibodies appear to be related to granuloma annulare; their meaning remains to be ascertained.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Case 2, dark-red plaques with circinate borders on the dorsa of the feet</figDesc><graphic coords="2,58.33,63.21,465.00,176.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Case 2, the histological features showing central collagen degeneration with an infiltrate of lymphoid cells, histiocytes, and giant cells (H&amp;E x80).</figDesc><graphic coords="2,313.90,318.77,197.00,301.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Case 3, papular eruption and erythematous plaques on the right lateral chest.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 5 .</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Fig. 5. Case 3, the histological feature showing minimal collagen degeneration (*) with an infiltrate of mononuclear cells (H&amp;E x150).</figDesc><graphic coords="3,56.95,69.71,217.00,332.00" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Clinical, laboratory, and histopathological features in the patients</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Case 1: 40yr Female</cell><cell>Case 2: 65yr Male</cell><cell>Case 3: 60yr Female</cell></row><row><cell>Distribution</cell><cell>Neck, Chest, Back,</cell><cell>Hands, Feet, Extremities,</cell><cell>Trunk, Extremities</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Extremities</cell><cell>Trunk</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Duration</cell><cell>Five years</cell><cell>Five years</cell><cell>One year</cell></row><row><cell>Associated diseases</cell><cell>Hyperthyroidism</cell><cell>Diabetes mellitus</cell><cell>Hyperlipidemia, Obesity</cell></row><row><cell>Histopathological changes</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Collagen alteration</cell><cell>Fragmentation</cell><cell>Fragmentation</cell><cell>Fragmentation</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Hyalinization,</cell><cell>Hyalinization</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Necrobiosis</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Elastic tissue</cell><cell>Loss</cell><cell>Loss</cell><cell>Less</cell></row><row><cell>Histiocyte</cell><cell>Many, Epithelioid,</cell><cell>Many, Epithelioid,</cell><cell>A few</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Multinucleated</cell><cell>Multinucleated</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Aldan blue</cell><cell>Positive</cell><cell>Positive</cell><cell>Positive</cell></row><row><cell>Immunohistochemistry</cell><cell>ND</cell><cell>CD4+ T-cell</cell><cell>CD4+ T-cell</cell></row><row><cell>Direct immunofluorescence</cell><cell>ND</cell><cell>Negative</cell><cell>Negative</cell></row><row><cell>Autoantibodies</cell><cell>Anti-TSHR antibody</cell><cell>ANA (x20~x40 Speckled)</cell><cell>ANA (x640~x1280 Speckled,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ANA (x40 Speckled)</cell><cell></cell><cell>Homogeneous)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Immune complex</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">TSHR: thyroid stimulating hormone receptor, ANA: antinuclear antibody, ND: not done</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Histologic, ultrastructural studies of granuloma annulare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Umbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Winkelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch Dermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1681" to="1686" />
			<date type="published" when="1977">1977</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of T-cell subpopulations in granuloma annulare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Beuchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Winkelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Banks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ArchDermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized granuloma annulare: Histopathology and immunopathology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Dabski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Winkelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am Acad Dermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="39" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Vasculitis in granulo-rna annulare: Histopathology and direct immunofluorescence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ullman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Goltz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ArchDermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="463" to="467" />
			<date type="published" when="1977">1977</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Microangiopathy in cases of granuloma annulare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Haim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shafrir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Haim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lichtig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Dermatologica</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">147</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="1973">1973</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized granuloma annulare: Clinical and laboratory findings in 100 patients</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Dabski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Winkelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AmAcad Dermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Generalized and localized granuloma annulare, Int] Dermatol</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Friedman-Birnbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Muhlbauer jE: Granuloma annulare</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am Acad Dermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="230" />
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Circulating immune complexes in granuloma annulare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Peserico</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Ossi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Salvador</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch Dermatol Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">280</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The association of generalized granuloma annulare with antithyroid antibodies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gross</forename><surname>Pro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shelly</forename><forename type="middle">Wb</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Derm Venereol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1971">1971</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Immunological responses of a healthy elderly population</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Goodwinjs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Searles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ksk</forename><surname>Tung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clin Exp Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="410" />
			<date type="published" when="1982">1982</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collagen synthesis in granuloma annulare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kallioinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sandberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kinnunen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Oikarinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Invest Dermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">98</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="463" to="468" />
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Epidermal dendritic S100 positive cells in necrobiosis lipoidica and granuloma annulare, Br]Dermatol</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chambers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Milligan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fletcher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">123</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="765" to="768" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disseminated granuloma annulare as a presentation of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mcgregor Jm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Mcgibbon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clin Exp Dermatol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
