<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Thermally stable single atom Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 for selective hydrogenation and CO oxidation</title>
				<funder ref="#_z8cAP3h">
					<orgName type="full">Aichi Science &amp; Technology Foundation, Aichi, Japan</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_Kkrjaa5">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_gKgw2Un">
					<orgName type="full">Nagoya University Synchrotron Radiation Research Center</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2017-07-27">27 Jul 2017</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Zailei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>4 Engineering Drive 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>117585</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yihan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Physical Sciences and Engineering Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Advanced Membranes and Porous Materials Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>23955-6900</postCode>
									<country>Thuwal Saudi Arabia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Hiroyuki</forename><surname>Asakura</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Molecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Graduate School of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>615-8510</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Elements Strategy Initiative for Catalysts &amp; Batteries (ESICB)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>615-8245</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bin</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>4 Engineering Drive 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>117585</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jiaguang</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Maoxiang</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>4 Engineering Drive 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>117585</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Dalian Institute of Chemical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Catalysis</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116023</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Physical Sciences and Engineering Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Advanced Membranes and Porous Materials Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>23955-6900</postCode>
									<country>Thuwal Saudi Arabia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Physical Sciences and Engineering Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">KAUST Catalysis Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>23955-6900</postCode>
									<settlement>Thuwal</settlement>
									<country key="SA">Saudi Arabia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tsunehiro</forename><surname>Tanaka</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Molecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Graduate School of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>615-8510</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Elements Strategy Initiative for Catalysts &amp; Batteries (ESICB)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyoto University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>615-8245</postCode>
									<settlement>Kyoto</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Aiqin</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Dalian Institute of Chemical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Catalysis</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116023</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Dalian Institute of Chemical Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">State Key Laboratory of Catalysis</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>116023</postCode>
									<settlement>Dalian</settlement>
									<country key="CN">China</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Ning</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
							<email>ning.yan@nus.edu.sg</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">National University of Singapore</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>4 Engineering Drive 4</addrLine>
									<postCode>117585</postCode>
									<settlement>Singapore</settlement>
									<country key="SG">Singapore</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Thermally stable single atom Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 for selective hydrogenation and CO oxidation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2017-07-27">27 Jul 2017</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">EF11513C1EC0DA5D0E1B44B05078F59F</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/ncomms16100</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 7 Nov 2016 | Accepted 30 May 2017 |</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:33+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Single-atom metal catalysts offer a promising way to utilize precious noble metal elements more effectively, provided that they are catalytically active and sufficiently stable. Herein, we report a synthetic strategy for Pt single-atom catalysts with outstanding stability in several reactions under demanding conditions. The Pt atoms are firmly anchored in the internal surface of mesoporous Al 2 O 3 , likely stabilized by coordinatively unsaturated pentahedral Al 3 þ centres. The catalyst keeps its structural integrity and excellent performance for the selective hydrogenation of 1,3-butadiene after exposure to a reductive atmosphere at 200 °C for 24 h. Compared to commercial Pt nanoparticle catalyst on Al 2 O 3 and control samples, this system exhibits significantly enhanced stability and performance for n-hexane hydroreforming at 550 °C for 48 h, although agglomeration of Pt single-atoms into clusters is observed after reaction. In CO oxidation, the Pt single-atom identity was fully maintained after 60 cycles between 100 and 400 °C over a one-month period.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>E</head><p>lement sustainability has become a global issue. Maintaining current consumption rate, there are 22 elements facing depletion within the coming 50 years, including almost all Platinum Group metals that are crucial catalyst components <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref> . Despite the critical role of Pt in catalysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> , it is rare, in short supply in recent years and has no adequate alternatives. In this regard, single-atom catalysts (or atomically dispersed catalysts), in which all the metal atoms are exposed on the support available for catalytic reactions, could help to address the problem <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> . The electronic properties of isolated metal atoms may be distinctly different from the active sites in bulk materials and nanoparticles, potentially triggering innovative applications and enabling more effective usage of noble metal elements  .</p><p>A challenge in the development of single-atom catalysts is the increasing difficulty to stabilize single-atom species under drastic reaction conditions. Many industrially important catalytic processes involving Pt catalysts, such as reforming of hydrocarbons in petroleum refineries, are operated at several hundred degrees under oxidative or reductive atmosphere <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref> . In this context, single-atom catalysts that are able to withstand harsh reaction conditions are highly desirable. Very recently, Datye and co-workers have illustrated the trapping of atomic Pt species leached from alumina onto the defect sites in rod or polyhedral shaped ceria at 800 °C (ref. 31). Corma et al. reported subnanometric Pt species finely confined within the internal framework cavities of MCM-22, which withstands thermal treatment in air up to 540 °C, and is more stable in propane dehydrogenation than catalysts prepared via the conventional wet-impregnation method <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32</ref> . Flytzani-Stephanopoulos and Sykes et al. developed single-atom alloy catalysts, in which isolated Pt atoms substituted into the Cu(111) surface, that are stable for butadiene hydrogenation at 160 °C for more than 46 h (ref. 33). These examples highlight the importance of manipulating the interactions between metal atoms and the host support to achieve high stability without losing reactivity in single-atom catalysis.</p><p>Herein, we report a highly stable, atomically dispersed Pt catalyst supported on mesoporous Al 2 O 3 . The Pt À Al À O system is chosen because Al 2 O 3 is a common support for Pt in industrial and environmental applications. The catalyst was prepared by a modified sol-gel solvent vaporization self-assembly method <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34</ref> , followed by calcination in air and reduction with H 2 . Encouragingly, the catalyst maintained the catalytic activity as well as structural integrity when scrutinized in a series of reactions under drastic conditions with long durations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Catalyst synthesis and characterization. In the first step, C 9 H 21 AlO 3 , (EO) 20 (PO) 70 (EO) 20 triblock copolymer (P123) and H 2 PtCl 6 were mixed and dissolved in ethanol. With continued evaporation of the solvent, the amphiphilic P123 macromolecules associated with C 9 H 21 AlO 3 spontaneously assembled into a highly ordered, hexagonally arranged mesoporous structure with Pt precursor encapsulated in the matrix. The resulting gel was calcined in air at 400 °C, during which the P123 template decomposed while the C 9 H 21 AlO 3 was transformed into a rigid, well-aligned mesoporous Al 2 O 3 framework (m-Al 2 O 3 , as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>). The reductive behaviour of Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 over H 2 was determined from their temperature-programmed reduction (TPR) profiles (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>). A single reduction peak located at approximately 400 °C was observed for the 0.2 wt% Pt loading sample, while two peaks appeared for the 0.5 and 2.0 wt% Pt loading samples. Based on TPR profiles, 400 °C was selected as the unified reducing temperature. After reduction, ICP-OES analysis indicates the Pt loading of the samples to be 0.20, 0.48 and 1.93 wt%, respectively, in excellent agreement with the amount of the Pt precursor used (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref>).</p><p>The pre-catalysts and catalysts were labelled in the following manner: Pt weight percentage, nature of the support (for example, m-Al 2 O 3 , referring to mesoporous Al 2 O 3 ), and treatment atmosphere. For instance, 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 refers to 0.2 wt% Pt supported on mesoporous Al 2 O 3 which was calcined in air at 400 °C without reduction, whereas 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 refers to 0.5 wt% of Pt on mesoporous Al 2 O 3 , consecutively calcined in air and reduced with H 2 at 400 °C. FT-IR spectra (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">2</ref>) suggest complete removal of the P123 triblock copolymer and the ligand of aluminium isopropoxide in all samples. Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref> provides a photo of the aforementioned samples: 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 are grey, while the others are black. This contrasts with pure m-Al 2 O 3 which is light yellow. Organic elemental analysis suggested the presence of nitrogen (0.97 wt%) and carbon (0.79 wt%) in 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 whereas the content of these elements became negligible in 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">2</ref>).</p><p>The samples were subsequently investigated by scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) with high-angle annular dark-field (HAADF), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), Brunauer-Emmett-Teller (BET) surface area analysis, H 2 -O 2 and CO titration, diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transform spectroscopy (DRIFTS), <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al magic-angle spinning nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy (MAS NMR), X-ray diffraction (XRD) and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) to probe the characteristics of the support and the Pt species. These materials exhibit similar surface areas (200.6 to 227.3 m 2 g À 1 ), pore volumes (0.51 to 0.56 ml g À 1 ), and a diffraction peak at around 0.8°in the small-angle XRD pattern, unambiguously proving the mesoporous structure (Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5</ref>, Supplementary Table <ref type="table">3</ref>). No Pt peaks are detected from XRD patterns in 0</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 ,</formula><p>suggesting that most Pt species are present in small nanoclusters and/or isolated atoms. Weak diffraction peaks for Pt are found on 2.0Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 2.0Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , indicating the formation of Pt nanoparticles (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">6</ref>).</p><p>Consistent with BET and XRD analysis, the TEM images of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 show well-aligned, mesoporous Al 2 O 3 without any Pt nanoparticles (Fig. <ref type="figure">2a,</ref><ref type="figure">b</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7a-d</ref>), and TEM-EDS images reveal that Pt is uniformly dispersed throughout the sample (Fig. <ref type="figure">2c</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7e</ref>). Indeed, HAADF-STEM technique clearly demonstrates the existence of isolated Pt atoms with high number density in 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Fig. <ref type="figure">2d</ref>) and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 (Fig. <ref type="figure">2f</ref>). This is remarkable, since 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 was even treated at 400 °C in the presence of H 2 . Apart from the dominant amount of isolated atoms, a few small clusters that exhibit considerable structural dynamics under electron beam were also observed. A snapshot image (Fig. <ref type="figure">2g,</ref><ref type="figure">h</ref>) shows that the cluster has loosely packed atoms with the interatomic distances longer than those observed in metallic Pt <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref> . However, it is difficult to affirm whether these small clusters are formed by loose packing of single Pt atoms, or by electron beam-induced fragmentation of the close packed structure. More images and intensity profiles of Pt species in these samples can be found in Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure">8</ref> and<ref type="figure">9</ref>. The numbers of atoms for the nearest neighbour distance from 525 single atoms identified on 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 532 single atoms identified on 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 were analysed (Fig. <ref type="figure">2e</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">9c</ref>), showing that a vast majority of Pt atoms are well separated from each other (distance Z 0.5 nm). Not surprisingly, Pt nanoclusters and nanoparticles are observed in samples with 0.5 and 2.0 wt% Pt loading. In addition, the enhanced Pt content is detrimental to the formation of high quality hexagonally arranged mesoporous Al 2 O 3 (Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure">10</ref> and<ref type="figure">11</ref>). Extended X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy (EXAFS) provides important evidence on the dispersion of Pt species on m-Al 2 O 3 . The Pt-Pt contribution at about 2.7 Å is absent in the k 3 -weighted EXAFS at the Pt L 3 -edge for either 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 or 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3a</ref>), strongly indicating that Pt exists predominantly as isolated atoms. The only prominent shell located at approximately 1.7 Å arises from Pt-O contribution, which is consistent with HAADF-STEM observation. At increased Pt loading (0.5 and 2.0 wt%), both Pt-O and Pt-Pt shells are present (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">12</ref>). The FT-EXAFS curves and the fitting results are summarized in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3d</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">13</ref>, Supplementary Table <ref type="table">4</ref>. The fitted Pt-O coordination number for both 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 is 3.8-4.0, implying that each Pt atom coordinates with four oxygen atoms on the support regardless of whether the sample has been reduced or not <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> . Notably, the four-coordination mode is inherently preferred by zero or low valent Pt complexes, which partially explains the high stability of the Pt single-atom catalyst in the system. The electronic state of Pt species was investigated by X-ray absorption near edge structure analysis (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3b</ref>). The spectra exhibit a decreasing trend in the white-line intensities at  m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3e</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">15b</ref>) consumed 2.7 equivalent H 2 per mole of Pt, much higher than the samples with 0.5 and 2.0 wt% Pt loading (0.8-1.3 equivalent H 2 per mole of Pt) (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">15c-f</ref>), demonstrating the excellent dispersion and reactivity of Pt atoms towards O 2 and H 2 at 0.2 wt% Pt loading. The CO adsorption behaviour of the samples using DRIFTS was also investigated. For 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3f</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">16a</ref>), a narrow, quasi-symmetrical band at around 2,087 cm À 1 is observed, which can be rationally ascribed as linearly adsorbed CO on Pt <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40</ref> . For Pt nanoparticles supported on a-Al 2 O 3 , CO stretching frequencies below 2,100 cm À 1 have been rigorously assigned to metallic adsorption sites on nanoparticle surfaces at either well-coordinated (B2,090 cm À 1 ) or undercoordinated (B2,070 cm À 1 ) Pt sites <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41</ref> , but CO adsorbed on Pt d þ single-atom sites may also exhibit a peak in this region.</p><p>In fact, the adsorption strength and DRIFT-IR peak of CO on Pt 1 sites are highly dependent on the system. While Pt À ions that are transformed from PtCl 6  2 À ions via ethanol reduction, forming a colourless complex (photo of these mixture solutions in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">18</ref> and electrospray ionization mass spectrometry spectra in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">19</ref>). High dosage of the C 9 H 21 AlO 3 complex agent helps to restrain the Pt atoms through effectively coordinating Al 3 þ species, preventing aggregation during selfassembly and calcination. Indeed, a mixture of Pt single-atoms and nanoparticles was obtained on m-Al 2 O 3 (0.2 wt% Pt) by the conventional wet-impregnation method (sample abbreviated as 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -imp)-the only difference being that the Pt precursor was introduced on pre-formed m-Al 2 O 3 instead of being added at the beginning (Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure">20</ref> and<ref type="figure">21</ref>).</p><p>The Al 2 O 3 mesoporous structure and the associated unique surface environment play a vital role on the stability of atomically dispersed Pt. Three prominent peaks at 7, 38 and 70 p.p.m. are present in the <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS NMR spectra (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3g</ref>) for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , which can be assigned as Al 3 þ species in tetrahedral (AlO 4 at 7-10 p.p.m.), pentahedral (AlO 5 at 38 p.p.m.) and octahedral (AlO 6 at 70 p.p.m.) coordination, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42</ref> . It is worth noting that only two signals at 10 and 70 p.p.m. are present for commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 . By comparing with the <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MQ NMR spectra of the gel and C 9 H 21 AlO 3 , we find that pentahedrally coordinated Al 3 þ species mainly form in calcination and reduction processes (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">22a</ref>). As such, the presence of a high concentration of pentahedrally coordinated Al 3 þ species, accounting for more than one-third of Al 3 þ species in m-Al 2 O 3 based on recovery time and twodimensional <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al multiple quantum NMR measurement (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3h</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">22b-d</ref>), is a direct consequence of the high quantity of defects induced by the mesoporous structure of the framework. Further NMR analysis comparing the spectra of fresh, dry sample and the sample after exposure to air revealed that a majority of Al V species stay in the bulk (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">22f,</ref><ref type="figure">g</ref>). Despite of its low abundance on surface, Al V species may be critical to keep 0.2 wt% Pt atomically dispersed. Indeed, it has been elegantly and well established that unsaturated pentacoordinate Al 3 þ centres on Al 2 O 3 surface can strongly anchor atomically dispersed Pt species <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42</ref> . Considering there is no direct bonding between Al and Pt in EXAFS spectrum, Pt atoms plausibly bind to these sites via oxygen bridges <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35</ref>   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">23</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">24</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">25</ref>). Interestingly, 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 is a luminescent material under UV light irradiation whereas 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 is not (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3i</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32</ref> .</p><p>The thermal stability of 0.2 wt% Pt supported on m-Al 2 O 3 and p-Al 2 O 3 was further investigated by calcination at 600 and 800 °C in air for 4 h. XRD patterns, BET analysis and their pore size distribution curves (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">26</ref>), TEM images (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">27</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> , Al MAS-NMR spectra and IR spectra of CO absorption (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">28</ref>) indicate that m-Al 2 O 3 preserved its mesoporous structure and surface area, with a majority of Pt species maintaining single-atom identities. Noteworthy, Pt can be emitted as volatile PtO 2 at 800 °C under oxidative conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> . However, the Pt content remained at around 0.2 wt% after thermal treatments at 600 and 800 °C (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref>), highlighting Pt is strongly anchored in m-Al 2 O 3 in the material. On the other hand, p-Al 2 O 3 exhibited decreased surface area, diminished pentahedral unsaturated Al 3 þ centres and collapsed porous structure after high temperature treatment. Meanwhile, the Pt species in p-Al 2 O 3 was largely transformed into nanoparticles. These control experiments indicate that the mesoporous structure and the unique interior surface framework of m-Al 2 O 3 play a decisive role for efficient stabilization of atomically dispersed Pt.</p><p>Catalytic activity: Selective hydrogenation reactions. The activity and selectivity of single-atom Pt catalysts were investigated over a series of reactions in the presence of H 2 , including the hydrogenation of nitrobenzene <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43</ref> , acetophenone <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44</ref> , phenylacetylene <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36</ref> and 1,3-butadiene <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33</ref> (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">30</ref> and Supplementary Tables <ref type="table">5</ref><ref type="table">6</ref><ref type="table">7</ref>). In all cases, excellent yields of desired products were obtained. For instance, 98.7% selectivity to 1-phenylethanol in the hydrogenation of acetophenone was achieved over 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , which is higher than 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (78.9%) and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 (68.3%) (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">5</ref>). The excellent activity and selectivity not only highlight the applicability of the catalyst for hydrogenation reactions, but are encouraging testimonies of the single-atom identity and the positively charged nature of Pt species on m-Al 2 O 3 (ref. 36). Aromatic ring normally coordinates to multiple metal atoms before undergoing hydrogenation, and remain to interact with metal surface during step-wise hydrogenation <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45</ref> . This mechanism is not possible over single-atom catalysts, which satisfactorily explains why ring hydrogenation on 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 was almost fully suppressed. In contrast, positively charged Pt species favours C ¼ O bond adsorption and activation forming an Z 1 (O) configuration, as previously established on Pt nanoparticle catalysts <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47</ref> . In our system, Z 1 (O) acetophenone adsorbed on Pt single-atom site plausibly reacts with spilled-over hydrogen to form 1-phenylethanol. Afterwards the product transfers to Al 2 O 3 support where it is more strongly adsorbed before finally diffuses into the solution phase <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47</ref> , leading to regeneration of the Pt site for a new cycle.</p><p>Next, selective hydrogenation of 1,3-butadine were studied in detail to investigate the stability of our single-atom Pt catalysts in reductive atmosphere at elevated temperatures. 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 transformed 1,3-butadiene into butenes with 499% selectivity at 50 °C, without affecting the co-feed propylene molecule. The TOF for butane formation is 0.034 s À 1 , a few times higher than earlier reported Pt 1 Cu catalyst under comparable condition (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">8</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33</ref> . 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts, on the other hand, exhibited much lower selectivity (77 and 29%, respectively) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4a</ref>, Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">31</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">32</ref>). To evaluate the long-term stability of these catalysts under H 2 atmosphere at high temperature, the three catalysts were exposed to the mixture of gas reagents at 200 °C for 24 h (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4b</ref>, Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">33</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">34</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">35</ref>). Afterwards, their catalytic performances were re-evaluated at 30 °C for 12 h. Remarkably, 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 even exhibited slightly increased activity and near-quantitative selectivity towards butenes, confirming the preservation of Pt active sites after high temperature treatment (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4c</ref>, Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">33</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">34</ref><ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">35</ref>), whereas 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 dropped in activity and selectivity. To our delight, a number of well-separated Pt atoms are clearly identified by HAADF-STEM on spent 0.2Pt/ m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalyst, with no visible Pt atom aggregation being observed (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4d</ref>, Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">36</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">37</ref>). The IR spectrum of CO adsorption on 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 shows a single sharp peak at 2,090 cm À 1 , substantiating HAADF-STEM finding that Pt species remain predominantly isolated. The major CO absorption peak on spent 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalyst, on the other hand, shifts to 2,064 cm À 1 suggesting significant formation of Pt nanoparticles (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4e</ref>).</p><p>Catalytic activity: n-hexane reforming. Most Pt catalysts for high temperature applications under reductive conditions are related to oil refining. The hydro-reforming of n-hexane provides a good model reaction to understand the catalytic conversion of linear hydrocarbons into branched isomers under H 2 which is a vital reaction for fuel and chemical production from naphtha. Typically, n-hexane reacts via four major pathways: cracking to shorter chain hydrocarbons; isomerization to 2-methylpentane, 3-methylpentane and multi-branched isomers; cyclization to methylcyclopentane or cyclohexane; and aromatization to benzene (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">38</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">48</ref> . One critical requirement in this process is to achieve long durability against deactivation via preventing carbon deposition. Previous studies were focused on Pt nanoparticles <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49</ref> , whereas little attention has yet been paid to single-atom catalysts. We compared the performance of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts for n-hexane reforming at 400 and 550 °C. The conversion of n-hexane was maintained below 30% in all cases to ensure that the reaction is under kinetic control. While the initial activities (reflected by n-hexane conversion) of the three catalysts at both 400 and 550 °C were similar, the selectivity of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 towards desired isomeric products was the highest among the three (ca. 50%), in particular at 550 °C (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4f</ref>, Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">39</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">40</ref>). The superior selectivity of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalyst for branched products is likely due to the strong interaction between Pt and support, which is known to be critical for n-hexane isomerization <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29</ref> . 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts were subjected to long-term stability tests. Under both 400 and 550 °C, the stability of the 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalyst, reflected by the substrate conversion, was superior than other catalysts. Its final activity merely dropped to 88% compared to the activity of the fresh catalyst after reacting at 550 °C for 48 h. In contrast, a staggering decrease of activity to 50% for 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after 48 h and to 38% for commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 after 24 h was observed (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4f</ref>). The deactivation rates of the three catalysts were generated by curve fitting the conversion as a function of time, followed by differentiation. 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 exhibited a horizontal line suggesting negligible deactivation whereas 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts continued to drop in activity (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4g</ref>). The selectivity for isomeric products remained relatively constant for all samples, with 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 being the most selective (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4h,</ref><ref type="figure">i</ref>).</p><p>There are no detectable Pt nanoparticles in the TEM images for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after reacting for 48 h at 400 and 550 °C (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">41</ref>), but a number of Pt nanoparticles were identified on 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">42</ref>) and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 (Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure">29</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">43</ref>) after the reaction. In addition, 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 had more carbon deposition than 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 from TEM images, thermogravimetry (TG) measurements (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">44</ref>) and visual inspection (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">45</ref>). BET analysis and <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS-NMR spectroscopy reveal insignificant changes of mesopores as well as Al species on 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 . Serious damage of the porous structure on 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 was however observed after reaction (BET analysis in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">46</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS-NMR spectra in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">47</ref>). Nevertheless, obvious changes in CO adsorption IR spectra are found for all samples. The CO absorption band broadened on 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , with the main peak shifting from 2,089 to 2,084 cm À 1 , together with a shoulder peak at 2,060 cm À 1 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">48</ref>). Meanwhile, there is a significant drop of Pt-O coordination number from 3.6 to 1.1 (after reaction at 400 °C) and 1.4 (after reaction at 550 °C), with concurrent increase of Pt-Pt coordination number to around 6 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">49</ref> and Supplementary Table <ref type="table">4</ref>). These suggested the formation of Pt 0 nanoparticles/nanoclusters after reaction, but there is still a substantial amount of isolated Pt atoms in the catalyst. On the other hand, only a single band at 2,060 cm À 1 can be observed for commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 and 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalysts, ascribed to linearly bonded CO on Pt 0 sites on nanoparticles (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">50</ref>).</p><p>Catalytic activity: CO oxidation. CO oxidation. To evaluate the catalyst stability under oxidative conditions, CO oxidation between 100 and 400 °C was conducted. While thermally stable Pt nanoparticle catalysts for CO oxidation have been developed <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30</ref> , high temperature Pt single-atom catalysts have been much less studied <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31</ref> . A feed gas containing 2.5 vol% CO, 2.5 vol% O 2 and balance Ar was passed through the reactor at a flow rate of 80 ml min À 1 (corresponding to a space velocity of 4.8 Â 10 7 ml h À 1 g À 1 pt , Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">51</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">52</ref>). The TOF was 0.023 s À 1 at 200 °C and steadily increased to 0.175 s À 1 at 250 °C (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">9</ref>). These numbers well match those of a Pt 1 catalyst on y-Al 2 O 3 (0.013 s À 1 at 200 °C and 0.187 s À 1 at 250 °C) <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">50</ref> . In the recycling experiment (100-400 °C), the activity of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 increased slightly in the first 13 rounds, and then became very stable in the subsequent 37 cycles (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5a</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">51</ref>). The temperature of the reactor was then fixed at 400 °C for 220 h, during which 100% CO conversion was maintained for the entire period (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5b</ref>). Afterwards, the 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 spent catalyst was inspected again in recycling experiments (100-400 °C). The conversiontemperature curves for 50th-60th cycles fully resemble those collected before long-term treatment at 400 °C, and this convincingly demonstrates exceptionally high catalytic stability (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5c</ref>). Finally, the temperature of the reactor was set at 230 °C-deliberately selected for an incomplete CO conversionand maintained for 70 h (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5d</ref>). No appreciable drop in CO conversion was detected.</p><p>The spent 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalyst after the abovementioned reaction sequence-corresponding to an exposure to reaction conditions for over a month-was thoroughly interrogated by a series of instrumental analysis. No Pt nanoparticles can be detected from the TEM image and TEM-EDS elemental mapping, indicating that Pt species is uniformly dispersed on spent 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">53a-d</ref>). The CO absorption peak remains sharp and quasi-symmetrical, centred at 2,090 cm À 1 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5e</ref>). In the EXAFS spectrum, Pt-O contribution located at approximately 1.7 Å remains as the only prominent shell, unarguably proving that Pt largely maintains single-atom identity (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5f</ref>, Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">53e</ref>). While the white line intensity (1.64) and Pt-O coordination number (3.6) remain almost identical after reaction, an increase in Debye-Waller factor was observed, reflecting some degree of evolution of catalyst active centre (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">4</ref>). BET analysis and the <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS-NMR spectrum confirm the integrity of the mesoporous structure, and the preservation of a majority of unsaturated pentahedral Al 3 þ species (Supplementary Figs <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">53f</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">54</ref>).</p><p>Similar recycling results were observed over 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 catalyst under dilute conditions (100 mg 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 mixed with 1.0 g commercial Al 2 O 3 , Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">55</ref>).   <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">58</ref>). The Pt species underwent agglomeration in these control samples to form larger particles as shown in TEM images (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">59</ref>). BET and TEM analysis also suggest decreased surface area with collapsed porous structures.</p><p>The CO adsorption experiment on spent commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 and 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 reveals the relative decrease of the peak at 2,090 cm À 1 with increase of the peak at about 2,064 cm À 1 , corroborating TEM findings (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">5e</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The metal-support interactions often play a pivotal role in shaping the stability and reactivity of supported metal catalysts <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">52</ref> . This effect is more pronounced and even becomes the determining factor in single-atom catalysts, considering isolated metal atoms are in sole contact with the support. Strong interactions between the metal atom and the support are conceived to be the key to preventing metal atom aggregation <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">6</ref> , while an overly strong interaction may lead to catalytically inactive species acting as spectators. In some earlier works <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">43</ref> , atomically dispersed Pt catalysts were obtained at low-temperature reduction conditions, and could be used in mild hydrogenation reactions. Unfortunately, atom aggregation into clusters and nanoparticles could occur when the catalysts are exposed to increased reduction temperature, or employed in harsher reaction conditions, plausibly due to insufficient anchoring effect of the support to Pt atoms.</p><p>In the current work, we have developed an atomically dispersed Pt catalyst supported on mesoporous Al 2 O 3 exhibiting astounding catalytic activity and stability under both oxidative and reductive atmospheres at high temperatures. The complex effect between the metal and support precursors enables the Pt cation to be strongly anchored in the inner surface of the support, staying in a four oxygen coordination mode that is intrinsically favoured by low valent Pt atoms. Additionally, the P123 template facilitates the formation of highly stable mesoporous structures enriched with unsaturated pentahedral Al 3 þ centres, further enhancing metal-support interactions. As a result, the singleatom catalyst can survive for long durations in a series of reactions under demanding conditions. An apparent limitation of the system is that the single-atom identity of Pt was achieved only at a low loading (0.2 wt%), plausibly due to the low abundance of Al V species on surface. Nevertheless, our work adds solid proof that the single-atom catalyst may not be necessarily more vulnerable than nanocluster and nanoparticle catalysts under harsh reaction conditions. Rational control of the structure and surface property of the support, and fine-tuning of the synthetic procedure, are two key factors to achieve desirable metal atom-support interactions in atomically dispersed Pt catalysts for high temperature operations with superior activity and stability. For the current system, future work should be directed to enriching Al V species on the surface by tuning the synthetic procedure, and/or incorporate other metal oxides such as silica and titania to the alumina support.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Catalysts synthesis. In a typical synthesis, Pluronic P123 (2.1 g) was dissolved in ethanol (20 ml) at room temperature. Then, 67% nitric acid (3.2 ml) and aluminium isopropoxide (4.08 g) were also dissolved in ethanol (20 ml). The two solutions were mixed under vigorous stirring <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">34</ref>  Catalysts characterization. Wide-angle XRD analysis was carried out using a Bruker D8 Advance X-Ray Diffractometer, at a scan rate of 2°min À 1 . It was operated at 40 kV applying a potential current of 30 mA. The microscopic features of the samples were characterized using a TEM equipped with EDX (JEM-2100F) operated at 200 kV. STEM images were acquired on a Cs-corrected FEI Titan G2 60-300 Microscope operated at 300 kV using an HAADF detector. TG analysis was performed using an EXSTAR TG/DTA 6300 (Seiko Instruments) at a heating rate of 5 °C min À 1 in air. The porous nature of the samples was investigated by measuring the physical adsorption of nitrogen at a liquid-nitrogen temperature of À 196 °C using an automatic volumetric sorption analyzer (NOVA3200e, Quantachrome). Electrospray ionization mass spectrometry spectra were obtained from a Bruker MicroTOF-Q system. The samples were directly injected into the chamber at 20 ml min À 1 . Typical instrument parameters: capillary voltage, 4 kV; nebulizer, 0.4 bars; dry gas, 2 l min À 1 at 120 °C; m/z range, 40-3,000. The <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS NMR measurements were carried out on a Varian 300 MHz NMR spectrometer using a 7.5 mm HX MAS probe with a spinning rate of 13 kHz at resonance frequencies of 156 MHz. ICP-OES analysis was conducted on iCAP 6000 series inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectrometry. The catalysts were digested in aqua regia (HCl/HNO 3 ¼ 3:1) at 373 K for 6 h and then diluted with deionized water to a certain volume before analysis. DRIFTS measurements were performed on a Thermo Scientific Nicolet iS50 instrument with an Hg-Cd-Te (MCT) detector, and a Praying Mantis high temperature reaction chamber with ZnSe windows. TPR, H 2 -O 2 and CO titration analyses were conducted on a ChemBET Pulsar TPR/TPD (Quantachrome). Pt L 3 -edge XAS spectra of Pt catalysts and reference samples were recorded at the BL5S2 beamline at the AichiSR (Aichi Synchrotron Radiation Center, Aichi, Japan) or at the BL01B1 beamline at the SPring-8. Data analysis was carried out with Athena and Artemis included in the Demeter package. For curve fitting analysis of EXAFS spectra, each theoretical scattering path was generated with FEFF 6.0 L. The k 3 -weighted EXAFS oscillation in the range of 3.0-12 Å À 1 was Fourier transformed. GC analysis was performed using an Agilent 7890 GC equipped with FID detector with two capillary columns: JW-CYCLODEX-B 30 m, 0.25 mm and JW-GS-ALUMINA/KCl 50 m, 0.53 mm. Another Agilent 7890 GC is equipped with a TCD detector and also two columns: G3591-80004 6Ft HayeSep Q 80/100 and G3591-80022 8Ft MolSieve 5A 60/80. GC-MS data were obtained using an Agilent Technologies 7890 GC with 5975 MSD. Catalytic activity evaluation. All reactions were evaluated in a fixed-bed reactor under ambient pressure with online GC detection, and the samples were grinded before the tests.</p><p>CO oxidation. 100 mg catalyst was loaded into the reactor tube. Then it was either calcined in air at 400 °C for 1 h or reduced in-situ with 5 vol% H 2 /N 2 at 400 °C for 1 h. After cooling to room temperature, the feed gas containing 2.5 vol% CO, 2.5 vol% O 2 and balance Ar was allowed to pass through the reactor at a flow rate of 80 ml min À 1 (corresponding to a space velocity of 2.4 Â 10 7 ml h À 1 g À 1 pt (6.7 Â 10 3 ml s À 1 g À 1 pt ), specific rate of 7.4 Â 10 À 3 mol CO g À 1 Pt s À 1 (1.4 mol CO mol À 1 Pt s À 1 ) or 1.5 Â 10 À 5 mol CO g À 1 cat s À 1 (2.9 Â 10 À 3 mol CO g À 1 Pt s À 1 )). In every reaction cycle, the temperature increased from 100 to 400 °C with ca. 50 °C interval and stabilized at each temperature for 20 min before measuring the CO conversion and the CO 2 generation. Once a cycle was finished, the reactor was cooled to room temperature to start a new cycle.</p><p>Selective hydrogenation. The as-synthesized pre-catalyst was reduced in H 2 at 400 °C for 1 h before the reaction. A gas mixture of 2% 1,3-butadiene, 20% propylene, 16% H 2 and balance He at a flow rate of 20 ml min À 1 was introduced at ascending temperature (30-200 °C). GC analysis was done at a few selected temperatures after stabilization at that point for at least 10 min. The deactivation test was performed at 200 °C for 24 h using 200 mg catalyst, after which the catalyst was re-evaluated at 30 °C.</p><p>Reforming. Three hundred milligrams catalysts were loaded into the reactor. The catalyst was pretreated at 400 and 550 °C for 1 h in pure H 2 . The reforming reaction was conducted with 0.1 ml h À 1 of n-hexane feeding carried by a syringe pump, and 6 ml min À 1 pure H 2 at 400 °C or 550 °C. Each temperature was maintained for 48 h. In addition to online GC analysis, the products were also collected in an ice-cooled cold trap for GC-MS analysis.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 |Figure 2 |</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 1 | Schematic illustration of the 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 synthesis process. Aluminum isopropoxide, P123, and H 2 PtCl 6 mixture ethanolic solution self-assembled into a gel after ethanol evaporation at 60 °C. The gel was calcined at 400 °C and reduced in 5% H 2 /N 2 at 400 °C, forming the single atom catalyst 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 .</figDesc><graphic coords="3,114.65,63.13,75.17,105.02" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 |</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3 | Characterization of the Pt single-atom and other control samples. (a) The k 3 -weighted Fourier transform of EXAFS spectra derived from EXAFS, n ¼ 3.0-12.0 Å À 1 , (b) normalized XANES spectra at the Pt L 3 -edge of Pt foil, H 2 PtCl 6 , and PtO 2 , 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , (c) schematic illustration of individual Pt atom located on the surface of m-Al 2 O 3 for sample 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , (d) FT-EXAFS curves between the experimental data and the fit, (e) H 2 -O 2 titration profiles, (f) IR spectra of CO adsorbed after the desorption processes for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , (g) the 27 Al MAS-NMR spectra of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 , (h) relative intensity changes of tetra-, penta-and octa-coordinated Al 2 O 3 with recovery time for a spin-lattice relaxation measurement of Al 2 O 3 for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , (i) photographs of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 under visible light and UV light (365 nm).</figDesc><graphic coords="4,398.57,346.45,111.80,95.30" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 |</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4 | Evaluation of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and control catalysts in 1,3-butadiene hydrogenation and n-hexane reforming reaction. (a) The selectivity of butenes and conversion of propene at 30 and 50 °C, (b) the selectivity of butenes and the conversion of 1,3-butadiene at 200 °C for 24 h, (c) the selectivity of butenes and conversion of propene at 30 °C for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 , after the entire reaction sequence, (d) an HAADF-STEM image for 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after the entire reaction sequence, and (e) CO adsorption IR spectra for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2O 3-H 2 after the entire reaction sequence, (f) the conversion of n-hexane at 400 and 550 °C, (g) the catalysts deactivation at 550 °C, (h) the isomerization selectivity at 400 °C, and (i) the isomerization selectivity at 550 °C for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts. The reaction was conducted in a gas mixture of 2% 1,3-butadiene, 20% propene, 16% H 2 and balance He at a flow rate of 20 ml min À 1 , 0.1 ml h À 1 n-hexane and 6 ml min À 1 pure H 2 at ambient pressure. Scale bar, 2 nm (d).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 5 |</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5 | Evaluation of 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and control catalysts in CO oxidation. (a) Conversion of CO from 100 to 400 °C with 1st-50th cycles, (b) maintained at 400 °C for 220 h, (c) another ten cycles from 100 to 400 °C, (d) maintained at 230 °C for 70 h after 60 cycles, (e) IR spectra for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after the CO oxidation sequence as shown in a-d, 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after 14 cycles CO oxidation and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts after ten cycles CO oxidation, (f) the k 3 -weighted Fourier transform spectrum derived from EXAFS for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after the CO oxidation sequence as shown in a-d, (g) conversion of CO from 100 to 400 °C in the 1st and the 10th cycles over commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 (named com-Pt/Al 2 O 3 ). 2.5 vol% CO, 2.5 vol% O 2 and balance Ar was allowed to pass through the reactor at a flow rate of 80 ml min À 1 .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1 /ZSM-5 prepared by atomic layer deposition and Pt 1 /CeO 2 prepared by atomic vapour trapping exhibited strong affinity with CO, with peak positioned at 2,095-2,115 cm À 1 , Pt 1 /FeO x synthesized via sol-gel method showed much weaker CO binding strength at 2,080 cm À 1 , which is similar to our catalyst. CO readily desorbed from 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 even at room temperature, with 3 cm À 1 red shift observed, which reflects the atomically dispersed Pt species may have non-identical coordination environments. For samples 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 2.0Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O Al 2 O 3 bearing predominant single-atom Pt d þ species with exceptional high thermal stability and reactivity under both O 2 and H 2 atmospheres.The strong interaction between Pt single-atoms and the support matrix is mainly attributed to the complex effect of H 2 PtCl 6 , aluminium isopropoxide (C 9 H 21 AlO 3 ) and P123. In an ethanol solution containing the P123 template, C 9 H 21 AlO 3 molecules can coordinate with PtCl 3</figDesc><table /><note><p><p><p><p><p>2 and 2.0Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 (Supplementary Fig.</p>16b-e</p>), two bands belonging to linearly bonded CO on Pt 0 nanoparticles (2,058 cm À 1 ) and on Pt d þ single-atoms (2,087 cm À 1 ) are observed. The CO absorption band dropped to ca. 1/3 of its original height after 30 min purging with N 2 at room temperature, and disappeared after heating at 100 °C for 2 min. This suggests weak interaction between adsorbed CO and Pt species, which is consistent with the CO titration experiment where CO adsorption and desorption were found in equilibrium (Supplementary Fig.</p>17</p>). All these characterizations combined provide compelling evidence that our protocol affords 0.2 wt% Pt on m-</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. We further synthesized Pt supported on disordered porous Al 2 O 3 without adding the P123 template as a control sample (abbreviated as p-Al 2 O 3 ). p-Al 2 O 3 could not withstand high temperature treatment with H 2 , resulting in the collapse of pores together with the agglomeration of supported Pt species (TEM images, XRD patterns, BET measurement, CO adsorbed IR spectra and H 2 -O 2 titration in Supplementary Figs</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1,3-butadiene at 200 °C for 24 h, (c) the selectivity of butenes and conversion of propene at 30 °C for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 , after the entire reaction sequence, (d) an HAADF-STEM image for 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after the entire reaction sequence, and (e) CO adsorption IR spectra for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 after the entire reaction sequence, (f) the conversion of n-hexane at 400 and 550 °C, (g) the catalysts deactivation at 550 °C, (h) the isomerization selectivity at 400 °C, and (i) the isomerization selectivity at 550 °C for 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 catalysts. The reaction was conducted in a gas mixture of 2% 1,3-butadiene, 20% propene, 16% H 2 and balance He at a flow rate of 20 ml min À 1 , 0.1 ml h À 1 n-hexane and 6 ml min À 1 pure H 2 at ambient pressure. Scale bar, 2 nm (d).</figDesc><table><row><cell>0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , too, was highly stable in CO oxidation despite</cell></row><row><cell>a slightly lower activity (Supplementary Fig. 56). Moreover,</cell></row><row><cell>after calcined at 600 °C the catalyst remained high stability over</cell></row><row><cell>14 cycles (0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 -600) (Supplementary Fig. 28e).</cell></row><row><cell>In comparison, the catalytic activity of commercial Pt/Al 2 O 3 ,</cell></row><row><cell>0.2Pt/p-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -imp decreased only</cell></row><row><cell>after several cycles (100-400 °C) (Fig. 5g, Supplementary</cell></row><row><cell>Figs 57 and</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>. Next, stoichiometric amounts of H 2 PtCl 6 (0.2, 0.5, and 2.0 wt% of Pt respectively, compared with Al 2 O 3 to be generated) dissolved in ethanol (0.0193 mol l À 1 ) were added to the mixture under stirring. The solution was covered with a PE film and stirred at room temperature for 48 h and then placed in an oven at 60 °C for ethanol evaporation for 72 h. The final gel was calcined at 400 °C for 4 h at a heating rate of 1°C min À 1 , named as 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 2.0Pt/ m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 . The samples (0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 , 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 and 2.0Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -O 2 )were reduced in 5% H 2 /N 2 at 400 °C for 1 h at a heating rate of 5 °C min À 1 . The resulting samples are named as 0.2Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , 0.5Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 and 2.0Pt/m-Al 2 O 3 -H 2 , respectively.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>NATURE COMMUNICATIONS | 8:16100 | DOI: 10.1038/ncomms16100 | www.nature.com/naturecommunications</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>We thank the <rs type="institution">National University of</rs> <rs type="grantName">Singapore Young Investigator Award</rs> (WBS: <rs type="grantNumber">R-279-000-464-133</rs>) for financial support. HAADF-STEM measurement at <rs type="institution">King Abdullah University of Science and Technology, Saudi Arabia</rs>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS NMR measurements were carried out at <rs type="institution">Dalian Institute of Chemical Physics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, China</rs>; the XAS measurements were performed at the BL5S2 at the <rs type="institution">Aichi Synchrotron Radiation Center</rs> under the approval of <rs type="funder">Aichi Science &amp; Technology Foundation, Aichi, Japan</rs> (Proposal No. <rs type="grantNumber">201506061</rs>) and at the BL01B1 at the SPring-8 (<rs type="affiliation">Japan Synchrotron Radiation Research Institute, Hyogo, Japan</rs>) under the approval of JASRI (Proposal No. <rs type="grantNumber">2016A1025</rs>). The XAS measurement at the AichiSR was financially supported by the <rs type="funder">Nagoya University Synchrotron Radiation Research Center</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_z8cAP3h">
					<idno type="grant-number">R-279-000-464-133</idno>
					<orgName type="grant-name">Singapore Young Investigator Award</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Kkrjaa5">
					<idno type="grant-number">201506061</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_gKgw2Un">
					<idno type="grant-number">2016A1025</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Data availability. The data that support the findings of this study are available from the authors on reasonable request.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Author contributions</head><p>N.Y. and Z.Z. conceived the idea, designed the experiments, analysed the data and wrote the manuscript. Z.Z. carried out the catalyst synthesis, evaluated their catalytic performances and conducted some characterizations. Y.H. and Y.Z carried out HAADF-STEM characterizations. T.Z., A.W. and M.Z. arranged and conducted <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> Al MAS NMR characterizations and DFT simulation. T.T. and H.A. carried out the XAS measurements. B.Z. and J.Z. participated in material characterizations and catalytic reaction evaluation. All authors discussed the results and edited the manuscript.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head><p>Supplementary Information accompanies this paper at <ref type="url" target="http://www.nature.com/naturecommunications">http://www.nature.com/ naturecommunications</ref> Competing interests: The authors declare no competing financial interests.</p><p>Reprints and permission information is available online at <ref type="url" target="http://npg.nature.com/reprintsandpermissions/">http://npg.nature.com/ reprintsandpermissions/</ref> </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The importance of elemental sustainability and critical element recovery</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Matharu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Green Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1949" to="1950" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Forecast of Platinum Supply &amp; Demand in 2015</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<publisher>Johnson Matthey</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-atom catalysts: a new frontier in heterogeneous catalysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acc. Chem. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1740" to="1748" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Catalysis: tens of thousands of atoms replaced by one</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">525</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="325" to="326" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Atomically dispersed supported metal catalysts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Flytzani-Stephanopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Chem. Biomol. Eng</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="545" to="574" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Catalysis by supported single metal atoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Catal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gold atoms stabilized on various supports catalyze the water-gas shift reaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Flytzani-Stephanopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acc. Chem. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="783" to="792" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Control of metal nanocrystal size reveals metal-support interface role for ceria catalysts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Cargnello</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">341</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="771" to="773" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating single-atom Pt-ceria catalysts by surface step decoration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Dvorak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10801</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supported metal clusters: synthesis, structure, and catalysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Gates</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="522" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A case of strong metal-support interactions: combining advanced microscopy and model systems to elucidate the atomic structure of interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Willinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5998" to="6001" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maximum noble-metal efficiency in catalytic materials: atomically dispersed surface platinum</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bruix</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10525" to="10530" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low-temperature transformation of methane to methanol on Pd 1 O 4 single sites anchored on the internal surface of microporous silicate</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13441" to="13445" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Isolated metal atom geometries as a strategy for selective heterogeneous hydrogenations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kyriakou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">335</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1209" to="1212" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Photochemical route for synthesizing atomically dispersed palladium catalysts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">352</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="797" to="801" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermal methane conversion to syngas mediated by Rh 1 -doped aluminum oxide cluster cations RhAl 3 O 4</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12854" to="12860" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low-temperature carbon monoxide oxidation catalysed by regenerable atomically dispersed palladium on alumina</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Peterson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4885</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-atom catalysis in mesoporous photovoltaics: the principle of utility maximization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8147" to="8153" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A stable single-site palladium catalyst for hydrogenations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Vile</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11265" to="11269" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic formation of single-atom catalytic active sites on ceria-supported gold nanoparticles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Glezakou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Rousseau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6511</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Catalysis on singly dispersed bimetallic sites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7938</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tackling CO poisoning with single-atom alloy catalysts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6396" to="6399" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-atom catalyst of platinum supported on titanium nitride for selective electrochemical reactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Tak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Soon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2058" to="2062" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-atom Pt as Co-catalyst for enhanced photocatalytic H 2 evolution</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2427" to="2431" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-atom catalysis of CO oxidation using Pt 1 /FeO x</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Qiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="634" to="641" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A single-site platinum CO oxidation catalyst in zeolite KLTL: microscopic and spectroscopic determination of the locations of the platinum atoms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Kistler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8904" to="8907" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tuning selectivity of electrochemical reactions by atomically dispersed platinum catalyst</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">10922</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Catalytically active single-atom sites fabricated from silver particles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4198" to="4203" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A non-porous supported-platinum catalyst for aromatization of n-hexane</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Derouane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">349</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="313" to="315" />
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermally stable Pt/mesoporous silica core-shell nanocatalysts for high-temperature reactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Joo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermally stable single-atom platinum-on-ceria catalysts via atom trapping</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">353</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="150" to="154" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generation of subnanometric platinum with high stability during transformation of a 2D zeolite into 3D</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Selective hydrogenation of 1,3-butadiene on platinum-copper alloys at the single-atom limit</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lucci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">8550</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Facile synthesis for ordered mesoporous gamma-aluminas with high thermal stability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3465" to="3472" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Coordinatively unsaturated Al 3 þ centers as binding sites for active catalyst phases of platinum on gamma-Al 2 O 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kwak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">325</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1670" to="1673" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stabilizing a platinum 1 single-atom catalyst on supported phosphomolybdic acid without compromising hydrogenation activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8319" to="8323" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unidirectional suppression of hydrogen oxidation on oxidized platinum clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2500</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">XANES determination of the platinum oxidation state distribution in cancer cells treated with platinum(IV) anticancer agents</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Foran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Beale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Hambley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">125</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7524" to="7525" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of active sites in CO oxidation and water-gas shift over supported Pt catalysts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">350</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ligand-capped Pt nanocrystals as oxide-supported catalysts: FTIR spectroscopic investigations of the adsorption and oxidation of CO</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Borchert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Angew. Chem. Int. Ed</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2923" to="2926" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Utilizing quantitative in situ FTIR spectroscopy to identify well-coordinated Pt atoms as the active site for CO oxidation on Al 2 O 3 -supported Pt catalysts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Catal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5599" to="5609" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Role of pentacoordinated Al 3 þ ions in the high temperature phase transformation of g-Al 2 O 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Kwak</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Phys. Chem. C</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9486" to="9492" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FeO x -supported platinum single-atom and pseudo-single-atom catalysts for chemoselective hydrogenation of functionalized nitroarenes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5634</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Functionalization of platinum nanoparticles with L-proline: simultaneous enhancements of catalytic activity and selectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Schrader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Warneke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Backenkohler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kunz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="905" to="912" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intermediates in the hydrogenation of benzene to cyclohexene on Pt(111) and Pd(111): a comparison from DFT calculations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Morin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Sautet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surf. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">600</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1339" to="1350" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Study of selective hydrogenation of acetophenone on Pt/SiO 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-S</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H.-W</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W.-H</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Catal. A-Gen</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">248</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="117" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Molecular insight into Pt-catalyzed chemoselective hydrogenation of an aromatic ketone by in situ modulation-excitation IR spectroscopy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Maeda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Baiker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Catal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2007" to="2013" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The pathway to total isomer selectivity: n-hexane conversion (reforming) on platinum nanoparticles supported on aluminum modified mesoporous silica (MCF-17)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Musselwhite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Na</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Alayoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Somorjai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16661" to="16665" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designed catalysts from Pt nanoparticles supported on macroporous oxides for selective isomerization of n-hexane</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>An</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Alayoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Musselwhite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Na</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Somorjai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">136</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6830" to="6833" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CO oxidation on supported single Pt atoms: experimental and ab initio density functional studies of CO interaction with Pt atom on theta-Al 2 O 3 (010) surface</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Moses-Debusk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12634" to="12645" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Furfuraldehyde hydrogenation on titanium oxide-supported platinum nanoparticles studied by sum frequency generation vibrational spectroscopy: acid-base catalysis explains the molecular origin of strong metal-support interactions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">134</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14208" to="14216" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strong metal-support interactions between gold nanoparticles and nonoxides</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">138</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="56" to="59" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
