<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Gut microbiota from multiple sclerosis patients enables spontaneous autoimmune encephalomyelitis in mice</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kerstin</forename><surname>Berer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Hertie Senior Professor Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>82152</postCode>
									<settlement>Martinsried</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><forename type="middle">Ann</forename><surname>Gerdes</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Clinical Neuroimmunology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University Hospital</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Ludwig-Maximillians University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>81377</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Egle</forename><surname>Cekanaviciute</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Neurology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94143</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Xiaoming</forename><surname>Jia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Neurology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94143</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">BGI-Shenzhen</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>518083</postCode>
									<settlement>Shenzhen</settlement>
									<country>China;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Zhongkui</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Chuan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">BGI-Shenzhen</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>518083</postCode>
									<settlement>Shenzhen</settlement>
									<country>China;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Luisa</forename><surname>Klotz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">BGI-Shenzhen</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>518083</postCode>
									<settlement>Shenzhen</settlement>
									<country>China;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Neurology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University Hospital Münster</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48149</postCode>
									<settlement>Münster</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Uta</forename><surname>Stauffer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute of Immunobiology and Epigenetics</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>79108</postCode>
									<settlement>Freiburg</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sergio</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Baranzini</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Neurology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94143</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Human Genetics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94143</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tania</forename><surname>Kümpfel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Clinical Neuroimmunology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University Hospital</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Ludwig-Maximillians University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>81377</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Reinhard</forename><surname>Hohlfeld</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Clinical Neuroimmunology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University Hospital</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Ludwig-Maximillians University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>81377</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">Munich Cluster for Systems Neurology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig-Maximillians University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>81377</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Gurumoorthy</forename><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Hertie Senior Professor Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>82152</postCode>
									<settlement>Martinsried</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff8">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute of Biochemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Research Group for Neuroinflammation and Mucosal Immunology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>82152</postCode>
									<settlement>Martinsried</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Hartmut</forename><surname>Wekerle</surname></persName>
							<email>hwekerle@neuro.mpg.de.</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Hertie Senior Professor Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>82152</postCode>
									<settlement>Martinsried</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">Munich Cluster for Systems Neurology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ludwig-Maximillians University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>81377</postCode>
									<settlement>Munich</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff9">
								<orgName type="department">Edited by Lawrence Steinman</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University School of Medicine</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Gut microbiota from multiple sclerosis patients enables spontaneous autoimmune encephalomyelitis in mice</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5AD880611EE62146B2B1267C4BBDA676</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1711233114</idno>
					<note type="submission">and approved August 7, 2017 (received for review June 30, 2017</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:36+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Freely available online through the PNAS open access option.</p><p>Data deposition: Normalized datasets related to this paper are available from the UCSF Data Sharing Service (Dash) at <ref type="url" target="https://doi.org/10.7272/Q6N58JH2">https://doi.org/10.7272/Q6N58JH2</ref> and raw data have been deposited in the European Bioinformatics Institute (EMBL-EBI) database, <ref type="url" target="https://www.ebi.ac.uk">https://www.ebi. ac.uk</ref> (accession no. ERP101460).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>There is emerging evidence that the commensal microbiota has a role in the pathogenesis of multiple sclerosis (MS), a putative autoimmune disease of the CNS. Here, we compared the gut microbial composition of 34 monozygotic twin pairs discordant for MS. While there were no major differences in the overall microbial profiles, we found a significant increase in some taxa such as Akkermansia in untreated MS twins. Furthermore, most notably, when transplanted to a transgenic mouse model of spontaneous brain autoimmunity, MS twin-derived microbiota induced a significantly higher incidence of autoimmunity than the healthy twinderived microbiota. The microbial profiles of the colonized mice showed a high intraindividual and remarkable temporal stability with several differences, including Sutterella, an organism shown to induce a protective immunoregulatory profile in vitro. Immune cells from mouse recipients of MS-twin samples produced less IL-10 than immune cells from mice colonized with healthy-twin samples. IL-10 may have a regulatory role in spontaneous CNS autoimmunity, as neutralization of the cytokine in mice colonized with healthy-twin fecal samples increased disease incidence. These findings provide evidence that MS-derived microbiota contain factors that precipitate an MS-like autoimmune disease in a transgenic mouse model. They hence encourage the detailed search for protective and pathogenic microbial components in human MS.</p><p>gut microbiome | multiple sclerosis | experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis | twin study | germ-free mice T he risk of developing multiple sclerosis (MS) is driven by both genetic factors and environmental exposures <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref>. Risk genes have been determined by large-scale genome-wide association studies (GWAS), which identified more than 200 different DNA variants associated with disease susceptibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref>. Environmental risk factors include smoking, reduced exposure to sunlight, and infection with Epstein-Barr virus <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref>. Very recently, the intestinal microbiota emerged as an additional potential triggering factor <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5)</ref>.</p><p>The notion that commensal gut bacteria are causally related to brain autoimmunity is supported by a transgenic mouse model of spontaneous experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE). In this model, nearly all animals raised in specific pathogen-free (SPF) conditions develop a relapsing-remitting (RR) variant of the disease within months of age <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref>. Importantly, when kept in a germfree environment, animals from the same strain remain disease-free. However, spontaneous disease promptly follows exposure of germfree mice to SPF-derived fecal material <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref>. Taken together, these observations indicate that the encephalitogenic immune response observed in these mice is mediated by the intestinal microbiota.</p><p>Translation of these experimental observations into human MS poses considerable practical challenges. Complicating factors are, in particular, genetic diversity <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8)</ref> and lifestyle, such as diet <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9)</ref>, both of which profoundly impact the individual gut microbiota. In addition, age, therapy, and neurological condition (10) might also affect the gut microbial composition. In an attempt to eliminate genetic variance and reduce environmental variance to a minimum, we identified and recruited 34 monozygotic (MZ) twin pairs, discordant for MS, for a microbiome study. All the probands were of Caucasian origin and had grown up together with their healthy twins to adulthood in Germany. We studied their gut microbiota in two tiers: first, intestinal microbial profiles of MS twins and healthy twins were compared by 16S ribosomal RNA (rRNA) amplicon and metagenomic shotgun sequencing. Second, we transplanted fecal samples from selected twin pairs to germ-free mice to assess functional differences in the human intestinal microbiota of MS and healthy twins.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>MZ Twin Cohorts Discordant for MS. We assembled a cohort of 34 MZ twin pairs clinically discordant for MS. In each pair, one twin has clinically definite MS according to the current diagnostic criteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref>, whereas the co-twin is unaffected. Our MS twin cohort resembles the general MS population with respect to female Significance Studies using experimental models have indicated that multiple sclerosis (MS)-like disease can be triggered in the gut following interactions of brain autoimmune T lymphocytes with local microbiota. Here we studied the gut microbiota from monozygotic human twin pairs discordant for multiple sclerosis. When we transferred human-derived microbiota into transgenic mice expressing a myelin autoantigen-specific T cell receptor, we found that gut microbiota from multiple sclerosis-affected twins induced CNS-specific autoimmunity at a higher incidence than microbiota from healthy co-twins. Our results offer functional evidence that human microbiome components contribute to CNS-specific autoimmunity.</p><p>preponderance, age distribution, age at onset, and distribution of clinical subtypes [RR MS, secondary progressive MS, primary progressive MS, and clinically isolated syndrome (CIS)] (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(12)</ref>. The twin cohort is homogenous in terms of geographic environment and genetic background. Furthermore, immunophenotyping of peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) from all twin pairs did not show relevant differences in the frequencies of CD4 + T cells, Th1 cells, Th17 cells, and Treg cells (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">S1</ref>).</p><p>Microbial Profiling of MS-Discordant MZ Twins by 16S rRNA and Metagenomic Shotgun Sequencing. To search for differences between microbiomes of MS-affected versus nonaffected twins, we applied 16S rRNA sequencing and metagenomics shotgun sequencing. 16S rRNA amplicon sequencing revealed no major differences in microbial community structures. Specifically, MS twins and healthy twins exhibited comparable microbial community richness (alpha diversity) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1A</ref>). A concomitant principal coordinate analysis (PCoA) also did not point to disease-dependent clustering of samples (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1B</ref>). Further, analysis at the level of individual taxa [up to genera or the operational taxonomic units (OTUs) level] did not indicate significant differences between MS and healthy twins. However, when patients were stratified for the use of disease-modifying therapy, several taxa (most notably Akkermansia muciniphila) were significantly increased in untreated MS twin siblings (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S2</ref>).</p><p>Comparing the microbiome composition of MS and healthy twins is a first, purely descriptive step in exploring the role of the microbiota in MS. Disease-related functional differences in the microbiomes of healthy or MS twins might be revealed by shotgun metagenomic sequencing. Using Human Microbiome Project (HMP) Unified Metabolic Analysis Network (HUMAnN2) tool1, we assessed the microbial community, performed functional profiling on the bacterial DNA sequences, and identified 242 unique bacterial species across 98 genera, 1.2 million gene families, and 558 bacterial metabolic pathways. Interestingly, analysis of gut bacterial composition showed higher similarity between discordant twin siblings than among unrelated twin pairs (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">S3</ref>), thus confirming the influence of the host's genetics in the composition of the gut microbiome. To determine possible associations of specific bacterial species, gene families, or metabolic pathways with MS, we performed logistic regression analysis. In harmony with 16S sequencing findings, after adjusting for twin pair, number of genome equivalents sequenced, and multiple comparisons, no specific bacterial species, gene families, or metabolic pathways were significantly associated with the MS disease phenotype.</p><p>RR Mice Colonized with Human MS Twin-Derived Microbiota. To explore the functional role of human microbiota in CNS inflammation, we used our previously described spontaneous RR mouse model <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7)</ref>. Several qualities render these mice a particularly promising reporter system. RR mice express a transgenic myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein (MOG)-specific T cell receptor in more than 70% of their CD4 + T cells. Beginning at 2 mo of age, more than 80% of the mice spontaneously develop an inflammatory demyelinating disease that recapitulates features of early human MS: The disease course is often relapsing-remitting, affects varying parts of the brain and spinal cord with lesions featuring round-cell infiltrates and large confluent areas of demyelination with axonal degeneration, and responds to B celldepleting therapy <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref>. Most importantly, spontaneous disease critically depends on an intact commensal microbiome, as germfree RR mice remain healthy <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref>.</p><p>We reasoned that if the gut microbiota is a determinant factor contributing to the severity and course of human MS, transplantation of human fecal microbial communities from MS twins should result in a higher frequency of spontaneous EAE than the transfer of fecal material from healthy twins. We selected a subgroup of five twin pairs who were all discordant for RR MS and in which the affected twins had different disease durations and were either without therapy or were treated with IFN-β (for further details refer to Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">S1</ref>). Each donor fecal sample was diluted in prereduced PBS and introduced into a group of 6-wk-old, germ-free RR mice by oral gavage. Mouse fecal pellets were collected 2 and 6 wk after transplantation to assess the stability as well as composition of the intestinal microbiota by 16S rRNA amplicon sequencing (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2A</ref>).</p><p>Unsurprisingly, we detected significantly reduced alpha diversity (∼10%) in colonized mice compared with the donor humans (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2B</ref>). PCoA confirmed the divergent gut microbial community structures in human and mouse samples (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2C</ref>), indicating that only a subset of microbial species from human donors was able to colonize mouse recipients. The microbiota transfer rate was consistent across samples and independent of the disease state of the donor. Since the composition of the intestinal microbiota is profoundly imprinted by host genetics, diet,  and other environmental factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(13)</ref>, it was not surprising that the composition of gnotobiotic mouse fecal samples reflected incomplete colonization by the human donor microbiota. Similar changes were noted in previous human-to-mouse transplant experiments <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15)</ref>. PCoA of mouse samples demonstrated clustering by donor and twin pair but not by EAE disease state (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2D</ref>). In addition, comparison of the percentage of microbial genera that was transferred from the human donor to recipient mice did not indicate any disease-based trends and highlighted a comparatively high mean transfer rate of 90.3% (Table <ref type="table">S2</ref>). Finally, the recipient mouse microbiome remained highly stable between 2 and 6 wk after colonization, as indicated by representative bar plots of mean relative abundance of bacterial genera and corresponding analysis (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2E</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Increased Incidence of Spontaneous EAE in RR Mice Colonized with</head><p>Microbiota from MS-Affected Twins. Remarkably, RR mice transplanted with MS patient-derived microbiota developed spontaneous EAE at a higher frequency than animals colonized with intestinal bacteria from healthy twins (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3A</ref>). The triggering of EAE in germ-free RR mice by human microbial transfer per se is notable, considering that so far this has been achieved only with some mouse-associated bacteria <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref>. However, monocolonization with experimental bacterial consortia (such as altered Schaedler flora) and segmented filamentous bacteria did not induce spontaneous EAE <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref>.</p><p>We next set out to determine the differences that made MSderived microbiota more pathogenic than healthy-derived samples. Analysis of the mouse microbiome at the level of individual taxa revealed significant differences between MS-and healthy twin-colonized mice, both at the genus and OTU taxonomical levels. While the genera Adlercreutzia and Tannerella were more abundant in the feces of mice transplanted with the healthy twin fecal material, fewer bacteria of the genera Ruminococcus were present in these mice. The most significant difference, however, was a reduced abundance of the genus Sutterella in mice colonized with microbiota from the MS twins compared with recipients of fecal material from healthy twins (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3B</ref>). Consistent with our results, Sutterella has previously been associated with better outcomes in patients with inflammatory bowel disease <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(16)</ref> as well as with resistance to EAE development in male TNFR2 -/-mice <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(17)</ref>.</p><p>The gut flora may also affect CNS autoimmune responses by changing the metabolic environment of the gastrointestinal tract to produce metabolites such as short-chain fatty acids and aryl hydrocarbon receptor (Ahr) ligands, which are known to affect microglia and astrocytes <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(18)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(19)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(20)</ref>. To identify potential metabolic pathways that are altered in recipient mice, we performed shotgun metagenomic sequencing on total stool DNA. Interestingly, shotgun metagenomic sequencing of mouse fecal pellets uncovered several metabolic pathways that were associated with the MS disease status of the donor and thus were upregulated in the intestines of mouse recipients of MS microbiota. Pathways associated with the disease phenotype included pyruvate fermentation, L-tyrosine biosynthesis, and chondroitin sulfate degradation (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S4</ref>). While the functional significance of these pathways to MS pathogenesis remains unclear, these results indicate that the gut microbiome influences MS disease risk not only through specific bacterial composition, as suggested by other studies, but also by potentially changing the metabolic environment of the human gastrointestinal tract. Additional studies are required to validate these findings as well as to identify similar associations in a larger cohort of human subjects.</p><p>Reduced IL-10 Production in RR Mice Colonized with Microbiota from MS-Affected Twins. A search for relevant immunological changes possibly responsible for the differential EAE induction pointed to IL-10 as a key factor. While the global composition of immune tissues (dendritic cells, macrophages, and B cells, as well as T cell subsets, including Foxp3 + regulatory T cells) remained unaffected by fecal transfers (Fig. <ref type="figure">S5</ref>), there were functional dissimilarities in the production of antibodies and cytokines. Serum anti-MOG autoantibody titers of the IgG1 class were slightly increased in MS-colonized RR mice, while IgG2a levels were decreased (Fig. <ref type="figure">S6</ref>). In addition, we performed a comprehensive qPCR-based screening for cytokines and barrier and tight junction proteins in the small intestine and colon of mouse recipients. We did not find significant differences in the expression levels of IL-1α, IL-1β, IL-6, IL-9, IL-11, IL-18, IL-21, GM-CSF, IFN-γ, TNF-α, Claudin-1, Claudin-2, Claudin-4, Claudin-5, Myo9b, Occludin, RegIIIγ, Tjp-1, Tjp-2, or Tjp-3 between mice transplanted with control or MS twin fecal samples (Fig. <ref type="figure">S7</ref>). The expression levels of IL-4, IL-5, IL-13, IL-22, and IL-27 were below the detection limit.</p><p>Most informative was the pattern of cytokines released by activated splenic T cells. There was a modest change in IL-17 release, with IFN-γ remaining unaltered (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3C</ref>). More strikingly, spleen cells from recipients of control microbiota produced much higher amounts of IL-10 upon stimulation with anti-CD3/anti-CD28 monoclonal antibodies than cells from recipients of MS microbiota (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3C</ref>). This difference was of functional relevance. We colonized germ-free RR mice with healthy donor fecal material and subsequently treated them with anti-IL-10 neutralizing or isotype control antibodies. Blocking IL-10 increased disease incidence compared with isotype control-treated mice (from 30 to 55%; P = 0.0006, Fisher's exact test) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3D</ref>).</p><p>The immunological profiles observed in the colonized RR mice were consistent with the patterns observed in PBMCs from a subgroup of eight twin pairs which included several donors used for the mouse colonization experiments. There, anti-CD3/ anti-CD28 stimulation induced stronger production of antiinflammatory IL-10 in T cells from healthy than from MS donors (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4A</ref>). In contrast, we found no differences in the frequencies of CD4 + T cells, Th1 cells, Th17 cells, and Treg cells (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">S1</ref>). Also, production of IFN-γ, IL-17, and IL-4 cytokines in response to in vitro stimulation with phytohemagglutinin (PHA) or anti-CD3/anti-CD28 was largely indistinguishable between T cells from MS-affected and healthy twins (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4B</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Chronic inflammatory diseases have been recently associated with altered profiles of the intestinal bacterial flora <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(21)</ref>. These changes were revealed by studies making use of new sequencing technologies, which, however, cannot per se resolve whether the microbial changes were primary or secondary to cognate diseases. Causal relations were established in metabolic conditions such as obesity by transplanting human-derived microbiota to rodents; these recipients of disease-derived fecal samples developed an equivalent metabolic condition <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(22)</ref>. Applying similar strategies to studies of chronic autoimmune or degenerative diseases <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(23)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(24)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(25)</ref> has remained more challenging. This definitely applies to exploring links between MS and changes of intestinal microbiota.</p><p>Here we took a two-tiered approach to address this question. First, we compared the intestinal microbial profiles of MS twins and healthy twins by microbial 16S rRNA amplicon and metagenomic shotgun sequencing. Second, we transplanted fecal samples from MS-affected and healthy twins into germ-free mice. We did not detect significant differences in MS-related microbial profiles between MS-affected and healthy twins. In this respect, our results differ from findings reported by others. A recent study using pyrosequencing of 16S rRNA gene in 20 Japanese patients with RR MS detected associations with Clostridium and Bacteroidetes species <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(26)</ref>. These signatures were not seen in our cohort, nor were they reported in another independent screening <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(27)</ref>. However, it should be noted that these studies (including our own) are relatively limited in size. Second, it is likely that microbial associations vary according to geographical region, human genetic background, and many other factors, including treatment. However, it is worth noting that, after adjusting for treatment, we found Akkermansia species were increased in untreated MS twins, which was also found to be increased in another independent cohort of MS patients [see ref. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27</ref> and the companion paper by Cekanaviciute et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(28)</ref>]. Third, fecal material may be suboptimal for studying processes possibly restricted to circumscribed intestinal segments. Gut microbiota differ radically in their functional potential, density, and composition along different segments of the small and large intestine <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(29)</ref>. Thus, in the feces, pathogenic organisms populating the small intestine at low density could be eclipsed by high-density colonic communities. Obviously, more detailed studies of much larger cohorts are needed to further explore the complexities of MS-related microbial associations.</p><p>The second tier of our strategy, transfer of human microbiota into germ-free RR mice, led to a particularly interesting observation. We found that not only could human microbiota trigger classic RR EAE, but, even more significantly, transplants from MS-affected donors triggered EAE at higher rates than did transplants from their healthy control-derived counterparts. This difference was not large in magnitude but was significant and reproducible. A detailed analysis of 16S rRNA sequences revealed significant differences between MS-and healthy twincolonized mice at the level of individual taxa (genera and OTUs). The most prominent MS-dependent change was a reduction in the bacterial genus Sutterella.</p><p>The increased incidence of spontaneous EAE in MS samplerecipient gnotobiotic RR mice could be due to either increased activation of autoimmune effector T cells or a weakened regulatory mechanism. Our results seem to favor the latter. Indeed, functional screening of peripheral blood lymphocytes from a subgroup of monozygotic twins indicated decreased IL-10 production in MS-derived samples. This is in accord with previous work, which described decreases of Tr1-like, IL-10-producing T cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(30)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(31)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(32)</ref>. The differential IL-10 response noted in human PBMCs was mirrored in gnotobiotic RR mice. In germfree RR mice recolonized with MS-derived fecal samples, spleen T cells produce less IL-10 than their equivalents from control sample recipients. This recalls previous reports describing enhanced IL-10 production in the intestinal immune system driven by bacterial polysaccharide A (33) and protection from actively induced CNS autoimmune disease <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(34)</ref>. A relative lack of protective factors rather than an increase in disease-promoting factors is also supported by our observation that in vivo treatment with anti-IL-10 antibody resulted in an increased incidence of spontaneous EAE in our RR model. Although there is currently no conclusive evidence of a genetic association of MS with the IL-10 gene or IL-10-related pathways, this by no means excludes the possibility that this crucially important pathway is modulated by external factors (e.g., microbiota).</p><p>In conclusion, we here provide evidence that human MSderived microbiota contain factors that precipitate an MS-like autoimmune disease in a humanized transgenic mouse model. This observation provides possibilities for characterizing the precise role and functional mechanisms by which the human intestinal microbiota contributes to the pathogenesis of neuroinflammatory diseases. The findings may eventually have important implications not only for the pathogenesis but also for the therapy and potentially even prevention of human MS.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Details of cohort recruitment, sample acquisition, and information collection are provided in SI Methods. The study was approved by the local Ethics Committee of the Ludwig-Maximilians University Munich, and all participants gave written informed consent. All animal procedures were in accordance with the guidelines of the Committee on Animals of the Max Planck Institute of Neurobiology and the Max Planck Institute of Immunobiology and Epigenetics with a license from the Regierung von Oberbayern as well as the Regierungspräsidium Freiburg. Procedures for 16S and metagenomic sequencing, data analysis, mouse colonization, flow cytometry, ELISA, cytokine profiling, and real-time qPCR are described in detail in SI Methods.</p><p>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. We thank Prof. Thomas Boehm for supervising the maintenance of our germ-free mouse colony; Birgit Kunkel for technical assistance; Norbert Joswig, Melanie Pfunder, Manuela Schätzle, and Christian Schauerte for maintaining our germ-free colony and for technical support; Angelika Bamberger for support in patient care; Dr. Klaus Dornmair and Dr. Naoto Kawakami for helpful suggestions and comments; and Dr. Nicolaus König for support in the recruitment of the twin cohort. We also thank the international multiple sclerosis microbiome consortium (iMSMS) for helpful discussions and feedback. This work was funded by the Hertie Foundation, a DFG Koselleck Award, DFG Grant TR-128, the German Competence Network on Multiple Federal and Bavarian Divisions of the German MS Society, Verein Therapieforschung für MS Kranke e.V. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. No overt differences in alpha or beta diversity were detected by comparing the fecal microbial profiles of healthy twins with those of MS twins. (A) Phylogenetic (alpha) diversity of fecal microbiota in healthy twins (HD, black; n = 34) and MS twins (MS, green; n = 34). (B) PCoA of weighted UniFrac community distances for fecal microbiota of healthy twins (black; n = 34) and MS twins (green; n = 34).</figDesc><graphic coords="2,301.83,559.96,244.38,107.66" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Human microbiota can be efficiently transferred to mouse recipients. (A) Design of humanized gnotobiotic mouse experiment: 6-wk-old, germ-free RR SJL/J mice were gavaged with fecal samples from the healthy twin or the MS twin from a MZ twin pair. Fecal samples for 16S rRNA sequencing analysis were harvested at 2 and 6 wk after colonization. Humanized gnotobiotic RR mice were observed for the development of clinical signs of EAE for 12 wk. (B) Phylogenetic (alpha) diversity of fecal microbiota in human twin pairs (purple; n = 8) and mouse recipients (gray; n = 47). ****P &lt; 0.0001 (Mann-Whitney u test). (C) PCoA of weighted UniFrac community distances comparing fecal microbiota of human donors (purple; n = 8) and mouse recipients (gray; n = 47). (D) PCoA of weighted UniFrac community distances for fecal microbiota of mice transplanted with microbiota from healthy (n = 23) or MS (n = 24) twins. (E) Mean relative abundances of bacterial genera in fecal samples of mice that received microbiota of healthy donors (HD; n = 20-26) or MS patients (MS; n = 22-26) at 2 and 6 wk after transplantation.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,39.91,52.78,500.67,398.89" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Intestinal microbiota plays a pivotal role in CNS-specific autoimmunity. (A) Incidence of spontaneous EAE in humanized gnotobiotic RR SJL/J mice. Germ-free RR SJL/J mice were gavaged with fecal material from healthy (HD; n = 18) or MS (MS; n = 20) twins using in total five MZ twin pairs. *P &lt; 0.05 (Gehan-Breslow-Wilcoxon test). (B) Relative abundance of Sutterella in fecal samples of mice that received the microbiota of healthy donor (HD; n = 23) or an MS patient (MS; n = 24) using in total five MZ twin pairs. Each circle represents an individual stool sample, and the horizontal line and whiskers indicate mean ± SEM. ***P &lt; 0.001 (Mann-Whitney u test). (C) Cytokine production by splenocytes from humanized gnotobiotic SJL/J mice. Spleen cells were stimulated for 72 h with 1 μg/mL anti-CD3 antibody or 1 μg/mL anti-CD3 and 0.5 μg/mL anti-CD28 antibody. Levels of IFN-γ, IL-17, and IL-10 in the supernatants were measured by ELISA. Bars display mean ± SEM; n = 12-16 mice per group. Data were pooled from three independent experiments. *P &lt; 0.05; **P = 0.0069 (Mann-Whitney u test). (D) IL-10 neutralization increases spontaneous EAE in humanized gnotobiotic RR SJL/J mice. Germ-free RR SJL/J mice were gavaged with fecal material from healthy twins and were treated weekly with either isotype control antibodies (n = 10) or neutralizing anti-IL-10 antibodies (n = 11). Data were pooled from two independent experiments.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,134.31,52.78,320.72,301.27" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Gut bacteria from healthy twins trigger an antiinflammatory T cell response. (A) IL-10 production of CD4 + T cells isolated from PBMCs of selected twin pairs. T cells were stimulated for 96 h with 1 μg/mL anti-CD3 and anti-CD28 antibodies. Levels of IL-10 (seven pairs, two singletons) in the supernatants were measured by ELISA. *P &lt; 0.05 (Wilcoxon test). (B) Cytokine profiles of CD4 + T cells isolated from PBMCs of selected twin pairs Depending on PBMC availability and quality, eight twin pairs were selected for further in vitro stimulation assays, and data are depicted for each cytokine where stimulation-dependent production above the individual detection level could be documented. T cells were stimulated for 48 h with 5 μg/mL PHA. Levels of IFN-γ (five pairs, three singletons), IL-17 (eight pairs), and IL-4 (seven pairs, one singleton) in the supernatants were measured by the Luminex Bead-based Multiplex Assay.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,38.78,351.78,244.37,253.08" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Demographic and clinical characteristics of MZ twins discordant for MS</figDesc><table><row><cell>Characteristic</cell><cell>MZ twins</cell></row><row><cell>No. of pairs</cell><cell>34</cell></row><row><cell>Gender, female/male</cell><cell>26/8</cell></row><row><cell>Age in years (range in years)</cell><cell>41.3 ± 10.8 (21-63)</cell></row><row><cell>Age in years at disease onset</cell><cell>28.0 ± 9.0 (14-47)</cell></row><row><cell>(range in years)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Time in years clinically discordant</cell><cell>13.2 ± 9.6 (1-33)</cell></row><row><cell>for MS (range in years)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Pairs clinically discordant for MS</cell><cell>18 (53)</cell></row><row><cell>longer than 10 y (%)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Pairs with a positive family</cell><cell>11 (32)</cell></row><row><cell>history of MS (%)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>MS type, n (%)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>CIS</cell><cell>3 (9)</cell></row><row><cell>RR-MS</cell><cell>22 (65)</cell></row><row><cell>SP-MS</cell><cell>7 (21)</cell></row><row><cell>PP-MS</cell><cell>2 (6)</cell></row><row><cell>Disease-modifying treatment, n (%)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Untreated</cell><cell>15 (44)</cell></row><row><cell>IFN-β</cell><cell>13 (38)</cell></row><row><cell>Natalizumab</cell><cell>4 (12)</cell></row><row><cell>Glatiramer acetate</cell><cell>1 (3)</cell></row><row><cell>Azathioprine</cell><cell>1 (3)</cell></row></table><note><p>Continuous data are expressed as mean ± SD. Categorical data are expressed as the number of observations (%). CIS, clinically isolated syndrome; PP-MS, primary progressive MS; RR-MS, relapsing-remitting MS; SP-MS, secondary progressive MS.</p></note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>, Cyliax Stiftung, and the Max Planck Society. K.B. was supported by the James Heineman Research Award of the Minerva Stiftung. G.K. is supported by European Research Council Starting Grant GAMES 635617. S.E.B. is supported by grants from the US Department of Defense and the US National MS Society. E.C. is supported by a NIH/Institutional Research and Academic Career Development Award.</figDesc><table /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>Downloaded from https://www.pnas.org by 147.161.165.28 on March 4, 2025 from IP address 147.161.165.28.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nature plus nurture: The triggering of multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wekerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Swiss Med Wkly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">145</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">14189</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple sclerosis genetics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sawcer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Franklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Lancet Neurol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="700" to="709" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">XVI European Charcot Foundation lecture: Nutrition and environment: Can MS be prevented?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Munger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ascherio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Neurol Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">311</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Microbial view of central nervous system autoimmunity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Berer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Krishnamoorthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">FEBS Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">588</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4207" to="4213" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Wekerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Hohlfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Gut Microbiota in Multiple Sclerosis: A Bioreactor Driving Brain Autoimmunity</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="123" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spontaneous relapsing-remitting EAE in the SJL/J mouse: MOG-reactive transgenic T cells recruit endogenous MOG-specific B cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Pöllinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Exp Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">206</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1303" to="1316" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Commensal microbiota and myelin autoantigen cooperate to trigger autoimmune demyelination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Berer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">479</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="538" to="541" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human genetics shape the gut microbiome</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">159</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="789" to="799" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cross-species comparisons of host genetic associations with the microbiome</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Goodrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Davenport</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Waters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">352</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="532" to="535" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Control of brain development, function, and behavior by the microbiome</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mazmanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell Host Microbe</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="576" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diagnostic criteria for multiple sclerosis: 2010 revisions to the McDonald criteria</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Polman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ann Neurol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="292" to="302" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defining the clinical course of multiple sclerosis: The 2013 revisions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lublin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="278" to="286" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bacteria from diverse habitats colonize and compete in the mouse gut</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Seedorf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">159</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="253" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effect of diet on the human gut microbiome: A metagenomic analysis in humanized gnotobiotic mice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Turnbaugh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci Transl Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="14" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gut immune maturation depends on colonization with a hostspecific microbiota</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">149</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1578" to="1593" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Complement, a target for therapy in inflammatory and degenerative diseases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Drug Discov</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="857" to="877" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TNFR2 deficiency acts in concert with gut microbiota to precipitate spontaneous sex-biased central nervous system demyelinating autoimmune disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Bonn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Franklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Ericsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mckarns</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">195</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4668" to="4684" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Host microbiota constantly control maturation and function of microglia in the CNS</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Erny</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Neurosci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="965" to="977" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gut microbiota regulate motor deficits and neuroinflammation in a model of Parkinson&apos;s disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">167</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1469" to="1480" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>e12</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Type I interferons and microbial metabolites of tryptophan modulate astrocyte activity and central nervous system inflammation via the aryl hydrocarbon receptor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Rothhammer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="586" to="597" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Role of the gut microbiota in immunity and inflammatory disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Kamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">U</forename><surname>Seo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Núñez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="321" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gut microbiota from twins discordant for obesity modulate metabolism in mice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Ridaura</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">341</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1241214</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The oral and gut microbiomes are perturbed in rheumatoid arthritis and partly normalized after treatment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="895" to="905" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fecal microbiota composition differs between children with β-cell autoimmunity and those without</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>De Goffau</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Diabetes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1238" to="1244" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gut microbiota are related to Parkinson&apos;s disease and clinical phenotype</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Scheperjans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mov Disord</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="358" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dysbiosis in the gut microbiota of patients with multiple sclerosis, with a striking depletion of species belonging to Clostridia XIVa and IV clusters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Miyake</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS One</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">137429</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alterations of the human gut microbiome in multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Jangi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12015</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gut bacteria from multiple sclerosis patients modulate human T cells and exacerbate symptoms in mouse models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cekanaviciute</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas1711235114</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Nat Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The human gut microbiome: Ecology and recent evolutionary changes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu Rev Microbiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="411" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alterations in CD46-mediated Tr1 regulatory T cells in patients with multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Astier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Meiffren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hafler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Clin Invest</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">116</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3252" to="3257" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">IL-10 suppressor activity and ex vivo Tr1 cell function are impaired in multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Martinez-Forero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur J Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="576" to="586" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Functional inflammatory profiles distinguish myelin-reactive T cells from patients with multiple sclerosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sci Transl Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="274" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inducible Foxp3+ regulatory T-cell development by a commensal bacterium of the intestinal microbiota</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Round</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mazmanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12204" to="12209" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An intestinal commensal symbiosis factor controls neuroinflammation via TLR2-mediated CD39 signalling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4432</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advancing our understanding of the human microbiome using QIIME</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Navas-Molina</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Methods Enzymol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">531</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="444" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Open-source sequence clustering methods improve the state of the art</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kopylova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="e15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Phylogenetic diversity (PD) and biodiversity conservation: Some bioinformatics challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Faith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Evol Bioinform Online</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UniFrac: A new phylogenetic method for comparing microbial communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Lozupone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl Environ Microbiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8228" to="8235" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moderated estimation of fold change and dispersion for RNA-seq data with DESeq2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Love</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Anders</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Genome Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">550</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
