<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Tunable moiré bands and strong correlations in small-twist-angle bilayer graphene</title>
				<funder ref="#_n3MH8Zt">
					<orgName type="full">Welch Foundation</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_QA9xnPT">
					<orgName type="full">National Science Foundation</orgName>
					<orgName type="abbreviated">NSF</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_s8M3n8s #_ueMM4H2">
					<orgName type="full">Semiconductor Research Corporation Nanoelectronics Research Initiative SWAN center, National Science Foundation</orgName>
					<orgName type="abbreviated">NSF</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_a6XMYFw">
					<orgName type="full">US Army Research Office</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Samsung Corporation</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kyounghwan</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Microelectronics Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78758</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ashley</forename><surname>Dasilva</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78712</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Shengqiang</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>85721</postCode>
									<settlement>Tucson</settlement>
									<region>AZ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Babak</forename><surname>Fallahazad</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Microelectronics Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78758</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Larentis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Microelectronics Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78758</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Takashi</forename><surname>Taniguchi</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute for Materials Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1-1 Namiki Tsukuba Ibaraki</addrLine>
									<postCode>305-0044</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kenji</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute for Materials Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1-1 Namiki Tsukuba Ibaraki</addrLine>
									<postCode>305-0044</postCode>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Leroy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Arizona</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>85721</postCode>
									<settlement>Tucson</settlement>
									<region>AZ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Allan</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78712</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Emanuel</forename><surname>Tutuc</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Microelectronics Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>78758</postCode>
									<settlement>Austin</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Tunable moiré bands and strong correlations in small-twist-angle bilayer graphene</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">97FB6792E8D15737AF9CC2A022BB9E8D</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1620140114</idno>
					<note type="submission">Contributed by Allan H. MacDonald, February 14, 2017 (sent for review December 16, 2016; reviewed by Philip Kim and Konstantin S. Novoselov</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:36+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>According to electronic structure theory, bilayer graphene is expected to have anomalous electronic properties when it has long-period moiré patterns produced by small misalignments between its individual layer honeycomb lattices. We have realized bilayer graphene moiré crystals with accurately controlled twist angles smaller than 1°and studied their properties using scanning probe microscopy and electron transport. We observe conductivity minima at charge neutrality, satellite gaps that appear at anomalous carrier densities for twist angles smaller than 1°, and tunneling densities-of-states that are strongly dependent on carrier density. These features are robust up to large transverse electric fields. In perpendicular magnetic fields, we observe the emergence of a Hofstadter butterfly in the energy spectrum, with fourfold degenerate Landau levels, and broken symmetry quantum Hall states at filling factors ±1, 2, 3. These observations demonstrate that at small twist angles, the electronic properties of bilayer graphene moiré crystals are strongly altered by electron-electron interactions. M oiré patterns form when nearly identical two-dimensional (2D) crystals are overlaid with a small relative twist angle <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(4)</ref>. The electronic properties of moiré crystals depend sensitively on the ratio of the interlayer hybridization strength, which is independent of twist angle, to the band energy shifts produced by momentum space rotation <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(5)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(12)</ref>. In bilayer graphene, this ratio is small when twist angles exceed about 2° <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13)</ref>, allowing moiré crystal electronic structure to be easily understood using perturbation theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(5)</ref>. At smaller twist angles, electronic properties become increasingly complex. Theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15)</ref> has predicted that extremely flat bands appear at a series of magic angles, the largest of which is close to 1°. Flat bands in 2D electron systems, for example the Landau level bands that appear in the presence of external magnetic fields, allow for physical properties that are dominated by electron-electron interactions, and have been friendly territory for the discovery of fundamentally new states of matter. Here we report transport and scanning probe microscopy (SPM) studies of bilayer graphene moiré crystals with carefully controlled small-twist angles (STA), below 1°. We find that conductivity minima emerge in transport at neutrality, and at anomalous satellite densities that correspond to ±8 additional electrons in the moiré crystal unit cell, and that the conductivity minimum at neutrality is not weakened by a transverse electric field applied between the layers. Our observations can be explained only by strong electronic correlations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Our STA bilayer graphene samples are fabricated by sequential graphene and hexagonal boron-nitride (hBN) flake pick-up steps using a hemispherical handle substrate <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(16)</ref> that allows an individual flake to be detached from a substrate while leaving flakes in its immediate proximity intact. To realize STA bilayer graphene, we start with a single graphene flake and split it into two separate sections (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1A</ref>). The separated flakes are then sequentially picked up by an hBN flake attached to the hemispherical handle. Between the first and the second graphene flake pick-up, the substrate is rotated by a small (0.6-1.2°) angle (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1</ref> B and C) that can be controlled to 0.1°accuracy. Because the two graphene sections stem from the same crystal grain, they have crystal axes that are aligned at the onset. The substrate rotation yields a controlled twist between the two graphene layers (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1C</ref>) and forms a moiré crystal (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1D</ref>). The device fabrication is completed by encapsulating it in an hBN dielectric <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(17)</ref> and defining a top-gate and edge metal contacts (18) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1E</ref>).</p><p>An example of the four-point conductance (G) vs. top-gate bias (V TG ) data measured in an STA bilayer graphene device at different temperatures (T) is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1F</ref>. The data show a local conductance minimum when the carrier density (n) approaches zero (charge neutrality) that is similar to the minimum seen in simple gated graphene samples. In addition, two pronounced satellite conductance minima are observed at V TG = ± 2.2 V, corresponding to n = ±2.5 × 10 12 cm -2 . All conductance minima weaken with increasing temperature, and are no longer visible at temperatures above 80 K. This striking observation departs from the density dependence of the conductance expected in either Bernal stacked <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(19)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(20)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(21)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(22)</ref> or large angle twisted bilayer graphene <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(23)</ref>, and is instead more similar to the conductance of graphene closely aligned with an hBN substrate (2-4). As we explain below, we associate the satellite conductance minima with filling the first two bands of states produced by the moiré crystal with electrons or holes. Surprisingly, the satellite conductance minima are more pronounced than for graphene on hBN, occur at different carrier densities per moiré period, and have a temperature dependence that suggests a gap has opened for charged excitations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Moiré Bloch Bands. In reciprocal space, the first Brillouin zone (BZ) of monolayer graphene is a hexagon. When a second layer is added with a twist angle (θ) with respect to the first, the corners of the two layer BZs are displaced from each other by a wave vector ΔK = 2Ksinðθ=2Þ, where K is the magnitude of the reciprocal lattice vector at the BZ corner at which the gap between conduction Significance Accurately controlled, very long wavelength moiré patterns are realized in small-twist-angle bilayer graphene, and studied using electron transport and scanning probe microscopy. We observe gaps in electron transport at anomalous densities equal to ±8 electrons per moiré crystal unit cell, at variance with electronic structure theory, and the emergence of a Hofstadter butterfly in the energy spectrum in perpendicular magnetic fields. These findings open up an avenue to create artificial crystals by manipulating the relative angle between individual layers in a heterostructure. and valence bands closes in graphene. This relative rotation between the layers leads to a (moiré) BZ with reciprocal lattice vectors that are proportional to the twist angle (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2A</ref>). In real space, the rotation is manifested by a long-wavelength moiré pattern with λ = a=ð2sinðθ=2ÞÞ, where a is the graphene lattice constant. Within the moiré pattern unit cell, the local bilayer stacking configuration varies (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2B</ref>). Gradual changes between AA-like regions in which the real-space hexagons lie nearly on top of each other, and alternating AB and BA (Bernal) regions in which half the lattice points of one layer are in the middle of the hexagonal plaquettes of the other are readily recognized in the generically noncrystalline structure.</p><p>A good starting point for thinking about the electronic properties of STA bilayer graphene in the nonperturbative regime is to use the electronic structure model derived in ref. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15</ref> that adds interlayer tunneling to individual layer Dirac models, and accounts for the structural moiré pattern illustrated in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2B</ref> through a corresponding spatial pattern in the sublattice dependence of tunneling. This model does not account for atomic relaxations in the individual layer honeycomb lattices, which are certainly present, or for electron-electron interactions. Because it has the periodicity of the moiré pattern, this model is relatively easily solved numerically by taking advantage of translational symmetry, and yields (moiré) bands in a momentum space BZ defined by the moiré pattern. Each band in the moiré BZ accommodates 4 electrons per moiré period when spin and valley degrees of freedom are included. The model's predictions for several different twist angles are summarized in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2C</ref>, where we see that even for twist angles as small as ≅2°(5, 10, 13), the Dirac cones (linear band crossings) of the isolated layers, centered at K and K′, respectively, are still recognizable. The van Hove singularity that appears at the midpoint between K and K′ (the M point) is an important feature of twisted bilayer graphene's electronic structure in the perturbative regime and produces observable features in the tunneling density-of-states (TDOS). The gap between conduction and valence bands is largest at the moiré BZ center (Γ). For twist angles smaller than ≅2°(14, 15), however, the low-energy (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2C</ref>) band structure begins to depart qualitatively from the perturbative limit, becoming highly sensitive to twist angle. The moiré bands at the first magic twist angle (∼1°) are illustrated in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2C</ref>, where we see that the lowest conduction and valence bands are extremely flat, and nearly degenerate even at the Γ-point, where some higher-energy bands are also present at low energies. For twist angles below the first magic angle, the low-energy bands seem to partially recover their perturbative-regime form, except that a second pair of flat bands appears at low energy. Because the energetic widths of these moiré bands can be comparable to or smaller than the characteristic energy scale for interactions between the electrons that occupy these bands, e 2 =4π« 0 «λ, physical properties in this regime might be expected to be strongly altered by correlations; e is the electron charge, « 0 is the vacuum dielectric permittivity, and « = 3 is the hBN relative dielectric constant so e 2 =4π« 0 «λ ≅ 20 meV for λ ≅ 20 nm. Indeed, our observations demonstrate that this is the case.</p><p>SPM in STA Bilayer Graphene. Because we expect a strong dependence of electronic properties on twist angle, it is critically important that the angle achieved by the rotation process be directly measured. To this end, we use scanning tunneling microscopy and spectroscopy to examine the topography of the longwavelength moiré patterns and their local electronic properties <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(24)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(25)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(26)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(27)</ref>. The SPM samples are realized using the techniques of Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">1</ref> A-D but do not possess a top-gate stack. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2D</ref> shows an SPM topography image of a moiré pattern with λ = 20.1 ± 0.6 nm, corresponding to a twist angle of θ = 0.7 ± 0.03°. The AA stacked regions appear as bright spots, demonstrating that the low-energy TDOS is enhanced at these sites, consistent with theoretical studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14)</ref>. To understand the electronic properties more deeply, we perform TDOS spectroscopy measurements as a function of position. The spatially averaged results measured at a back-gate voltage V BG = -31 V applied on the doped Si substrate, such that the sample is undoped, are shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2E</ref> (black trace). We observe two low-energy TDOS peaks flanking the charge neutrality point (red solid line at the Fermi level), followed by two dips in the TDOS marked by red dashed lines. Two additional TDOS peaks occur at higher energies. Using the back-gate voltage, we tune the carrier density and find that at V BG = 2 V the first conduction band TDOS dip aligns with the Fermi level, while the dip associated with the charge neutrality point weakens (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2E</ref>, blue trace). Using the measured moiré unit cell area A = ð ffiffi ffi 3 p =2Þλ 2 and the back-gate capacitance of 10.8 nF/cm 2 , we find that the conduction band TDOS dip corresponds to a bilayer density of 7.8 ± 0.6 electrons per moiré unit cell, corresponding to 2 electrons for each spin and valley degree of freedom. This observation was reproduced in four moiré patterns with twist angles ranging between 0.7°and 1°and contrasts with observations made in the larger twist angle perturbative regime, which show dips near 4 electrons per moiré unit cell. Perhaps unsurprisingly, this observation contrasts with the density-of-states (DOS) calculated from the noninteracting electron model summarized by Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2C</ref> data, which show minima at ±4 carriers per moiré unit cell (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">S1</ref>). The complete evolution of the TDOS with back-gate voltage is plotted in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2F</ref>. The data show a central peak, which remains near the Fermi level for all gate voltages, splits when the sample is charge neutral (V BG = -31 V), and moves upward in energy relative to a more rigid background as the central peak states are occupied. The movement of the two dips associated with filling 8 electrons per moiré period are shown by the dashed lines for both the conduction and valence bands. These qualitative changes in TDOS shape with carrier density do not occur in isolated graphene sheets or at larger twist angles, and can be explained only by electron-electron interaction effects.</p><p>Electron Transport in STA Bilayer Graphene. In Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3A</ref>, we present the four-point longitudinal resistance (R xx ) vs. n measured in a series of bilayer graphene samples with twist angles θ &lt; 1°. The data show R xx local maxima at neutrality, along with pronounced satellite R xx maxima at finite n values. The resistivity behavior at neutrality is similar to that in moiré crystals realized in graphene on hBN. Based on the observations in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2</ref> D-F data, the θ-values were assigned assuming a carrier density of ±8 electrons per moiré unit cell at the satellite R xx maxima. We note that the θ-values determined using this assumption are smaller by 0.1-0.2°with respect to the relative rotation angle used during the graphene layers transfer. We attribute this reduction to a tendency of the two graphene monolayers to rotate toward Bernal stacking (θ = 0°) during the annealing steps that follow the layer transfer, an observation verified by SPM measurements. As shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3B</ref>, the conductance measured in lateral moiré periods (W/λ, where W is the sample width) is approximately independent of twist angle, and comparable to e 2 /h when n/n 0 ≅ 4; n/n 0 ≡ nA is the density per moiré unit cell, and h is the Planck constant. These data suggest that the number of quantum transport channels is proportional to W/λ. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3C</ref> shows R xx vs. n in an STA bilayer graphene with θ = 0.97°, measured at different temperatures. The data show insulating temperature dependence at n = ± 4.5 × 10 12 cm -2 , suggesting a gap opening at ±8 electrons per moiré unit cell and weaker temperature dependence at charge neutrality. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3D</ref> summarizes the G vs. T -1 values at charge neutrality (K), and at n = ± 4.5 × 10 12 cm -2 [Γ(+) and Γ(-)]. The Γ(+) and Γ(-) data can be fit by assuming a combination of activated ð G ∝ e -ðΔ=2kTÞ Þ, and variable range-hopping ðG ∝ e -ðT0=TÞ 1=3 Þ conduction processes, with an energy gap Δ = 15 ± 5 meV; k is the Boltzmann constant, and T 0 ≈ 0.5 K is a fitting parameter. The presence of the transport gap is qualitatively consistent with Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">2F</ref> data, and the gap value is comparable with the estimated interaction scale for electrons localized in one period of the moiré pattern. A potential energy difference between the layers can dramatically change bilayer graphene electronic properties, for example giving rise to a tunable band gap in Bernal stacked bilayer graphene. To reveal the role of a potential energy difference induced by a transverse electric field (E) on the transport properties of STA bilayer graphene, in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3E</ref> we show a contour plot of R xx vs. top and back-gate biases (V TG , V BG ) in the θ = 0.97°sample at T = 1.5 K. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3F</ref> replots the same data as a function of the density per moiré unit cell n=n 0 , and E = (C TG • V TG -C BG • V BG )/2e 0 , where C TG and C BG are the top and back-gate capacitances, respectively. The data in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">3</ref> E and F reveal two remarkable findings. First, the R xx maxima are continuously present at 0 and ±8 electrons per moiré unit cell, over a wide range of transverse E fields. Most remarkable is the presence of an R xx maximum at charge neutrality in the entire E field range, particularly because band structure calculations show that the DOS minimum at charge neutrality disappears when an on-site energy difference is applied between the layers (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S2</ref>). This observation is consistent with other indications that the conductance minimum at charge neutrality is stabilized by electron-electron interactions.</p><p>Our observations are only partly understood. We associate the appearance of satellite resistance peaks at ±8 electrons per moiré period for twist angles below the first magic angle, instead of at the ±4 electron density expected in the perturbative regime <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29)</ref>, with the second flat band present near the Dirac point. The appearance of an electron-electron interaction-induced pseudogap at neutrality can be understood in terms of the expected instability of linear band crossings (Dirac bands) in two dimensions at small Fermi velocities, and its insensitivity to a displacement field between the layers can be understood in terms of the strong hybridization between layers in low-energy bands at STA <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">(15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30)</ref>. Finally, the upward energetic shift of the central peak states relative to the background as they are filled, clearly visible in the SPM measurements, can be understood in terms of the localization of these wavefunctions near AA points in the moiré pattern.</p><p>Magnetotransport and the Hofstadter Butterfly. We now turn to the magnetotransport properties of STA bilayer graphene. The energy spectrum of a 2D electron system subject to a spatially periodic potential, and a perpendicular magnetic field (B) has a fractal structure known as the Hofstadter butterfly, characterized by two topological integers: ν, representing the Hall conductivity in units of e 2 /h, and s, the index of subband filling <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(31)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">(32)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">(33)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(34)</ref>. Gaps in the energy spectrum are observed when the density per moiré unit cell and the magnetic flux per moiré unit cell (ϕ ≡ BA) satisfy the following Diophantine equation:</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">n n 0 = ν ϕ ϕ 0 + s,<label>[1]</label></formula><p>where ϕ 0 = h=e is the quantum of magnetic flux. For s = 0, the integer ν reverts to the number of electrons per flux quanta, or Landau level (LL) filling factor. Conversely, in the limit of small B fields the integer s is the moiré band filling factor. A representative subset of the quantum Hall states (QHSs) that satisfy Eq. 1 is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">4A</ref>.  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">S3</ref>) at ν = 1-3 break the spin and valley degeneracy <ref type="bibr">(20-22, 35, 36)</ref>. Although a full description of the ground states at these filling factors is beyond the scope of this work, these QHSs can only be by interaction, and their observation is consistent with electron-electron interactions dominating the transport properties of STA bilayer graphene at B = 0 T. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">4D</ref> shows the evolution of the QHSs as a function of E field examined in the same sample by sweeping V TG and V BG at a fixed magnetic field. The data show that R xx at neutrality is reduced in an applied E field, suggesting a weakening of the (ν, s) = (0, 0) state. Whereas the observation is similar to the evolution of the lowest orbital LL QHSs in Bernal stacked bilayer graphene associated with the spin-to-valley polarized transition, we note that the (ν, s) = (±1, 0), (±2,0), (±3,0) remain visible in the accessible E field range (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">S3</ref>).</p><p>In summary, we demonstrate controlled moiré crystals with long wavelengths in STA bilayer graphene, and probe the electronic properties by SPM and electron transport. The data reveal pseudogaps that open at neutrality and ±8 electrons per moiré BZ, which are robust with respect to an applied transverse electric field, cannot be explained by electronic structure calculations, and are likely stabilized by electron-electron interaction. In high magnetic fields, we observe a Hofstadter butterfly in the energy spectrum, with subband indices of ±8, and broken symmetry states in the lowest LL.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>moiré crystal | graphene | twisted bilayer | moiré band | Hofstadter butterfly</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Author contributions: B.J.L., A.H.M., and E.T. designed research; K.K., A.D., S.H., B.F., S.L., B.J.L., A.H.M., and E.T. performed research; T.T. and K.W. contributed materials (hBN); K.K., S.H., B.J.L., A.H.M., and E.T. analyzed data; and K.K., A.D., S.H., B.J.L., A.H.M., and E.T. wrote the paper. Reviewers: P.K., Harvard University; and K.S.N., University of Manchester. Conflict of interest statement: A.H.M. published a paper with P.K. in 2016 based on work performed primarily during 2013. A.H.M. and P.K. are not active collaborators. T.T. and K.W. have published papers with both reviewers. Their role in these papers was providing materials, and there was no active collaboration.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. STA bilayer graphene. (A) Optical micrograph showing a single graphene flake, subsequently split into two sections along the dotted line. (B) The first section is detached from the substrate using a hemispherical handle. (C) The second section is detached from the substrate using the same hemispherical handle. The substrate is rotated by a small angle between the two steps. Because the two flakes stem from the same graphene domain, an STA is introduced between the crystal axes of the individual layers. (D) Schematic illustration of the moiré pattern formation as a result of the twist angle between the two layers. (E) Optical micrograph of an STA bilayer graphene sample. (F) G vs. V TG (bottom axis) and n (top axis) measured in an STA bilayer graphene sample at different temperatures.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,39.91,52.78,500.67,159.36" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. SPM mapping of the moiré pattern in an STA bilayer graphene, and DOS. (A) The first BZ of each graphene layer, and of the moiré pattern. (B) Illustration of the local stacking in twisted bilayer graphene. (C) Moiré bands of twisted bilayer graphene. For twist angles θ larger than 2°most states are strongly localized in one layer, linear band crossings (Dirac points) occur at the moiré BZ corners (K, K′) with velocities that are slightly suppressed relative to those of the isolated graphene, a van Hove singularity occurs at the midpoint of K and K′, and a small gap opens at the center of the moiré BZ (Γ), at the extrema of the first moiré conduction and valence bands. For θ ∼ 1°the first moiré bands are extremely narrow. For smaller twist angles, a second conduction and valence band are present at energies below the Γ-centered gaps. The lowest-energy bands above and below charge neutrality are shown in blue and red, respectively. (D) SPM topography image showing a λ = 20.1 nm moiré pattern. The sample voltage is 0.3 V and the tunnel current is 100 pA. (E) TDOS at two different backgate voltages, -31 V (black) and +2 V (blue). The features corresponding to the charge neutrality point and the secondary dips in the TDOS curves are marked by solid and dashed lines, respectively. The traces are offset for clarity. (F) TDOS as a function of sample voltage and back-gate voltage. The solid and dashed lines trace the movement of the charge neutrality point and the secondary dip in the TDOS. The data of D-F were collected at T = 4.5 K.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,44.39,52.78,500.67,301.38" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Evolution of STA bilayer graphene transport properties with twist angle, transverse E field, and temperature. (A) R xx vs. n measured at T = 1.5 K in STA bilayer graphene with different twist angles. (B) Normalized conductance (Gλ/W) vs. density per moiré unit cell (n/n 0 ) in STA bilayer graphene samples with different twist angles. (C) R xx vs. n at different temperatures measured in an STA bilayer graphene sample with λ = 14.5 nm, corresponding to θ = 0.97°. (D) Arrhenius plot of G measured at the K and Γ points in the sample of C. The data show an activated dependence at elevated temperatures consistent with an energy gap, coupled with variable range hopping at low temperatures. (E) Contour plot of R xx vs. V TG and V BG measured at T = 1.5 K in the STA bilayer graphene sample of C and D. The density separation between the peak at charge neutrality and the peaks at Γ is independent of the E field. (F) Contour plot of data in E as a function of n (top axis), n/n 0 (bottom axis), and transverse E field.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,39.35,52.78,501.74,303.82" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. Magnetotransport properties of STA bilayer graphene. (A) LL fan diagram constructed using the Diophantine equation 1. The green (orange) lines represent QHSs observed experimentally in C at ν = ±4, 8, 12 and s = 0 (s = ± 8). The purple lines represent broken-symmetry QHSs at ν = ±1, 2, 3 and s = 0 corresponding to C data. (B) R xx (Top) and R xy (Bottom) vs. V TG measured at B = 10 T, and T = 1.5 K in an STA bilayer graphene with θ = 0.97°. The ν-values are marked for each QHS. The QHSs with ν = ±4, 8, 12 and s = 0 (s = ±8) are marked in green (orange). The QHSs with ν = ±1, 2, 3 are marked in purple. (C) Contour plot of R xx as a function of ϕ/ϕ 0 and n/n 0 in the same sample. The ϕ/ϕ 0 = 1 value corresponds to B = 24.5 T. The data are measured at T = 1.5 K up to B = 14 T, and at T = 5 K for B fields larger than 15 T. (D) Contour plot of R xx vs. n/n 0 and E field, at B = 12 T, and T = 1.5 K. The ν-values are marked for each QHS. The QHSs with ν = ±4, 8, 12 and s = 0 (s = ±8) are marked in green (orange). Several transitions are observed as a function of the transverse E field, with R xx at (ν, s) = (0, 0) decreasing with the applied E field.</figDesc><graphic coords="5,43.82,192.13,501.74,457.51" type="bitmap" /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1" xml:id="foot_0"><p>To whom correspondence may be addressed. Email: leroy@email.arizona.edu, macd@ physics.utexas.edu, or etutuc@mer.utexas.edu. This article contains supporting information online at www.pnas.org/lookup/suppl/doi:10. 1073/pnas.1620140114/-/DCSupplemental.3364-3369 | PNAS | March</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_1"><p>28, 2017 | vol. 114 | no. 13 www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1620140114 Downloaded from https://www.pnas.org by 147.161.137.100 on March 4, 2025 from IP address 147.161.137.100.</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_2"><p>Downloaded from https://www.pnas.org by 147.161.137.100 on March 4, 2025 from IP address 147.161.137.100.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. We thank <rs type="person">Hema C. P. Movva</rs> for technical assistance. This work was supported by the <rs type="funder">Semiconductor Research Corporation Nanoelectronics Research Initiative SWAN center, National Science Foundation (NSF)</rs> Grants <rs type="grantNumber">EECS-1610008</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">EECS-1607911</rs>, the <rs type="funder">US Army Research Office</rs> under Grant <rs type="grantNumber">W911NF-14-1-0653</rs>, <rs type="funder">Samsung Corporation</rs>, and <rs type="funder">Welch Foundation</rs> Grant <rs type="grantNumber">TBF1473</rs>. A portion of this work was performed at the <rs type="institution">National High Magnetic Field Laboratory</rs>, which is supported by <rs type="funder">NSF</rs> Cooperative Agreement DMR-<rs type="grantNumber">1157490</rs> and the <rs type="institution">State of Florida</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_s8M3n8s">
					<idno type="grant-number">EECS-1610008</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_ueMM4H2">
					<idno type="grant-number">EECS-1607911</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_a6XMYFw">
					<idno type="grant-number">W911NF-14-1-0653</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_n3MH8Zt">
					<idno type="grant-number">TBF1473</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_QA9xnPT">
					<idno type="grant-number">1157490</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scanning tunnelling microscopy and spectroscopy of ultra-flat graphene on hexagonal boron nitride</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Mater</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cloning of Dirac fermions in graphene superlattices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ponomarenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">497</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7451</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="594" to="597" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hofstadter&apos;s butterfly and the fractal quantum Hall effect in moiré superlattices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">497</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7451</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="598" to="602" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Massive Dirac fermions and Hofstadter butterfly in a van der Waals heterostructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Hunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">340</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6139</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1427" to="1430" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Graphene bilayer with a twist: Electronic structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lopes Dos Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nmr</forename><surname>Peres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Castro</forename><surname>Neto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">256802</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Commensuration and interlayer coherence in twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mele</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">161405</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic structure of turbostratic graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Shallcross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kandelaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pankratov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">165105</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emergence of superlattice Dirac points in graphene on hexagonal boron nitride</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yankowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="382" to="386" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continuum model of the twisted graphene bilayer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jmbl</forename><surname>Dos Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nmr</forename><surname>Peres</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Castro</forename><surname>Neto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">155449</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence for interlayer coupling and moiré periodic potentials in twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">186807</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unraveling the intrinsic and robust nature of van Hove singularities in twisted bilayer graphene by scanning tunneling microscopy and theoretical analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Brihuega</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">196802</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Commensurate-incommensurate transition in graphene on hexagonal boron nitride</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Woods</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Energy spectrum and quantum Hall effect in twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Koshino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">195458</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Localization of Dirac electrons in rotated graphene bilayers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Trambly</forename><surname>De Laissardière</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mayou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Magaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="804" to="808" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moire bands in twisted double-layer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bistritzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="12233" to="12237" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">van der Waals heterostructures with high accuracy rotational alignment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1989" to="1995" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Boron nitride substrates for high-quality graphene electronics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Nanotechnol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="722" to="726" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One-dimensional electrical contact to a two-dimensional material</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">342</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6158</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="614" to="617" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Direct observation of a widely tunable bandgap in bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">459</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7248</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="820" to="823" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Broken-symmetry states in doubly gated suspended bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Weitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Yacoby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">330</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6005</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="812" to="816" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chemical potential and quantum Hall ferromagnetism in bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">345</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6192</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="58" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tunable fractional quantum Hall phases in bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Maher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">345</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6192</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantum Hall effect, screening, and layerpolarized insulating states in twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sanchez-Yamagishi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">108</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">76601</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Observation of Van Hove singularities in twisted graphene layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="109" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Single-layer behavior and its breakdown in twisted graphene layers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Luican</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">126802</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Angle-dependent van Hove singularities in a slightly twisted graphene bilayer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">109</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">126801</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Local spectroscopy of moire-induced electronic structure in gate-tunable twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">155409</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Charge inversion and topological phase transition at a twist angle induced van Hove singularity of bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5053" to="5059" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Superlattice-induced insulating states and valley-protected orbits in twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">116804</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic properties of asymmetrically doped twisted graphene bilayers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>De Laissardiere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Namarvar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mayou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Magaud</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">235135</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Energy-levels and wave-functions of Bloch electrons in rational and irrational magnetic-fields</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hofstadter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2239" to="2249" />
			<date type="published" when="1976">1976</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Magnetic subband structure of electrons in hexagonal lattices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Claro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Wannier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6068" to="6074" />
			<date type="published" when="1979">1979</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Landau-level subband structure of electrons on a square lattice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6713" to="6717" />
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moire butterflies in twisted bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bistritzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Macdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys Rev B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">84</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">35440</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transport spectroscopy of symmetry-broken insulating states in bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Velasco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jr</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Nanotechnol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="156" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Competing valley, spin, and orbital symmetry breaking in bilayer graphene</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Hunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://arxiv.org/abs/1607.06461" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
