<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bi-level energy optimization model in smart integrated engineering systems using WSN</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2022-02-05">5 February 2022</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Faculty of Information and Communication Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Anna University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Chennai</settlement>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rathinam Technical Campus</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="IN">India</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of ECE</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Hindustan College of Engineering and Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Coimbatore</settlement>
									<country>India Jaya J</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bi-level energy optimization model in smart integrated engineering systems using WSN</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2022-02-05">5 February 2022</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">1EE6B810DBB8B3B4E1D534F25382BAA8</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.egyr.2022.01.183</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 8 November 2021 Received in revised form 1 January 2022 Accepted 22 January 2022</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:37+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Fuzzy interactions Bi-level processing Max-product compilation Asymmetric optimization Implementation of the minimal max-norm matrix are all topics covered</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Based on fuzzy relational inequality, a bi-level linear programme optimizes the visible light brightness and operating costs of access points in a wireless transmission station system. Consider the first computing problem utilizing a minimum solution matrix. A convex infinite set is generated by a restricted number of closed intervals. Second, computing is an objective-domain nonlinear mathematical optimization problem. A multi-objective optimization problem is used to solve the second programming challenge. The constraint set must be used. Use discrete optimization techniques and branch-and-bound procedures for ''digital integer linear programming''. Our technique has been shown to be both practical and successful. The programming complexity increases as the organization expands.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">Introduction</head><p>Fuzzy relational algebra, which was developed by E. Sanchez in the 1970s, has been a prominent part of medical research for over three decades. In addition to equations and inequalities, fuzzy relation systems, which embed both, have proven effective in numerous practical contexts, including fuzzy inference systems, texture analysis and reconstruction, clinical issues, knowledge engineering, three-tier streaming media systems based on the HTTP protocol, P2P computer networks, and Bit torrent-like P2P network systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Wu and Guu, 2004)</ref>. There are two major research themes in fuzzy relational systems: The first research objective is to resolve a fuzzy relation system with a specific composition <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(Qiu et al., 2020)</ref>. It demonstrates that it is the bedrock of the majority of relevant research. The second area of research is fuzzy relation optimization problems, which have a fuzzy relation system as a constraint <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Yang et al., 2016)</ref>. Fuzzy relation optimization challenges frequently rely on a number of management objectives and needs to create their objective functions. Single-level objective problems are the majority of the optimization problems with a constraint on a fuzzy relational system. Additionally, system administrators may have additional requirements that must be taken into consideration when single-level optimization is employed. <ref type="bibr">Yang et al. examined</ref> single-level min-max programming using a BT-P2P file-sharing system <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Rastogi et al., 2015;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Bulanov et al., 2004)</ref>. <ref type="bibr">Guu et al. developed</ref> bi-level optimization to achieve a balance of realistic management requirements <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Bjorklund et al., 2003;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Pedrycz, 1985)</ref>.</p><p>As per further explored difficult managerial requirements by creating a three-tiered optimization problem for the firm <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(Stamou and Tzafestas, 2001;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">Shieh, 2007)</ref>. Their solution for bilevel optimization with max-product fuzzy relation inequalities included wireless communication. The goals' aspects allow for both management qualities. Fairness was applied to the wireless communication station system. Growing numbers of individuals utilize wireless communication. Signals, data, and information are delivered by fixed emission basic stations. Start from the premise to n EBSs, for example, A 1 , A 2 , . . .. An (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Markovskii, 2005)</ref>. The jth EBS will emit a high-intensity electromagnetic wave x j &gt; 0, j = 1, 2, . . . , n. The channel of interaction determines the intensity of electromagnetic waves <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Bi et al., 2014)</ref>.</p><p>B 1 , B 2 , . . . .B m testing points are required at each location to guarantee the communication quality criteria is chosen to measure the electromagnetic radiation's intensity (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Lin and Yang, 2020)</ref>. The amount of electromagnetic radiation released by a substance A j is denoted by a ij x j at the ith testing point B i <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Yang et al., 2015)</ref>. It must be assumed that at B i , minimal quality of communication is required is b i (bi &gt; 0). Reduced all parameters to a unit interval [0, 1] and explained the model with the help of fuzzy relations <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(Guu and Wu, 2019)</ref>. a m1 x 1 Va m2 x 2 V . . . Va mn x n≥ bm} (1)</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">{a 11 x 1 Va 12 x 2 V . . . Va 1n x n≥ b 1 a 21 x 1 Va 22 x 2 V . . . Va 2n x n≥ b2 . . .</formula><formula xml:id="formula_1">A • Tx T T ≥ Tb T (2) where A = (a ij ) (m×n) ∈ [0, 1] m×n , x = (x 1 , x 2 , . . . , x n ) ∈ [0, 1] n , b = (b 1 , b 2 , . . . ., b m ) ∈ [0, 1] m ,</formula><p>and • denote the composition of the maximum product <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(Sofi et al., 2015)</ref>.</p><p>Many people agree that the human body is negatively impacted by electromagnetic waves. To restrict or eliminate the negative effects of electromagnetic fields on the human body, it is critical to keep both the system performance and the strength of the electromagnetic radiation the same. Variable x(x 1 , = x 2 , x 3 , x 4 . . . x n ) can play a significant role because of this <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Guu et al., 2017)</ref>. Therefore, we should try to lower the intensity of electromagnetic fields, the variables that meet the system (1). To address this, the team of Yang et al. discovered a latticed linear programming as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">min z i (x) = x 1 ∨ x 2 ∨ x 3 . . . x n s.t Aox T ≥ b T</formula><p>By reducing the need to seek all minimal approaches to the limitation system, this novel approach saved the researchers time (1). X 1 (A, b) includes the following: The primary purpose of (3) is to maintain the maximum quantity of radiation while keeping the quantity at a minimal. A systems analyst must keep in mind that excessive energy output could harm the human body. Even still, Theorem 4 in Section 3) shows that there are no unique optimal solutions to Problem (3). X 1 (A, b) is an infinite set of optimum solution to Problem (3), sometimes known as X 1 (A, b). As a result, we use an unlimited set of X 1 (A, b) values to look for the most ideal solution, which employs a second optimization objective <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Shang et al., 2014)</ref>. In the above definition, optimizing the second objective given X 1 (A, b). Constraint reuse is a secondlevel issue. To increase non-operational base stations, we must reduce operational base stations. When base stations fail, their maintenance costs fall. The second goal is to reduce base station operating costs.</p><p>While a non-functional base station has no electro-magnetic strength, a functional base station does. For instance, in order to keep the zero norm of the vector x = (x 1 , x 2 , x 3 , x 4 . . . x n ) at the lowest possible level, one must not deploy additional base stations <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Alcalá-Fdez and Alonso, 2015)</ref>. It is the number of non-zero elements in x, such as x 0 .</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">∥x∥ 0 = |{i|x i ̸ = 0, 1 ≤ i ≤ n}|</formula><p>Due to this, the second objective is changed to be the min ∥x∥ 0 value. This difficulty is described as follows:</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">min ∥x∥ 0 s.t x ∈ X 1 (A, b)</formula><p>By combining the first and second level issues, we obtain <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(Morshedy et al., 2019)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">min z 1 (x) = x 1 ∨ x 2 ∨ x 3 ∨ x 4 • • • ∨ x n - (3) s.t Aox T ≥ b T , min z 2 (x) = ∥x∥ 0 , s.t x ∈ X 1 (A, b) (4)</formula><p>Problem-solving solutions are compiled through a process called X 1 (A, b) (3). Aim 1 in Problems (3)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) is to keep electromagnetic waves intensity as low as possible, whereas objective 2 is to keep base station operating expenses as low as possible. Problem (3) can be solved using the idea of a minimal solution matrix presented by Yang et al. While Yang's method fails to provide the whole solution set to the problem, this paper will prove that (3). We could not employ Yang's methods in the original study since it did not address the bi-level problem. This study seeks to discover the best possible solution to the problem stated above, which is bi-level objective programming (3), (4). The final section of Section 3 looks at the ideal solution set for Problem (3) and measures its quality by utilizing a minimum-maximum norm solution matrix. This chapter studies the problem at the second level (4). We use the set of minimum-norm solutions to solve the problem (4). We have included a mathematical example in Section 5 to show how and why our proposed method might be implemented and would produce accurate results. Section 4 discusses several forms of management requirements in order to highlight multiple kinds of bi-level difficulties.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.">Yang's method for first level problems</head><p>The optimal solution to the issue addressed in this Section 3. Specifically, Yang's method can only be utilized to discover a limited number of optimum solutions to the given problem (3). While it is true that, in some situations, the set of any and all efficient outcomes to Problem (3) is not a convex infinite set, it is possible for some non-convex solutions to exist, too. Yang's method has the unfortunate property of being unable to uncover all potential answers to the problem (3). Also, it has little to no effect on the bi-level problem (3)-(4).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1.">Yang's problem-solving method is based on the matrix of minimal solutions</head><formula xml:id="formula_6">∀x = (x 1 , x 2 , x 3 , x 4 , . . . x n ) ∈ [0, 1] n which denotes mas norm -∥x∥ ∞ = max 1≤j≤n x j = x 1 ∨ x 2 ∨ x 3 ∨ • • • ∨ x n where ∥x∥ ∞</formula><p>Consider the set X (A, b) be the sum of all system (1) solutions, i.e.</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">X (A, b) = x ∈ [0, 1] n |A • x T ≥ b T If so, the best solution set for Problem (3) is X (A, b). X (A, b) = x 1 * ∈ X (A, b)|∥x 1 * ∥ ∞ , ∀x ∈ X (A, b)</formula><p>As per Discrimination Matrix definition <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Loetamonphong and Fang, 1999</ref>)</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, 1 ≤ j ≤ n, gives d ij = x = { b i a ij }, if a ij ≥ b i , 0, if a ij &lt; b i (5)</formula><p>The system's discrimination matrix is known as D = (d ij ) m×n .</p><p>Theorem 1. x must be a vector whose components are {1, 1, 1 . . . 1}.</p><p>For system (1), each column of the discrimination matrix D must contain a nonzero <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Shieh, 2008)</ref>. The solution matrix D = (d ij ) m×n for the system. The system's solution matrix is S = (S ij ) where S ij is in the set {0, d ij }.</p><p>Theorem 2. If S = (S ij ) m×n is a solution to the system, then S = (s 1 , s 2 , s 3 , s 4 , . . . , s n ). When the vector was considered.</p><formula xml:id="formula_9">X S = (∥S T 1 ∥ ∞ , ∥S T 2 ∥ ∞ , ∥S T 3 ∥ ∞ , ∥S T 4 ∥ ∞ , . . . ∥S T n ∥ ∞ ), = ∨ m i=1 S i1 , ∨ m i=1 S i2 , ∨ m i=1 S i3 , ∨ m i=1 S i4 , . . . , ∨ m</formula><p>i=1 S in , is the solution.</p><p>If S = (S ij ) m×n The system's solution matrix.</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">X S = ∨ m i=1 S i1 , ∨ m i=1 S i2 , ∨ m i=1 S i3 , ∨ m i=1 S i4 , . . . , ∨ m i=1 S in ,<label>(6)</label></formula><p>The end result is a matrix solution of system (1) from S.</p><p>Lemma 1. A solution matrix S exists for (1)</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">, S = x i.e. X S ≤ x, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m.</formula><p>Let,</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">r i = min 1≤j≤n {d ij |d ij ̸ = 0}, (7) R i = {j|d ij = r i , 1 ≤ j ≤ n}. (8)</formula><p>The significant definition in this part is a minimum matrix. The lowest solution matrices (1) is a matrix S m = (S m ij ) that has these properties: S m a system solution matrix (1) <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Yang et al., 2015)</ref></p><formula xml:id="formula_13">. ∀j / ∈ R i , S m ij = 0.</formula><p>Additional claims state that S m is the smallest basic matrix solution to X S m . Theorem 3 asserts that if system (1) has (i.e. S m ), then X S m is the corresponding minimal solution to problem (3). The system</p><formula xml:id="formula_14">minimal solution matrix is denoted as MSM = S m . X ms (A, b) = {X s m |S m ∈ MSM}. By Yang's method, only specific solutions of Problem (3) can be found, that is, X S m (A, b).</formula><p>A second look at the set X S m (A, b), which Yang's approach obtains, as seen below. So for Problem (3), X S m (A, b) might not equal to X 1 (A, b). As Theorem 3 claims, there is a unique solution to Problem X s ∈ X ms (A, b) when X s is the best possible solution (3). It is possible, but this is still only an optimization approach that does not guarantee that a solution is optimal (4) <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(Luoh and Liaw, 2010)</ref>. We cannot solve Problem (3) to (4) as it is (A, b). Thus, X S m is not the best solution (11) (or: it is not the optimal solution)? X ms (A, b) ̸ = X 1 (A, b).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.">Problems with minimum-maximum norm solution matrices (3)</head><p>On the other side, in this part, we explore the best collection of Problem solutions (3) (which we denote as X 1 (A, b)) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Fang and Li, 1999)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.">Multiple norm solution matrix</head><p>A consistent system (1) implies an optimal solution to problem (3) <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Bělohlávek et al., 2017)</ref>.</p><formula xml:id="formula_15">r max-min = max 1≤i≤m r i = max 1≤i≤m min 1≤j≤n {d ij |d ij ̸ = 0} (9)</formula><p>One final conclusion to draw is that you can use Theorem 3 as well as the notion of minimal solution matrix to evaluate whether or not an argument is correct <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Anderson, 1974)</ref>.</p><p>If a system is constant, the optimal solution to the issue is reached.</p><p>x1 * = (r max-min , r max-min , r max-min , . . . , r max-min ).</p><p>(10)</p><p>Based on the theorem,</p><formula xml:id="formula_16">x 1 * = x 1 * 1 , x 1 * 2 , x 1 * 3 , . . . .x 1 *</formula><p>n is a solution to problem X. (3). The only way to resolve the problem is to find a solution (3). Next, we solve for</p><formula xml:id="formula_17">x 1 * 1 ∨ x 1 * 2 ∨ x 1 * 3 ∨ • • • x 1 * n = r max-min</formula><p>in the following system (1).</p><p>So, ∀1 ≤ j ≤ n, x 1 * j ≤ r max-min , which is addressed as x 1 * ≤ x1 * .</p><p>(11)</p><p>Accordingly, x1 * = (r max-min , r max-min , r max-min . . . r max-min ) is also a solution to the problem in question, which means that an acceptable solution to that problem can be found. Finally, we can conclude that</p><formula xml:id="formula_18">x1 * 1 ∨ x1 * 2 ∨ x1 * 3 ∨ • • • ∨ x1 * n = r max-min</formula><p>When these elements are merged, the result is the best solution to the issue (3). Finally, using the value r max-min : The smallest and the maximum-norm discrimination matrix is shown in Eq. ( <ref type="formula">11</ref>). D can be modelled as a discrimination matrix (1). Matrix with cross products of vectors</p><formula xml:id="formula_19">t ij = d ij d ij ≤ r max-min , 0, otherwise. system</formula><p>(1) has a minimum maximum-norm discrimination matrix whose elements are m × n. Matrix T can be computed from D as follows: Replace all the entries d ij with zero, if d ij &gt; r max-min .</p><p>Assume system (1) is complete. In this matrix, D is not zero. After constructing the minimum-maximum norm discrimination matrix, it is possible to check for nonzero elements. The matrix storing the answer to the minimum maximal norm. T is the system's highest mean-square difference discriminating matrix (1). In matrix T = (t ij ) m×n , t ij can have the values 0, t ij , but if there exists a unique ji ∈ {1, 2, 3, 4, . . . , n} such that</p><formula xml:id="formula_20">t ij = 0, then T is a matrix having a minimal maximum norm ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, t ij = t ij ̸ = 0.</formula><p>Also, T is a solution matrix. According to the preceding theorem, let T = (t ij ) m×n be the system's solution matrix (1). A solution matrix must be at least as big as the biggest ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m and 1 ≤ j ≤ n such that t ij ≤ r max-min holds. If system (1) is valid, the lowest absolute maximum solution matrix (or minimum). A minimum-maximum norm matrix solution T = (t ij ) m×n</p><p>for each system's lower-maximum-norm (1). As the system's corresponding solution</p><formula xml:id="formula_21">X T = ∨ m i≤i≤m t i1 , ∨ m i≤i≤m t i2 , ∨ m i≤i≤m t i3 , ∨ m i≤i≤m t i4 , . . . , ∨ m</formula><p>i≤i≤m t in is considered a min-max norm matrix solution, it is called a minimum-maximum norm matrix solution (1). We use MMNS = T |T is a minimum-maximum norm solution matrix of (1) and X mmns (A, b) = X T  |T ∈ MMNS for the system (1).</p><p>When solving a system, all possible min-max norm matrix solutions are simply X mmns <ref type="bibr">(A, b)</ref>. Therefore X mmns (A, b) ̸ = ∅.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.">Optimal solution set of problem</head><p>We summaries the solution set for problem (3) here, and so the above mentioned set X mmns is it (A, b). Problem (3) is best</p><formula xml:id="formula_22">solved if system (1) is consistent.X 1 = ∪ x∈Xmmns(A,b) [x, x1 * ].</formula><p>Collects all matrices with a minimal maximum norm X mmns provides the best results), the optimal value is r max-min . Therefore, we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_23">y 1 ∨ y 2 ∨ y 3 ∨ y 4 • • • ∨ y n ≥ r max-min Also, y ≤ x1 * provides y 1 ∨ y 2 ∨ y 3 ∨ y 4 • • • ∨ y n ≥ r max-min Alternatively, y ∈ X 1 (A, b) indicates the concept of y j ≤ r max-min , ∀1 ≤ j ≤ n. y 1 ∨ y 2 ∨ y 3 ∨ y 4 • • • ∨ y n = r max-min seeking effort to benefit y 1 ≤ r max-min , ∀1 ≤ j ≤ n. A consequence of this is that y ≤ x1 * is an optimum solution to Problem (3), y ∈ X (A, b). Furthermore, we demonstrate that X 1 (A, b) ⊆ ∪ x∈Xmmns(A,b) [x, x1 * ]. Find the most ideal solution for problem y ∈ X (A, b) (3).</formula><p>Similarly, Theorem 2 asserts that if y is an element of X (A, b), then there is a T such that x T</p><formula xml:id="formula_24">≤ y i.e ∨ 1≤i≤m t ij ≤ y j , ∀1 ≤ j ≤ n, it follows that t ij ≤ r max-min , ∀ 1 ≤ i ≤ m, 1 ≤ j ≤ n.</formula><p>T is the system's minimum-maximum-norm solution matrix (1). As a result, X T result, the solution with the lowest max-norm matrix is not unique.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.">The solution to the bilevel problem (3)-(4)</head><p>The purpose of this part is to build an efficient approach for finding the optimal solution to our suggested bi-level Problem (3)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>). Indeed, Problems (3)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) are virtually the same as the subsequent second-level Problem (4),</p><formula xml:id="formula_25">min z 2 (x) = ∥x∥ 0 , s.t x ∈ X 1 (A, b) (A)</formula><p>Theorem 4 proves that the feasible domain, in the majority of cases, i.e. X 1 (A, b) is an infinite yet non-convex set. Additionally, the objective function Z 2 (x) = ∥x∥ 0 is nonlinear and expressible implicitly. As a result, solving Problem (4) directly is challenging. The fourth issue is transformed into a discrete optimization problem min z 2 (x) = ∥x∥ 0 , s.t x ∈ X mmns <ref type="bibr">(A, b)</ref>. Take note that the feasible domain in Problem (A), namely X mmns (A, b), a set of things A conventional branch-and-bound strategy or MATLAB's complex mathematical abilities may be used to tackle this 0-1 integer programming issue. Let T = (t ij ) m×n be the system's minimum-maximum-norm discriminating matrix (1). The index sets</p><formula xml:id="formula_26">{J i |i ∈ I} are defined as J i = {j|t ij ̸ = 0, j ∈ J} (B)</formula><p>where I = {1, 2, 3, . . . , m} and J = {1, 2, 3, . . . , n}. On the basis of the index sets {J i |i ∈ I} acquired previously, we design the following 0-1 integer programming</p><formula xml:id="formula_27">min n ∑ j=1 max 1≤i≤m f ij , s.t n ∑ j=1 f ij = 1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, f ij = 0 or 1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, 1 ≤ j ≤ n, f ij = 0, ∀i, j with j / ∈ J i . (C)</formula><p>Problem (4) (C). A C-solution problem is an efficient solution to issues with optimal solution characteristics, as shown in proofs 6 and 7. The single equations for the above two multi-variable problems are identical; in other words, the multi-variable problems (C) (which can be solved using division method or other standard mathematical software) and the zero-to-one integer linear programming difficulties are correspondingly lowered to one single problem: problem (C).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.">Relationship between (4) and (A)</head><p>This indicates that if XT is the optimal solution for A, it is also optimal for B.</p><p>Proof. Assume X T * ∈ x mmns <ref type="bibr">(A, b)</ref>, where T * ⊆ MMNS is a matrix of minimum max-norm solutions. (Feasibility) As a result of Theorem 4,</p><formula xml:id="formula_28">X T * ∈ x mmns (A, b) ⊆ X 1 (A, b). Assume that y ∈ X 1 (A, b) is a possible option (4). X 1 (A, b) = ∪ x∈Xmmns(A,b) [x, x1 * ].</formula><p>There exists a function</p><formula xml:id="formula_29">X T * ∈ x mmns (A, b) such that X T ≤ y ≤ x1 * denotes ∥x T * ∥0 ≤ ∥y∥ 0 . We have ∥x T * ∥0 ≤ ∥x T ∥ 0 because X T * ∈ x mmns (A, b</formula><p>) is a possible solution to the problem and ideal answer. Inequalities contribute to the value of ∥y∥0 ≤ ∥x T * ∥ 0 .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.">Relationship between (A) and (C)</head><p>Assign the feasible domain of Problem (C) to the symbol X (f ).</p><p>Bear in mind that MMNS denotes the collection ∀ system's minimum maximum norm solution matrix (1). Now, we will establish a correspondence between X (f ) and MMNS.</p><p>ψ</p><formula xml:id="formula_30">: MMNS → X (f ), T → f T</formula><p>where T = (t ij ) m×n is an arbitrarily large minimum-maximumnorm solution matrix, and f T is a matrix representing</p><formula xml:id="formula_31">{f T ij |i ∈ I, j ∈ J}, f T ij = {1 if t ij ̸ = 0} 0 if t ij = 0 Checking if f T is a plausible solution to Problem (C) is easy, i.e. f T ∈ X (f ).</formula><p>Additionally, the mapping ψ the sets are linked one-to-one, MMNS and X (f ) mapping towards</p><formula xml:id="formula_32">ψ -1 : X (f ) → MMNS, f → T f (H)</formula><p>where f = {f ij |i ∈ I, j ∈ J} is an arbitrary feasible solution to the issue (C) and</p><formula xml:id="formula_33">T f = (t ij ) m×n with (t ij ) f = {t ij if f -ij = 1, }0 otherwise. (I) Theorem 3. Assume that f = X (f )T = (t ij ) m×n ∈ MMNS is an arbitrary minimum maximum norm solution matrix. Let f ∈ X (f )</formula><p>provide a potential answer to the problem (C). Then there is</p><formula xml:id="formula_34">∥X T ∥ 0 = n ∑ j=1 min 1≤i≤m f ij (J)</formula><p>where X T is the solution to T .</p><formula xml:id="formula_35">X T = ∨ m i∈I t i1 , ∨ m i∈I t i2 , ∨ m i∈I t i3 , ∨ m i∈I t i4 , . . . , ∨ m i∈I t in Given that f is a realistic solution to problem (C), implies that f ij = 0 or 1, ∀i ∈ I, j ∈ J. This implies ∨ i∈I f ij = 0 or 1, ∀j ∈ J, as |{j ∈ J| ∨ i∈I f ij = 1}| = ∑ j∈J (∨ i∈I f ij ), it has ∥X T ∥ 0 = |{j ∈ J| ∨ i∈I t ij ̸ = 0}| = |{j ∈ J| ∨ i∈I f ij = 1}| = ∑ j∈J ∨ i∈I f ij = n ∑ j∈J max 1≤i≤m f ij (K) Theorem 4. If f * is the best solution (C) and T * = ψ(f * ) = (t ij ) m×n is the minimum maximal norm solution matrix, then X T * = ∨ i∈I t * i1 , ∨ i∈I t * i2 , ∨ i∈I t * i3 , ∨ i∈I t * i4 , . . . , ∨ * i∈I t *</formula><p>in an ideal answer to the issue (A). Given that T * a matrix having a minimal max-norm solution, X T * ∈ X mmns (A, b) is a matrix solution with the smallest maximum norm, i.e. (A).</p><p>Let X T * ∈ X mmns (A, b) denote any possible solution to Problem (A), with T denotes the minimum max-norm quantitative approach. Assume that f = ψ -1 (T ) is an acceptable solution to Problem (C) that matches T . On the other hand, f * denotes the answer to T * . According to Theorem 3,</p><formula xml:id="formula_36">{∥X T ∥ 0 } = n ∑ j=1 max 1≤i≤m f ij , ∥X T ∥ 0 = n ∑ j=1 max 1≤i≤m f * ij , (L)</formula><p>Additionally, because f * is the optimal solution to Problem (C) and f is a viable solution,</p><formula xml:id="formula_37">∑ n j=1 max 1≤i≤m f ij ≥ ∑ n j=1 max 1≤i≤m f * ij -M holds.</formula><p>In light of (L), we have</p><formula xml:id="formula_38">z 2 (x T ) = ∥X T ∥ 0 = n ∑ j=1 max 1≤i≤m f ij ≥ n ∑ j=1 max 1≤i≤m f * ij = ∥X T * ∥ 0 = z 2 (x T * ) (N)</formula><p>4.3. Algorithm for optimal solution of problem (3)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)</p><p>Because of the information provided in the previous section, here is a well-performing solution for addressing Problems (3)-( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) in this paragraph. As a means of addressing issues (3) to begin with, there was an Initial Algorithm developed (4).</p><p>Step-1: Utilize Theorem 1 to determine the consistency of system (1). If Aox T ≥ b is true, where x = (1 * , 1 * , 1 * , . . . , 1). Otherwise, system (1) will fail to solve the problem and will terminate.</p><p>Step-2: compute the system (1)'s discrimination matrix D = (d ij ) m×n .</p><p>Step-3: ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, the computer r i by( <ref type="formula">7</ref>), i.e. r i = min 1≤j≤n {d ij |d ij ̸ = 0}.</p><p>Step-4. Divide Problem (3) by ( <ref type="formula">14</ref>) to obtain the ideal value r max-min i.e. Step-5: Determine the system (1)'s minimal maximum-norm discrimination matrix T = (t ij ) m×n .</p><p>Step-6. ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, calculate the index set j 1 using the formula (B), i.e. J i = {j|t ij ̸ = 0, 1 ≤ j ≤ n}.</p><p>Step-7. Integer Programming Issue 0-1 Using (C), i.e. min</p><formula xml:id="formula_39">∑ n 1≤i≤m f ij s.t n ∑ j=1 f ij = 1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, f ij = 0 or 1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, 1 ≤ j ≤ m, f ij = 0, ∀i, j with j / ∈ J i . Solve Problem (C) using branch-and-bound, f ij or1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, 1 ≤ j ≤ m,</formula><p>Step 9. Construct the matrix T = (t ij ) m×n with respect to f ij , where t ij is defined by (I). Assume that T equals</p><p>The vector X T</p><formula xml:id="formula_40">= (∥T T 1 ∥ ∞ , ∥T T 2 ∥ ∞ , ∥T T 3 ∥ ∞ , ∥T T 4 ∥ ∞ , . . . ∥T T n ∥ ∞ ),</formula><p>thus, is the best solution to Problem (3)-(4).</p><p>• Complexity of computation in which n is variable number; m is the inequality numbers.</p><formula xml:id="formula_41">|J i |: index set j i , 1 ≤ i ≤ m; k = ∏ m i=1 |J i | index set J 1 × J 2 × J 3 , . . . × J m .</formula><p>Algorithm 1's initial step requires mn operations in order to check for consistency in system (1). The matrix D is computed in step 2 in 2mn operations. Step 3 incurs a cost of 2m(n -1). Calculating the best value r max-min in Step 4 requires m -1 operations due to the previously acquired r i |1 ≤ i ≤ m. Both Steps 5 and 6 are cost-effective in terms of operations. Steps 7 and 8 require (k -1)(m -1)(n -1)n branch and bind operations to get the best solution. The 9 th and 10th steps each cost mn and (m -1)n operations. As a result, each step in Algorithm 1 requires</p><formula xml:id="formula_42">mn + 2mn + 2m(n -1) + (m -1) + mn + mn + (k -1)(m -1)(n - 1)n + mn + (m -1)n = (k -1)(m -1)(n -1)n + 9mn -m -n -1 operations.</formula><p>O is the complexity of computation (kmn 2 ).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.">Generalize the second-level problem's objective function</head><p>To slow the rise of cellular computing, we require a bi-level programming problem that confronts max-product fuzzy similarity inequality. Indeed, we can use different objective functions z 2 (x) to explain additional management requirements. The various levels in a linear program could include one of two approaches: In other words, the second level's optimization problem (also known as the objective function z 1 (x) may be thought of as a monotone increasing function. Thus, (also known as the objective function) satisfies if z 2 (x) z 2 (y). By offering the above general Bilevel Programming Challenges, we are sufficient to facilitate a wider range of management requirements.</p><formula xml:id="formula_43">(I) ↦ → min z 1 (x) = ∥x∥ ∞ s.t A • x ≥ b (II) ↦ → min z 1 (x)s.t x ∈ X i (A, b), where X i (A, b)</formula><p>Proof. Let us assume that z 2 (x) is an increasing monotone functionality. If system (1) is stable, a min maximum-norm function exists. T system (1) has a correlational design that is consistent with it X T is the best answer to I-II. Previous proofs states that for any S ∈ H, X S a good answer to Problem I i.e., ∥X S ∥ ∞ = min x∈X (A,b) ∥x∥ ∞ = r max-min , where H denotes minimal max-norm solution matrices (1). As a result, there exists a T ∈ H such that z 2 (x T ) = min s∈H z 2 (x s ). To conclude the proof, we must verify that ∀, z 2 (x T ) ≤ z 2 (x). Assume x ∈ X 1 (A, b). According to Lemma 1, there exists a solution matrix S = (S ij ) m×n according to Lemma 1. Take note of the fact that X-INFY As a result, ∥X s ∥ ∞ = ∥x∥ ∞ . That is max 1≤i≤m min 1≤i≤n S ij = r max-min , which means that S is a matrix with a minimum max-norm solution, i.e. S ∈ H. Additionally, because z 2 (x) is a monotone rising function, z 2 (x S ) ≤ z 2 (x).</p><p>As a result, z 2 (x T ) = min s∈H z 2 (x s ) ≤ z 2 (x S ) ≤ z 2 (x).</p><p>So, X T is the best solution to Problems I-II. Algorithm number two is a two-step process. Algorithm 1's steps 1 through 6 and 8 through 10 are identical, step-7.</p><formula xml:id="formula_44">min z 2 ( max 1≤i≤m d i1 f i1 , max 1≤i≤m d i2 f i2 , max 1≤i≤m d i3 f i3 , max 1≤i≤m d i4 f i4 . . . max 1≤i≤m d in f in ) s.t n ∑ j=1 f ij = 1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, f ij = 0 or 1, ∀1 ≤ i ≤ m, 1 ≤ j ≤ n, f ij = 0, ∀i, j with j / ∈ J i .</formula><p>is used to define the 0-1 integer programmer.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.">Comparison to previous works</head><p>There appears to be only one layer of optimization that deals with fuzzy relational systems, as far as we know. Another way of thinking about this is for instance by looking at a study done by A.A. Molar et al. where they assessed the fuzzy relation optimization problem using four different features: linear, quadratic, geometric, and minimum-maximum. Lee and Guu, together with Fang et al. studied fuzzy relational simplex method, which utilizes max-min composing, as well as all the related research by and about these individuals. Using branch-and-bound strategy, they addressed their stated challenge. The results were tested using addition-min fuzzy relations. Solve the problem with a single variable and an ideal answer. Each of the problems below has a single-level optimization challenge. However, it adds a segment goal function. min z 2 (x) = ∥x∥ 0 .</p><p>where ∥x∥ 0 denotes the vector x zero-norm, To our knowledge, the connection has still not been put into the fuzzy set. The zeronorm optimal solution is suitable, and our suggested resolution algorithm has shown that it is realizable in application settings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.">Conclusion</head><p>To better comprehend management ideas for wireless transmission station systems. Finding a monotonic rising function that suggests superior management is actually level two optimization. In the first level of lattice-preserving linear equations, optimal solutions are difficult to discover. The limited systems domain is valid, but not the domain of first-level lattice linear programming. We solve second-order programming problems using mini-norm and max-norm matrices. These solutions are included in the minimal matrix paradigm. To solve our 0-1 issue, we used the standard branch-and-bound strategy. Our bi-level positions also provide extensive replies. The traditional Max-T mixture is the well-known Max-product. The classical composition is updated using a fuzzy relation approach. In future investigations, we are particularly interested in bi-level optimization and compositions like min-product, respects, and bipolar Max-T.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Network of wireless communication stations.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,63.54,55.32,199.20,170.56" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>(</head><label></label><figDesc>A, b) and x1 * = (r max-min , r max-min , r max-min , . . . , r max-min ) providing the best possible solution to the problem. It provides proof that the best possible solution for Problem (3) is x1 * itself (3). We show that to begin with, we have ∪ x∈Xmmns(A,b) [x, x1 * ] ⊆ X 1 (A, b). Its y ∈ ∪ x∈Xmmns(A,b) [x, x1 * ] So, use it. a minimum max-norm matrix X T ≤ y ≤ x1 * We know that y is a solution to Problem (1) because X T ≤ y (3). For Theorem 4 (Which value of Problem (3)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>=</head><label></label><figDesc>X mmns (A, b) Furthermore, Inequalities in the above equations denote y ∈ [x, x1 * ]. As a result, we have y ∈ ∪ x∈Xmmns(A,b) [x, x1 * ] As demonstrated in Theorem 4, when |X mmns (A, b)| &gt; 1 a</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>|d ij ̸ = 0}</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Declaration of competing interest</head><p>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of fuzzy systems software: Taxonomy, current research trends, and prospects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Alcalá-Fdez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Alonso</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Fuzzy Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="56" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Simulation: Methodology and application in agricultural economics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Rev. Mark. Agric. Econ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="1974">1974</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exact penalty decomposition method for zeronorm minimization based on MPEC formulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIAM J. Sci. Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1451" to="A1477" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resource optimization of spatial TDMA in ad hoc radio networks: A column generation approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bjorklund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Varbrand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE INFOCOM 2003. Twenty-Second Annual Joint Conference of the IEEE Computer and Communications Societies</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="818" to="824" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interaction of electromagnetic waves with plasma in the radiation-dominated regime</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Bulanov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Esirkepov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Koga</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Tajima</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Plasma Phys. Rep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="196" to="213" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fuzzy Logic and Mathematics: A Historical Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bělohlávek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Dauben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Klir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solving fuzzy relation equations with a linear objective function</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fuzzy Sets and Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Multiple objective optimization for systems with addition-min fuzzy relational inequalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fuzzy Optim. Decis. Mak</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="529" to="544" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A two-phase approach to finding a better managerial solution for systems with addition-min fuzzy relational inequalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Fuzzy Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2251" to="2260" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dichotomy algorithm for solving weighted min-max programming problem with addition-min fuzzy relation inequalities constraint</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Ind. Eng</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">146</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">106537</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An efficient solution procedure for fuzzy relation equations with max-product composition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Loetamonphong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Fuzzy Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="441" to="445" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Novel approximate solving algorithm for fuzzy relational equations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Luoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Liaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Math. Comput. Modelling</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="308" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the relation between equations with max-product composition and the covering problem</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Markovskii</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fuzzy Sets and Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="261" to="273" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A hybrid fuzzy zoning approach for 3-dimensional exploration geotechnical modeling: A case study at Semilan dam, southern Iran</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Morshedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Torabi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Memarian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">78</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="691" to="708" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On generalized fuzzy relational equations and their applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Pedrycz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Math. Anal. Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="520" to="536" />
			<date type="published" when="1985">1985</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fuzzy relation bilevel optimization model in the wireless communication station system</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Qiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Xue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2984095</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2984095" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Access</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60811" to="60823" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bloom dynamics of cyanobacteria and their toxins: Environmental health impacts and mitigation strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Rastogi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Madamwar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Incharoensakdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Microbiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1254">2015. 1254</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Minimal zero norm solutions of linear complementarity problems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Xiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Optim. Theory Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">163</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="795" to="814" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Solutions of fuzzy relation equations based on continuous t-norms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Shieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">177</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4208" to="4215" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deriving minimal solutions for fuzzy relation equations with max-product composition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Shieh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">178</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3766" to="3774" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision making in agriculture: A linear programming approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Sofi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bhat</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Mod. Math. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resolution of composite fuzzy relation equations based on Archimedean triangular norms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Stamou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Tzafestas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fuzzy Sets and Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">120</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="395" to="407" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding the complete set of minimal solutions for fuzzy relational equations with max-product composition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Guu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Oper. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Min-max programming problem subject to addition-min fuzzy relation inequalities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Fuzzy Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="119" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latticized linear programming subject to max-product fuzzy relation inequalities with application in wireless communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inform. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">358</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="55" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
