<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Taiji</forename><surname>Imoto</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Agricultural Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Agriculture</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yamaguchi University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Yamaguchi</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kazuyoshi</forename><surname>Yagishita</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Agricultural Chemistry</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Faculty of Agriculture</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yamaguchi University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Yamaguchi</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">5F67FE4A5C1B19EDD49C23BFB2BB4CD0</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00021369.1971.10860050</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received April 24, 1971</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.2" ident="GROBID" when="2025-07-02T08:53+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<label type="revision">a91ee48</label>
					<label type="parameters">startPage=-1, endPage=-1, consolidateCitations=0, consolidateHeader=0, consolidateFunders=0, includeRawAffiliations=false, includeRawCitations=false, includeRawCopyrights=false, generateTeiIds=false, generateTeiCoordinates=[], sentenceSegmentation=false, flavor=null</label>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Short Communication</head><p>[Agr. <ref type="bibr">BioI. Chern., Vol. 35, No.7, p. 1154~1156, 1971]</ref> A Simple Activity Measurement of Lysozyme The mixture of 2 ml of the color reagent and 1.5 ml of NAG solution was incubated in boiling water for 15 min and the decrease in O.D. 420 was plotted against NAG concentration. sodium carbonate. The color was also not affected when the mixture was allowed to stand for a few hours before or after boiling or when the boiling period was varied from 10 to 30 min as long as NAG and (NAGl: were used. Thus a stable and reproducible color is developed. A blank value of 0.850 (O.D. 420 ) was obtained within ± 1% deviation. 0.20 0.15 0.10 NAG (mg) 0.05 o 01-0 0.8 0.2 0.6 * Abbreviations used are: NAG; N-acetylglucosamine, NBS; N-bromosuccinimide. 1) N. Yamasaki, K. Hayashi and M. Funatsu, Agr. Bioi. Chern., <ref type="bibr">32, 64 (1968)</ref>.</p><p>2) K. Hamaguchi and M. Funatsu, J. Biochern., <ref type="bibr">46, 1659 (1959)</ref>.</p><p>3) A. Marzottl and L. Galzigna, Hoppe-Seyler's Z. Phys. Chern., <ref type="bibr">350, 427 (1969)</ref>. 4) K. Hayashi, N. Yamasaki and M. Funatsu, Agr. Bioi. Chern., <ref type="bibr">28, 517 (1964)</ref>. 5) M. Imanishi, N. Miyagawa and T. Amano, Biken J., <ref type="bibr">12, 25 (1965)</ref>.</p><p>6) O. Schales and S. S. <ref type="bibr">Schales, Arch. Biochern., 8, 285 (1945)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sir:</head><p>Bacterial cell wall lysis has been widely employed as a measure of the activity of lysozyme. Because of the complicated nature of this assay, it does not always reflect the true enzymic reaction. l l Methods which use oligo or poly N-acetylglucosamine (NAG*) derivatives as the substrate have been developed recently. These assays were monitored by</p><p>• • 2 31 d ' I 4 61</p><p>VIscosImetry' or re ucmg group ana yses. . This report describes a simple and reproducible reducing group analysis method by a modification of Schales' procedure. 61  The color reagent solution was made by dissolving 0.5 g potassium fericyanide in I litter of 0.5 M sodium carbonate and stored in a brown bottle. Two m1 of the reagent were mixed with 1.5 ml of sample solution and incubated in boiling water for 15 min in a !: Cl test tube stoppered with aluminum foil. After'" 0.4 cooling, the optical density at 420 nm was read versus water. The concentration of sodium carbonate was sufficiently high so as not to be affected by the buffer action of the sample solution. The color development was not affected by the high concentration of NBS oxidation was performed in 0.1 M acetate buffer, pH 4.5. The activity was measured under the same conditions as in Fig. <ref type="figure">2</ref> using 10 pg enzyme (0). The activity measured with viscosimetry was noted for comparison (6).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>""</head><p>.~50 &gt; 0.05% glycol chitin solution, 0.5 ml of lysozyme solution was added and incubated for 30 min at 40°C. Both solutions were buffered in 0.1 M acetate at pH 4.5 and preincubated at 40°C. After the reaction, 2 ml of color reagent were added and the mixture was immediately boiled for 15 min (a slight lysozyme reaction was detected even after addition of the color reagent). The glycol chitin solution itself did not cause any decrease in color. This means that glycol chitin used had a high degree of polymerization with a low content of reducing groups, and that nonspecific hydrolysis of glycol chitin did not take place under the assay conditions.</p><p>A standard curve for lysozyme concentration is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">2</ref>. A correction was applied for decolorization caused by lysozyme itself at each enzyme concentration. Decrease in O.D.m(JD m ) was 3.0jmg lysozyme. If lysozyme concentration is 10 pg, the correction is 0.030 (JD m ).</p><p>As a test experiment, the activities of NBS-</p><p>10 Lysozyme added (p.g) 5 o 0.1 0.2 7) J. T. Park and M. J. Johnson, J. Biol. Chern., 181, 149 (1949).</p><p>8) M. Somogyi, J. <ref type="bibr">Biol. Chern., 195, 19 (1952)</ref>. 9) R. Senzyu and S. Okimasu, Nippon Nogeikagaku Kaishi, 23, 432 (1950).</p><p>reproducible. The decrease in total color value (JD m X ml) was constant (18.0±0.5jmg NAG) for a given NAG amount in several fericyanide concentrations at least upto half the concentration employed here. The curve shows that 0~0.15 mg of NAG can be detected under these conditions (caution must be taken with other oligomers which have different color values). This method has adequate sensitivity for the detection of reducing groups produced by lysozyme action. Park-johnson's method 71 is too sensitive (affected by most cations present) and Somogyi's method SI is not sensitive enough.</p><p>For the measurement of lysozyme, glycol chitin 91 was used as a substrate. To 1 ml of FIG. <ref type="figure">2</ref>. Standard Curve for the Lysozyme Activity in 0.1 M Acetate Buffer, pH 4.5.</p><p>To 1 ml of 0.05% glycol chitin solution, 0.5 ml of lysozyme solution was added and incubated for 30 min at 40°C, and the reducing group produced was assayed as in Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>A</head><figDesc>FIG. 1. Standard Curve for N-Acetylglucosamine.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><figDesc>FIG. 3. Activity of NBS-Oxidized Lysozyme.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>T. IMOTO and K. YAGISHITA oxidized lysozyme 10J were followed using the standard curve obtained above and is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure">3</ref>. The lysozyme concentration was kept at 10 p.g. Note the good agreement with activity determined using viscosimetry.</p><p>Thus a simple and very reproducible activity measurement for lysozyme has been developed. By following the initial rate of the reaction, 10) K. Hayashi, T. Imoto and M. Funatsu, ]. Biochem., <ref type="bibr">54, 381 (1963)</ref>. more accurate kinetic data for lysozyme may be obtained and this is currently under investigation.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl/>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
