<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Location of the ostia of the renal arteries in the aorta</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Radiologlc</forename><surname>Anatomy</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ozan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Anatomy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Alemdaroglu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Radiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Medical Faculty</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Gtilhane Military Medical Academy</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>06018</postCode>
									<settlement>Ankara</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sinav</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Anatomy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Gtimtisalan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Anatomy</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Location of the ostia of the renal arteries in the aorta</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">7397BBC837B9746D20CF880C1B95D7EF</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:41+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>A total of 30 adult abdominal aorta specimens dissected from cadavers was used in our study. The location of the ostium of the superior mesenteric a. relative to the ostium of the celiac trunk was identified on the aortic wall. Following this, the locations of the ostia of the renal aa. on the internal wall of the abdominal aorta were examined relative to the ostia of the arteries mentioned earlier. The ostium of the superior mesenteric a. was usually localized on the inferior-fight side of the ostium of the celiac trunk. The mean value of the distance between the ostia was 17.9 mm. The ostium of the right renal a. was more cranial than the ostium of the left renal a. (53.3%). However, the ostia of both right and left renal aa. were at the same level in three cases (10%). Locations of the ostia of the renal aa. were usually on the lateral and anterolateral regions of the aortic wall. This study was carried out in order to contribute to selective angiography and surgical interventions for the removal and transplantation of organs, particularly of the kidney. Our results are compared with previous similar studies in man.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Localisation des orifices des art~res r6nales dans l'aorte</head><p>REsumE : 30 aortes abdominales des cadavres d'adultes ont 6t6 dissrqures. La localisation de l'orifice de l'a. mrsentErique supErieure et sa situation par rapport ~ celui du tronc coeliaque a EtE identifiEe sur la paroi aortique. La localisation des orifices des artrres rEnales par rapport g ceux de ces deux attires a EtE dEterminEe. L'orifice de l'a. mEsentErique supErieure est gEnEralement locali-s6 distalement et ~t droite de celui du tronc coeliaque. La distance moyenne entre les deux orifices Etait 17,9 mm. L'orifice de l'a. rEnale droite se trouvait en position plus crfiniale que celui de l'a. rdnale gauche (53,3 %). Cependant, les orifices de deux artrres droite et gauche se trouvaient au mame niveau dans trois cas (10 %). Les orifices des aa. rEnales Etaient localisEs gEnrralement dans les faces latErale et antEro-latErale de l'aorte. Le but de cette Etude est d'apporter une contribution ~ l'angiographie selective et aux interventions chirurgicales destinEes au prEl~vement et ~ la transplantation du rein. Nos rEsultats ont EtE compares ~t ceux d'autres Etudes rEa-lisEes chez l'homme.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Key words: Renal artery --Angiography --Abdominal aorta --Morphometric analysis</head><p>Renal and intrarenal vascular anatomy has been investigated in many previous studies <ref type="bibr">[1, 4, 6, 9, 11-13, 15, 16]</ref>. However, studies on location of the ostia of the renal aa. on the aortic wall are scant in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr">10]</ref>. Renal angiography is frequently used in the context of diagnosis and treatments. Therefore, the morphologic features of the ostia of the renal aa. on the aortic wall should be familiar to radiologists, especially those dealing with selective renal angiography.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and methods</head><p>Adult abdominal aorta specimens, a total of 30 in number, were obtained from cadavers in the Departments of Anatomy at the Medical Faculties of Gtilhane Military Medical Academy, Hacettepe University and 19 Mayis University.</p><p>The abdominal aorta of each cadaver was sectioned above the celiac trunk cranially and above the aortic bifurcation caudally, and resected from its branches. The lumen of each specimen was washed under tap water. The anterior wall of the aorta was fixed on a flat surface and the posterior wall was cut midsagittally. The cut margins were reflected laterally and also fixed on the flat surface. The ostia of aa. located on the aortic wall were visualised (Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>). Photographs of each specimen were taken together with a 5 cm ruler, and the following distances were measured: Ostia of the aa. localized on the internal wall of the aorta, ct: celiac trunk, sin: superior mesenteric a., lr: left renal a., rr: right renal a., aa: abdominal aorta 1. the distance between the midpoint of the distal border of the celiac ostium and the midpoint of the distal border of the superior mesenteric ostium (VcM) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>), 2. the distances from the midpoint of the celiac trunk to the midpoints of the distal borders of the right (VcR R) and left (VcL R) renal ostia (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>), 3. the distances from the midpoint of the distal border of the superior mesenteric ostium to the midpoints of the distal border of the right (VMR R) and left (VMLR) renal ostia (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>).</p><p>A horizontal line was drawn at the level of the renal aa. Then, the abdominal aorta was divided into ten equal vertical regions by lines crossing this horizontal line vertically. The locations of the ostia of the renal aa. on the aortic wall, and their cranial or caudal position in relation to the ostium of the superior mesenteric a. were identified (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>).</p><p>A parametric two-sample analysis test was carried out to evaluate the differences between the distances of the right and left renal ostia from the superior mesenteric and celiac ostia.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>The ostium of the superior mesenteric a. was located in the inferior and right lateral region of the ostium of the celiac t r u n k in 22 out of 30 of the cases (73.3%). The mean distance between the two ostia was:</p><p>VCM o = 18 mm The mean distances between the ostia of the renal aa. and the ostia of the superior mesenteric a. and the celiac trunk were collected in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>As shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>, the ostium of the right r e n a l a. was c l o s e r to the ostium of the superior mesenteric a. than the left. Thus, the ostium of the right renal a. had a cranial location in 53.3% of cases. However, the ostium of the left renal a. was located cranially in 36.6% of the cases. In the remaining 10%, both renal aa. were at the same level.</p><p>In order to evaluate the distances of the right and left renal ostia from the superior mesenteric and celiac ostia, a p a r a m e t r i c t w o -s a m p l e analysis test was done. There was no statistically significant difference between Vel r and Vcr r (p &gt; 0,05), however the difference between Vmlr and Vmr r was found to be significant (p &lt; 0,05).</p><p>The range of distribution of the locations of the renal aa. on the internal aortic wall is shown in Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>. Twentynine ostia (48.3%) were located in the lateral, 19 (31.6%) in the anterolateral and 10 in the anterolateral-lateral border zone, one in the posterolateral and one in the posterolateral-posterior border zone.</p><p>According to our findings, the locations of the arteries on the aortic wall were as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>Different studies dealing with the sites of origin of the renal aa. from the abdominal aorta were reviewed in the literature. However, the results of these studies depended only upon external observations and not on identification of the ostia of the renal aa. from within the aorta. A wide range of findings such as anterolateral, lateral and anterior locations were reported in this study <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>mm mesenteric</head><p>The distance between the celiac and the superior mesenteric ostia (VCMo) was found as 18 mm Publications in the angiographic literature consider the usual position of the renal ostia to be lateral <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> or dorsal <ref type="bibr">[10]</ref> on the aortic wall. There are two similar studies dealing with the locations of the renal ostia on the internal wall of the ~-~ 0 0</p><p>Fig. <ref type="figure">3</ref> The range of distribution of the k-Pk Pk PL-P P zone zone locations of renal Regions aa. on the aortic wall abdominal aorta <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr">10]</ref>. We defined certain such locations by using more significant anatomic landmarks. Moreover, we did not take into account the ostia of multiple renal aa. in order not to affect the data. As stated by many authors, the incidence of multiple renal aa. range from 13 to 60% and the mean value is reported as 30% <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14]</ref>. We also observed in our series that one specimen had bilateral and four specimens had unilateral multiple renal aa. (16%).</p><p>Bauer and Robbins reported that the ostia of the renal aa. were localized on the lateral and anterolateral walls of the aorta in 79 and 15.4% of cases, respectively <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. However, Odman and Ranniger found the incidence of a lateral location of the renal aa. to be 55.7% <ref type="bibr">[10]</ref>. Our findings were more compatible with the findings of Odman and Ranniger, since the incidence of lateral and anterolateral locations were 48.3% and 31.6%, respectively. According to Odman and Ranniger, the ostium of the right renal a. was located more on the anterior wall and that of the left renal a. on the lateral wall of the abdominal aorta. These authors also reported that renal aa. originating from the anterior wall had a more cranial position near the ostium of the superior mesenteric a. [ 10].</p><p>We found that renal ostia on the lateral wall of the abdominal aorta had a cranial, but ostia on the anterolateral wall a caudal position. This result accounted for the more cranial position of the right renal ostium in relation to the left renal ostium. Extreme (anterior or posterior wall) locations of renal ostia on the aortic wall have been reported to be related to developmental variations of the mesonephric aa. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>.</p><p>Although the distance between the ostia of the superior mesenteric a. and the celiac trunk differed in many cases, locations of the renal ostia did not exhibit significant differences. We believe that, for the success of catheterization in selective angiographic procedures, the following anatomical guidelines should be kept in mind:</p><p>• The ostium of the right renal a. is usually located on the lateral wall of the abdominal aorta and has a more cranial position than the left. It is nearer to the superior mesenteric ostium and approximately 14 mm distal to it.</p><p>• The location of the ostium of the left renal a. is similar to that of the fight; however its distance from the superior mesenteric ostium is approximately 17.5 mm distal to it.</p><p>• The ostium of the superior mesenteric a. is usually located on the right and approximately 18 mm distal to the ostium of the celiac trunk.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 1Ostia of the aa. localized on the internal wall of the aorta, ct: celiac trunk, sin: superior mesenteric a., lr: left renal a., rr: right renal a., aa: abdominal aorta</figDesc><graphic coords="2,34.29,58.09,165.12,251.52" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2Anatomical configuration of the ostia of the aa. on the aortic wall and the measured distances between them. aa: abdominal aorta, ct: celiac trunk, lr: left renal a., rr: right renal a., sin: superior mesenteric a.,Vcm: the distance between the ostia of the celiac trunk and the superior mesenteric a., Vclr: the distance between the ostia of the celiac trunk and the left renal a., Vcrr: the distance between the ostia of the celiac trunk and the right renal a., Vmlr: the distance between the ostia of the superior mesenteric and the left renal a., Vmrr: the distance between the ostia of the superior mesenterie and the right renal a.The regions on the internal wall of the aorta P: posterior, PL: posterolateral, L: lateral, AL: anterolateral, A: anterior</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Mean values of the distances for the left and right renal aa. measured from the critical points</figDesc><table><row><cell>Ostia</cell><cell>Left renal a.</cell><cell>Right renal a.</cell></row><row><cell>Celiac</cell><cell>VCLRo</cell><cell>VCRRo</cell></row><row><cell>ostium</cell><cell>33.2 mm</cell><cell>30.0 mm</cell></row><row><cell>Superior</cell><cell>VMLRo</cell><cell>VMp, ao</cell></row><row><cell>ostium</cell><cell>17.4 ram</cell><cell>13.9</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>ReceivedNovember 5, 1996  / Accepted in final formJuly 22, 1997   </p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>Acknowledgement. We are very gratefull to <rs type="person">Necati Oguz</rs>, Head of the English Department of our academy, for the language editing of this text.</p></div>
			</div>			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Common variations in renal anatomy, affecting blood supply, form and topography</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Anson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Daseler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surg Gynecol Obstet</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">112</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="449" />
			<date type="published" when="1961">1961</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The aortic origin of renal arteries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch Pathol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="230" to="233" />
			<date type="published" when="1968">1968</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A postmortem study comparing renal angiograms and renal a. casts in 58 patients</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Robbins</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch Pathol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">83</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="307" to="314" />
			<date type="published" when="1967">1967</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Angiographic studies of the anatomy of single and multiple renal arteries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Boijsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Radiol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">183</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="1959">1959</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The origin of the renal a. in mammals and its anomalies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bremer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am J Anat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="200" />
			<date type="published" when="1915">1915</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visceral branches of abdominal aorta: topographical relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cauldwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anson</forename><surname>Bj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am J Anat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">73</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="1943">1943</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The development of the re&apos;ogenital organs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Felix</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Manual of human embryology</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Philadelphia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1912">1912</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="752" to="979" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Normal renal angiogram. ln: Renal angiography</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Kincaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical Publishers</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">18</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1966">1966</date>
			<pubPlace>Chicago</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variant renal and suprarenal blood supply with data on inferior phrenic, ureteral and gonadal arteries: statistical analysis based on 185 dissections and review of literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Merklin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Michels</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Int Coll Surg</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1958">1958</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The location of the renal arteries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ranniger</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am J Roentgenol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="1968">1968</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Renal vascular pedicle: anatomical study of 430 body-halves</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Pick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anson</forename><surname>Bj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Urol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="411" to="434" />
			<date type="published" when="1940">1940</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Variations in the renal vascular pedicle</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Samuel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Br J Urol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">478</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961">1961</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anatomical relationship between the intrarenal arteries and the kidney collecting system</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fjb</forename><surname>Sampaio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ahm</forename><surname>Aragao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Urol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">143</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="679" to="681" />
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Renal arteries: anatomic study for surgical and radiological practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fjb</forename><surname>Sampalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marf</forename><surname>Passos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surg Radiol Anat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="117" />
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The renal vascular patterns in man</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Urol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">80</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="1963">1963</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Renal vessels in 203 cadavers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Coutyss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Derbes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Urol Cutan Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="1940">1940</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
