<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Eosinophils secrete IL-4 to facilitate liver regeneration</title>
				<funder ref="#_2afxsdn">
					<orgName type="full">Wellcome Trust</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_hP9Ez5s">
					<orgName type="full">unknown</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_CYVUwyw">
					<orgName type="full">National Institutes of Health Director&apos;s Pioneer</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_Z5k3CPB">
					<orgName type="full">Agency for Science, Technology and Research National Science Scholarship</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2013-03-04">March 4, 2013</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sharon</forename><surname>Goh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Immunology Program and Departments of e Genetics and f Pathology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiovascular Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Neil</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Lung Biology Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California San Francisco</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94143</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Medical Research Council Centre for Inflammation Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Queen&apos;s Medical Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>EH16 4TJ</postCode>
									<settlement>Edinburgh</settlement>
									<country>United Kingdom;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jose</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Heredia</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiovascular Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><forename type="middle">Red</forename><surname>Eagle</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Odegaard</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Nadja</forename><surname>Lehwald</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of General, Visceral and Pediatric Surgery</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Medicine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Heinrich Heine University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>40225</postCode>
									<settlement>Duesseldorf</settlement>
									<country>Germany;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Khoa</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Immunology Program and Departments of e Genetics and f Pathology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<settlement>Stanford</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiovascular Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Lata</forename><surname>Mukundan</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiovascular Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Medical Research Council Centre for Inflammation Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Queen&apos;s Medical Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Edinburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>EH16 4TJ</postCode>
									<settlement>Edinburgh</settlement>
									<country>United Kingdom;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Locksley</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiovascular Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Departments of i Medicine and j Microbiology and Immunology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of California San Francisco</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94158</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Ajay</forename><surname>Chawla</surname></persName>
							<email>ajay.chawla@ucsf.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Cardiovascular Research Institute</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Departments of Physiology and Medicine</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California San Francisco</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94158</postCode>
									<settlement>San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">† by David J. Mangelsdorf</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Dallas</settlement>
									<region>TX</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Eosinophils secrete IL-4 to facilitate liver regeneration</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2013-03-04">March 4, 2013</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">D3EB6EB1B3FDCB6141C6F8EC9F1D3F90</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1073/pnas.1304046110</idno>
					<note type="submission">and approved April 29, 2013 (received for review</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-11T09:41+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Data deposition: The data reported in this paper have been deposited in the Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO) database, www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/geo (accession no. GSE45002).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The liver is a central organ for the synthesis and storage of nutrients, production of serum proteins and hormones, and breakdown of toxins and metabolites. Because the liver is susceptible to toxin-or pathogen-mediated injury, it maintains a remarkable capacity to regenerate by compensatory growth. Specifically, in response to injury, quiescent hepatocytes enter the cell cycle and undergo DNA replication to promote liver regrowth. Despite the elucidation of a number of regenerative factors, the mechanisms by which liver injury triggers hepatocyte proliferation are incompletely understood. We demonstrate here that eosinophils stimulate liver regeneration after partial hepatectomy and toxin-mediated injury. Liver injury results in rapid recruitment of eosinophils, which secrete IL-4 to promote the proliferation of quiescent hepatocytes. Surprisingly, signaling via the IL-4Rα in macrophages, which have been implicated in tissue repair, is dispensable for hepatocyte proliferation and liver regrowth after injury. Instead, IL-4 exerts its proliferative actions via IL-4Rα in hepatocytes. Our findings thus provide a unique mechanism by which eosinophil-derived IL-4 stimulates hepatocyte proliferation in regenerating liver. L iver is a highly regenerative organ in mammals. As such, in- jury to liver results in stimulation of quiescent hepatocytes to reenter the cell cycle, resulting in restoration of liver function <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2)</ref>. Since the advent of partial hepatectomy in 1931 <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3)</ref>, a number of signaling pathways have been identified in rodents that stimulate hepatocyte proliferation. For instance, Kupffer cell-derived cytokines such as IL-6 and TNF-α, stellate cell-derived hepatocyte growth factor (HGF), and platelet-derived serotonin have been implicated in the activation and promotion of hepatocyte proliferation after injury <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4)</ref>. Consistent with this, mice lacking IL-6, serotonin, or Met (the receptor for HGF in hepatocytes) exhibit impairment in liver regeneration after partial hepatectomy. In a similar manner, partial hepatectomy increases circulating levels of bile acids, which stimulate hepatocyte proliferation via activation of the nuclear receptor farnesoid X receptor <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(5)</ref>.</p><p>In all vertebrate species, tissue injury results in activation of the innate immune system, suggesting its participation in the repair of tissues <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref>. Recent studies suggest that injury to epithelial surfaces, such as skin, lung, and colon, results in rapid activation of a type 2 immunity, which promotes the repair of damaged barrier surfaces by inducing the wound-healing program <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8)</ref>. In each of these paradigms of tissue damage and repair, a central role has been ascribed to macrophages, which, in response to the locally produced type 2 cytokines IL-4 and IL-13, undergo alternative activation. However, it remains unknown whether the regenerative actions of type 2 immunity and alternatively activated macrophages are limited to replacement of barrier surfaces or whether they can also participate in regeneration of organs, such as the liver.</p><p>Another type 2 innate immune cell that has been implicated in tissue damage and repair is the eosinophil. Traditionally, tissue eosinophilia has been associated with pathogenesis of type 2 inflammatory pathologies, such as those associated with parasitic infections, allergies, and gastrointestinal disorders <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10)</ref>. In these settings, activation of eosinophils results in the secretion of cytotoxic granule cationic proteins, such as major basic protein, eosinophil cationic protein, and eosinophil peroxidase, which in aggregate promote tissue damage and dysfunction. However, recent studies have highlighted a potential role for eosinophils in tissue homeostasis and repair <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11)</ref>. For instance, in the model of surgical incision and closure, eosinophil number and alternative macrophage activation increased transiently after injury, suggesting that both cell types might be involved in the tissue repair response <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(12)</ref>. Furthermore, in the context of liver regeneration, nodular regenerative hyperplasia of the liver has been observed in patients with idiopathic hypereosinophilic syndrome <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(13)</ref>. Despite these advances, the functions of eosinophils and type 2 cytokine signaling have not been systematically investigated in the experimental paradigms of liver regeneration.</p><p>In this article, we present evidence that type 2 immune responses involving eosinophils and IL-4/IL-13 stimulate liver regeneration after partial hepatectomy and toxin-induced injury. Interestingly, signaling via the IL-4Rα in myeloid cells is not required for mediating the regenerative actions of type 2 cytokines in injured liver. Rather, type 2 cytokines stimulate liver regeneration, in part, via activation of the IL-4Rα on hepatocytes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>Eosinophils Are Recruited to the Liver After Hepatic Injury. To identify potential immune cells that participate in liver regeneration, we examined the immune cell repertoire of regenerating livers. Injury induced by partial hepatectomy or carbon tetrachloride (CCl 4 ) led to a dramatic increase in the recruitment of innate immune cells, including eosinophils, neutrophils, macrophages, and dendritic cells (Figs. S1 A and B, and S2), which coincided with the onset of hepatocyte proliferation. In contrast, the content of adaptive immune cells did not change significantly in these models of liver injury (Figs. S1 C and D and S2). Because tissue eosinophilia has been implicated in tissue damage/repair and liver growth <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(12)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(13)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">(14)</ref>, we quantified eosinophil numbers in the livers of uninjured and injured mice. In both models, eosinophil recruitment into injured livers was increased: A ∼2.4-fold increase was observed after partial hepatectomy, whereas injury by CCl 4 resulted in a ∼6.9-fold increase in the number of eosinophils recovered from the liver (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1 A</ref> and<ref type="figure">B</ref>). This increased migration of eosinophils into injured livers was accompanied by higher expression of eotaxin-1 (Ccl11) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S1 E</ref> and<ref type="figure">F</ref>) and could be blocked by antibodies directed against the α4 and αL integrins, which bind vascular cell adhesion molecule 1 and intercellular cell adhesion molecule 1 to promote the migration of eosinophils into tissues (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1</ref> A and B) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">15)</ref>. In aggregate, these results suggest that injury to liver is a potent stimulus for eosinophil recruitment, potentially implicating eosinophils in liver's regenerative response.</p><p>Eosinophils Regulate Liver Regeneration. To address this issue, we performed 70% hepatectomy in congenic wild-type (WT) and ΔdblGATA mice, with the latter lacking eosinophils because of a mutation in the promoter region of the Gata1 gene <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(16)</ref>. In response to partial hepatectomy <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">17)</ref>, hepatocyte proliferation increased rapidly in WT mice, as assessed by the incorporation of 5-bromo-2′-deoxyuridine (BrdU) at 36, 48, and 72 h after hepatectomy (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1 C</ref> and<ref type="figure">D</ref>). This proliferative response of hepatocytes was reduced by ∼44-52% in ΔdblGATA mice 36, 48, and 72 h after hepatectomy (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1 C</ref> and<ref type="figure">D</ref>). Notably, the peak time for BrdU labeling was similar in WT and ΔdblGATA mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1C</ref>), indicating that the observed decrease in BrdU incorporation does not result from a temporal shift in hepatocyte proliferation. Congruent with this observation, liver/body weight was ∼20% lower in ΔdblGATA mice 72 h after partial hepatectomy (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S3A</ref>).</p><p>To ascertain whether eosinophils were also required for liver regeneration after toxin-mediated injury, we treated WT and ΔdblGATA mice with a single dose of the liver toxin CCl 4 <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(18)</ref>. Although the extent of initial liver injury was similar in both strains of mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S3B</ref>), their regenerative responses were quite different. WT mice rapidly underwent hepatocyte proliferation and regenerated their damaged livers, whereas ΔdblGATA mice exhibited ∼50% reduction in hepatocyte proliferation (quantified by staining for the cellular proliferation marker K i 67), which was associated with persistence of necrotic debris (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1</ref> E and F and Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">S3C</ref>). Moreover, this impaired regenerative response of ΔdblGATA mice to partial hepatectomy or CCl 4 -mediated injury was associated with complete absence of liver eosinophils (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">S4</ref> A and B). These results highlight a previously unappreciated role for eosinophils in inducing hepatocyte proliferation after injury and implicate eosinophil-derived factors in the orchestration of liver regeneration.</p><p>Eosinophils Recruited to Injured Liver Secrete IL-4. Among the factors secreted by eosinophils, IL-4 has been implicated in both wound repair and liver regeneration <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(19)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">(20)</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">(21)</ref>. We thus evaluated the competence of eosinophils for IL-4 secretion in injured liver. After CCl 4 -induced liver injury, eosinophils, which can be distinguished by their expression of sialic acid-binding Ig receptor (Siglec-F) <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">(15)</ref>, were the predominant cell type competent for IL-4 secretion (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2A</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure">S5B</ref>) in IL-4 reporter mice (4get mice), a knock-in strain expressing the green fluorescent protein (GFP) from the IL-4 locus <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(22)</ref>. Similarly, partial hepatectomy in 4get mice demonstrated that ∼81-84% of GFP + cells were eosinophils (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2B</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure">S5A</ref>), with the remainder being mast cells and T helper type 2 (Th2) cells (Figs. S5 A and B and S6 A and B). In contrast to a recent report <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(23)</ref>, GFP+ cells did not express the pan-natural killer/natural killer T (NK/NKT) cell marker CD49b (Fig. <ref type="figure">S5 A</ref> and<ref type="figure">B</ref>). This difference likely stems from the increased sensitivity and specificity of 4get mice for detecting cells competent for IL-4 secretion. To further verify whether eosinophils were capable of secreting IL-4 in injured liver, we used knockin human CD2 (KN2) reporter mice in which cell surface expression of human CD2 (huCD2) faithfully reports the secretion of IL-4 protein <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(24)</ref>. Congruent with the GFP positivity of eosinophils in 4get mice, eosinophils infiltrating injured liver expressed huCD2 on the cell surface, indicative of recent IL-4 secretion (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2</ref> C and D). Furthermore, in both models of liver injury, cells competent for IL-4 secretion, as marked by GFP + staining, colocalized with Ki67 + hepatocytes (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2E</ref>), suggesting a potential role for IL-4 in promoting hepatocyte proliferation.</p><p>Activation of IL-4/IL-13 Signaling Facilitates Liver Regeneration. Because of the known functional redundancy between IL-4 and IL-13 <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">26)</ref>, we quantified the regenerative capacity of liver in IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice. After 70% hepatectomy, BrdU incorporation was reduced by ∼35-75% at 36, 48, and 72 h in IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2 F</ref> and<ref type="figure">G</ref>). Consistent with our findings that hepatocyte proliferation is impaired in IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice, the temporal profile of BrdU incorporation was similar in both genotypes (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2G</ref>), and liver/body weight was reduced by ∼30% in IL-4/ IL-13 -/-mice 72 h after partial hepatectomy (Fig. <ref type="figure">S7A</ref>). Furthermore, the regenerative response of IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice to CCl 4 -induced liver injury was blunted, as evidenced by a ∼45% reduction in the number of Ki67 + hepatocytes (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2 H</ref> and<ref type="figure">I</ref>) and a ∼35% increase in necrotic debris area (Fig. <ref type="figure">S7 B</ref> and<ref type="figure">C</ref>).</p><p>To gain an understanding of how IL-4/IL-13 regulate liver regeneration, we performed genome-wide transcriptional analysis with microarrays on livers of WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice treated with CCl 4 . Gene set enrichment analysis with Database for Annotation, Visualization and Integrated Discovery (DAVID) <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">(27)</ref> revealed that gene ontology (GO) terms associated with the cell cycle, nuclear division, and mitosis were overrepresented within the differentially expressed genes (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3A</ref> and Table <ref type="table">S1</ref>). This suggested that IL-4/IL-13 stimulate the reentry of quiescent hepatocytes into the cell cycle. In support of this, genes required for entry into and progression through the cell cycle, such as cyclin B1 (Ccnb1), cell division cycle 20 (Cdc20), early growth response protein-1 (Egr1), forkhead box protein M1 (Foxm1), were expressed at lower levels in livers of IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice after injury (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3</ref> B and C). Moreover, expression of genes encoded by alphafetoprotein (Afp), H19 and insulin-like growth factor 2 (Igf2), which are dynamically regulated in fetal (expressed), adult (repressed), and regenerating (expressed) liver, was also reduced in the livers of IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3C</ref>). These changes in gene expression were verified by quantitative RT-PCR analysis of liver mRNAs of WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3C</ref>). Importantly, expression of FoxM1 protein, a master regulator of hepatocyte proliferation and liver regeneration <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(28)</ref>, and its target gene cyclin b1 (Ccnb1) was markedly lower in mice lacking IL-4/IL-13 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3</ref> C and D). A similar decrease in expression of genes required for hepatocyte proliferation was observed in the ΔdblGATA mice, which lack eosinophils, after partial hepatectomy (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3E</ref>).</p><p>IL-4Rα Signaling in Hepatocytes, Not Myeloid Cells, Regulates Liver</p><p>Regeneration. Previous studies have implicated an IL-4-and IL-13driven program of alternative macrophage activation in tissue repair <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">(12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">29)</ref>, prompting us to examine the role of these cells in liver regeneration. For these studies, we used mice harboring deletion of IL-4Rα in myeloid cells [IL4Rα L/L LysM Cre (IL4Rα floxed allele crossed with Cre recombinase driven by Lysozyme 2 promoter); Fig. <ref type="figure">S8 A</ref> and<ref type="figure">B</ref>], which are impaired in alternative macrophage activation <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">(30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">31)</ref>. Surprisingly, genetic disruption of IL-4/IL-13 signaling in myeloid cells did not decrease the rate of BrdU incorporation in hepatocytes after partial hepatectomy (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4A</ref>). Consistent with these findings, the hepatic regenerative response was similar in control (IL4Rα L/L ) and IL4Rα L/L LysM Cre mice after CCl 4 -mediated injury (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4B</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure">S8C</ref>), implying that IL-4/IL-13 might act directly on hepatocytes to promote their proliferation.</p><p>To determine whether IL-4 can directly signal in hepatocytes, we examined the patency of the IL-4 signaling pathway in purified primary hepatocytes. WT murine hepatocytes expressed IL-4Rα, IL-13Rα1, and the common γc chain, which mediated the signaling response to IL-4 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4C</ref>) <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">(26)</ref>. On the basis of these findings, we tested whether deletion of IL-4Rα in hepatocytes, as in IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre (Fig. <ref type="figure">S8</ref> D and E) might impair liver's regenerative response to injury. Similar to IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2F</ref>), BrdU incorporation was reduced by ∼30% after partial hepatectomy in IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre (IL4Rα floxed allele crossed with Cre recombinase driven by Albumin promoter) (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4D</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure">S9A</ref>).</p><p>Congruent with this observation, hepatocyte proliferation, as quantified by K i 67 staining, was also decreased by ∼30% in IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre after injury with CCl 4 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4E</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure">S9B</ref>). Taken together, these results indicate that signaling via the hepatocyte IL4Rα mediates liver regeneration after injury.</p><p>IL-4 Stimulates Liver Growth. We next examined whether IL-4 signaling could enhance hepatocyte proliferation in the absence of injury. In primary hepatocytes, stimulation with IL-4 increased thymidine incorporation by ∼230% (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4F</ref>) and induced expression of genes associated with hepatocyte proliferation (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4G</ref>). Similarly, IL-4 administration to WT mice for 5 d enhanced hepatocyte proliferation, as demonstrated by a ∼10-fold increase in staining for the cellular proliferation marker K i 67 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4</ref> H and I). To probe the molecular mechanism by which IL-4 promotes hepatocyte proliferation, we analyzed the expression of genes that were down-regulated in livers of IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice. Treatment with IL-4 increased expression of FoxM1 mRNA and protein about fiveand between ∼1.5and twofold, respectively (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4</ref> J and K), and also induced markers of hepatocyte proliferation, such as the mRNAs encoded by Ccnb1, Cdc20, FoxM1, and H19 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4J</ref>). Thus, in the absence of injury, treatment with IL-4 is sufficient to drive quiescent hepatocytes into cell cycle and promote hepatocyte DNA replication both in vitro and in vivo.</p><p>A previous study has suggested an indirect mechanism by which IL-4 stimulates hepatocyte proliferation. Specifically, IL-4 was postulated to induce the expression of the potent hepatocyte mitogen IL-6 via deposition of complement <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(23)</ref>. To determine whether direct or indirect mechanisms contribute to IL-4-induced hepatocyte proliferation, we injected uninjured IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre mice with IL-4. As expected, treatment of IL4Rα L/L mice with IL-4 enhanced DNA synthesis in hepatocytes (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4L</ref>). Notably, IL-4 driven hepatocyte proliferation was decreased by ∼60% in IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4L</ref>), indicating that the proliferative actions of IL-4 are, in part, mediated via its direct effects on hepatocytes. The residual increase in hepatocyte proliferation might result from the ability of IL-4 to enhance IL-6 secretion from nonparenchymal cells, such as macrophages and stellate cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(23)</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we tested whether administration of IL-4 could protect WT mice from toxin (CCl 4 )-mediated liver injury (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4M</ref>). Although the initial extent of liver damage was similar in both groups of mice (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S10A</ref>), hepatocyte proliferation, as fied by nuclear staining for K i 67 (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S10B</ref>), was increased by ∼22% in IL-4-treated animals (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4N</ref>). Furthermore, this increase in hepatocyte proliferation was associated with a ∼43% decrease in necrotic cell area (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4O</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S10C</ref>), suggesting a potential therapeutic benefit of IL-4 in acute liver injury.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The regenerative capacity of the liver in part reflects its susceptibility to damage by ingested toxins and pathogenic infections. As such, multiple homeostatic mechanisms are activated on injury to initiate liver regeneration, each contributing only partially to the restoration of liver function <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2)</ref>. Here, we have demonstrated a role for eosinophils in orchestrating the regrowth of liver after injury. Moreover, our work has elucidated a direct mechanism by which eosinophil-derived IL-4 signals via the hepatocyte IL-4Rα to stimulate liver regeneration. In broad terms, these findings suggest that activation of type 2 immunity is integrally linked to reparative and regenerative programs in tissues, thereby exemplifying the host's protective strategy of tolerance against tissue damage <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">(8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32)</ref>. In support of this idea, we recently reported that eosinophil-derived IL-4 facilitates muscle regeneration <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(11)</ref>. Last, the ability of IL-4 to induce cell cycle progression in hepatocytes and protect against toxin-mediated injury has potential clinical implications for augmenting liver growth and regeneration in patients with liver disease.</p><p>Our studies differ in a number of important ways from a recent report that demonstrated a role for IL-4 in liver regeneration <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(23)</ref>. First, using homozygous KN2 mice that lack IL-4 (24), we failed to detect any differences in liver's regenerative response to injury. A substantial defect in liver regeneration was observed in IL-4/IL-13 knockout mice, which suggests that functional redundancy between IL-4 and IL-13 accounts for these discrepant results. Indeed, a large number of studies indicate that these two type 2 cytokines regulate an overlapping set of biological programs, including those in host defense, allergic inflammation, and metabolism <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">(25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">31)</ref>. Second, using the highly sensitive and specific 4get reporter mice, we failed to detect GFP expression in NKT cells, which previously had been identified NKT cells as the cellular source of IL-4, using intracellular staining. Because intracellular staining protocols require restimulation of cells ex vivo and the subsequent trapping of the produced cytokines in the Golgi complex, they tend to give false-positive results and do not faithfully report the endogenous production of cytokines in vivo <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(22)</ref>. In addition, rather than an indirect mechanism involving IL-4, complement, and IL-6, we provide genetic evidence for a direct mechanism in which activation of the IL-4Rα in hepatocytes stimulates hepatocyte proliferation.</p><p>Our current work also raises some interesting questions for future investigations. For instance, although treatment of uninjured mice with IL-4 is sufficient to drive hepatocyte proliferation, deletion of IL-4Rα in hepatocytes does not completely abrogate this response. This suggests that additional pathways are activated by IL-4 that can stimulate hepatocyte proliferation. Indeed, in various primary cell types and tissues, treatment with IL-4 can rapidly induce the expression of IL-6, a known activator of hepatocyte proliferation. Thus, in the future, it will be important to identify other IL-4Rα + cells in liver that participate in liver's regenerative response after injury.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and Methods</head><p>Animal Studies. Male mice aged 8-16 wk were used in the studies. Colonies of WT, ΔdblGATA, IL-4/IL-13 -/-, 4get, 4get ΔdblGATA, IL4Rα L/L , and IL4Rα L/L LysM Cre mice (all on the BALB/cJ background) and IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre mice on the C57BL/6J background were maintained in the Cardiovascular Research Institute's pathogen-free barrier facility according to institutional guidelines. Partial hepatectomy, which surgically removes 70% of the liver, was performed under Isoflurane anesthesia, as described previously <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">17)</ref>. Briefly, after a midline incision, the left lateral and median lobes were exposed, ligated, and completely excised, leaving behind the gall bladder and  For K i 67 staining, antigens were retrieved with Dako universal antigen retrieval solution (at pH 6.0), and tissue sections were subsequently stained with K i 67 antibody (1:50; Dako M7249). Secondary biotinylated anti-rat (1:200; Dako) coupled with Streptavidin-horseradish peroxidase (HRP) was used for detection of K i 67. Immunoblotting for proteins was performed by standard methods, using the following antibodies: IL4Rα (Santa Cruz E-1), IL2Rγ (Santa Cruz H-300), IL13Rα1 (Abcam Ab79277), phosphorylated pSTAT6 (BD Biosciences), STAT6 (Santa Cruz M20), FoxM1 (1:100; Santa Cruz K-19), β-actin (Sigma AC-40), and HSP90 (Santa Cruz H114).</p><p>Flow Cytometry. Liver was minced and digested with Dispase (2.4 U/mL; Invitrogen), dispersed, and subjected to RBC lysis. Cell suspension was then filtered through 100-μm and 40-μm cell strainers sequentially. For flow cytometric analysis, cells were stained with the following reagents and antibodies: Live/Dead stain and human CD2 (Invitrogen); Fc block, CD45, CD3, CD4, CD8, CD11b, F4/80, CD11c, CD49b, CD117, B220, and Ly6G (all from Biolegend); mouse IL4Rα and Siglec-F (BD Biosciences); and IL13R and FceRI (eBioscience).</p><p>Gene Expression Analyses. TRIzol reagent (Invitrogen) was used to extract total RNA from tissues, which was then treated with DNase (Invitrogen) to remove genomic DNA. Reverse transcription was performed on 1 μg of tissue RNA using the first strand cDNA synthesis kit (Origene). As described previously <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">(33)</ref>, quantitative real-time PCR analyses were carried out with cDNA templates using SsoFast EvaGreen Supermix (Biorad). All primer sequences are available on request. Relative expression of target mRNAs was calculated by the ΔΔCT method after normalization to the housekeeping gene 36B4.</p><p>For microarray studies, 25 μg total RNA was hybridized to Illumina Mous-eRef-8 v2.0 Expression BeadChip. After normalization, statistical analyses were performed with significance analysis of microarray (SAM), with a cutoff of &gt; twofold and P value &lt; 0.05. Functional annotation of differentially expressed genes was performed with DAVID. Complete linkage clustering of genes and arrays was performed using CLUSTER, and visualized with TREE-VIEW. The complete microarray data have been deposited with the Gene Expression Omnibus and can be accessed at GSE45002. Hepatocyte Culture. As described previously, hepatocytes were isolated by perfusion of liver with digestion buffer containing collagenase, followed by isodensity purification on a Percoll gradient <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">(34)</ref>. Primary hepatocytes were grown in Hepatozyme serum-free media (Invitrogen) at a density of ∼2 × 10 4 per cm 2 and stimulated with vehicle (Veh) or 10 ng/mL of IL-4 (Peprotech) for 36 h. Twenty-four hours before harvest, cells were pulsed with 2 μCi/mL 3 H-thymidine to monitor proliferation.</p><p>Statistical Analysis. All data are presented as mean ± SEM. Statistical significance was determined using the Student t test. A P value of &lt;0.05 was considered to be statistically significant and is presented as *P &lt; 0.05, **P &lt; 0.01, or ***P &lt; 0.001.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>type 2 immunity</head><label>2</label><figDesc>| tissue injury and repair | inflammation | parasites</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Impaired liver regeneration in mice lacking eosinophils. (A and B) Eosinophil numbers in livers of mice subjected to partial hepatectomy (PH) or toxin-induced injury (CCl 4 ) were enumerated using flow cytometry. Migration of eosinophils into injured livers is integrindependent and can be blocked by antibodies against α 4 and α L integrins (Ab). Isotype (Iso) immunoglobulins (IgG2a and IgG2b) were administered to control mice (n = 4-12 mice per group). (C) PH was performed in WT and ΔdblGATA mice, which lack eosinophils, and BrdU incorporation was examined at the indicated times to assess hepatocyte proliferation (n = 4-7 mice per genotype per time). (D) Remnant liver sections were stained for BrdU 36 h after partial hepatectomy. Representative images of WT and ΔdblGATA are shown. (E) Percentage of Ki67 + hepatocytes in WT and ΔdblGATA mice 2 d after administration of CCl 4 (n = 3-5 mice per genotype). (F) Quantification of necrotic area in WT and ΔdblGATA mice 2 d after administration of CCl 4 (n = 4-5 mice per genotype). *P &lt; 0.05, **P &lt; 0.01, ***P &lt; 0.001. All data are presented as mean ± SEM.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. IL-4/IL-13 promote liver regeneration. (A and B) Identification of eosinophils as the major cell population competent for IL-4 secretion after CCl 4mediated injury (A) and PH (B). Two days after administration of CCl 4 or PH in the IL-4 reporter mice (4get mice), the nonhepatocyte fraction was isolated and analyzed for expression of GFP and markers of eosinophils. Representative data from 3 independent experiments are shown in A and B. (C and D) Eosinophils produce IL-4 in injured livers. Expression of huCD2 on eosinophils (Siglec F + CD11b + ) 2 d after PH (C) or CCl4-induced injury (D) in KN2 mice. Isotype, gray histogram; huCD2, blue histogram. (E) GFP + cells localize in proximity to proliferating hepatocytes (Ki67 + ) 2 d after injury with CCl 4 (Upper) or PH (Lower). (F) Liver sections stained for BrdU 36 h after partial hepatectomy. Representative images of WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-are shown. (G) Liver regeneration in WT and IL-4/ IL-13 -/-mice was assessed by BrdU incorporation at indicated times after PH (n = 4-9 mice per genotype per time). (H) Representative liver sections from WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice were stained for K i 67 2 d after administration of CCl 4 . (I) Percentage of Ki67 + hepatocytes in WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice 2 d after CCl 4 treatment (n = 5 mice per genotype). *P &lt; 0.05, **P &lt; 0.01, ***P &lt; 0.001. All data are presented as mean ± SEM.</figDesc><graphic coords="3,469.49,312.93,68.43,98.42" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. IL-4/IL-13 signaling promotes cell cycle progression after liver injury. (A) Global gene expression analysis of WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-livers was performed 2 d after injury with CCl 4 . Gene ontology (GO) terms associated with cell cycle and mitosis are enriched among the differentially expressed genes. (B) Heat map presentation of differentially expressed genes in livers of WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice 2 d after injury with CCl 4 (red, high; green, low). (C) Quantitative RT-PCR analysis of genes associated with hepatocyte proliferation and liver regeneration. mRNAs from WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-mice were analyzed 2 d after injury with CCl 4 (n = 3-5 per genotype and treatment). (D) Western blot analysis of FoxM1 in WT and IL-4/IL-13 -/-livers. (E) Quantitative RT-PCR analysis of genes associated with hepatocyte proliferation in WT and ΔdblGATA mice was performed 2 d after PH (n = 5-8 per genotype and treatment). *P &lt; 0.05, **P &lt; 0.01, ***P &lt; 0.001. All data are presented as mean ± SEM.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. IL-4 stimulates hepatocyte proliferation in a cell-autonomous manner. (A and B) IL4Rα signaling in myeloid cells is not required for liver regeneration. (A) Liver regeneration in IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L LysM Cre mice was assessed by BrdU incorporation at 36 h after PH (n = 3-5 mice per genotype). (B) Quantification of necrotic area in IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L LysM Cre mice 2 d after administration of CCl 4 (n = 4-5 per genotype). (C) Immunoblot analyses of IL-4/IL-13 signaling receptors in primary hepatocytes. (D and E) IL4Rα signaling in hepatocytes is required for liver regeneration after injury. (D) BrdU incorporation in IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre mice was assessed 36 h after PH (n = 6-7 mice per genotype). (E) Quantification of Ki67 + hepatocytes in IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre mice 2 d after administration of CCl 4 (n = 5-7 mice per genotype). (F-K) Stimulation with IL-4 promotes hepatocyte proliferation in vitro and in vivo. (F) 3 H-thymidine incorporation in primary hepatocytes after in vitro stimulation with IL-4. Data are representative of 2 independent experiments. (G) Quantitative RT-PCR analysis of genes associated with hepatocyte proliferation in primary hepatocytes stimulated with Veh or IL-4 for 48 h (n = 3 per genotype and treatment). (H) WT C57BL/6J mice were injected with Veh or IL-4 for 5 d, and hepatocyte proliferation was quantified by K i 67 positivity (n = 5-6 per treatment group). (I) Representative sections showing staining for K i 67 in livers of mice treated with Veh or IL-4. (J) Quantitative RT-PCR analysis of genes associated with hepatocyte proliferation and liver growth in WT mice treated with Veh and IL-4. (K) Immunoblot analysis of FoxM1 expression in livers of mice treated with Veh or IL-4. (L) Mitogenic actions of IL-4 in IL4Rα L/L and IL4Rα L/L Alb Cre mice. Ki67 + hepatocytes were quantified in Veh or IL-4-treated mice (n = 5 mice per genotype and treatment). (M-O) Treatment with IL-4 protects mice from CCl 4 -induced liver injury. (M) Schematic for dosing of IL-4 to mice administered CCl 4 . (N) Percentage of Ki67 + hepatocytes in Veh and IL-4-treated mice 3 d after CCl 4 administration (n = 4 per treatment group). (O) Quantification of necrotic area in Veh and IL-4-treated mice 3 d after CCl 4 -induced injury (n = 4-5 mice per treatment group). *P &lt; 0.05, **P &lt; 0.01, ***P &lt; 0.001. All data are presented as mean ± SEM.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and caudate lobes. For the sham-operated controls, the liver was exteriorized through a midline incision and then subsequently put back into the peritoneal cavity. Acute liver injury was performed by a single i.p. injection of CCl 4 (0.4 mg/g, Sigma) suspended in olive oil. To block integrinmediated migration of eosinophils, mice were given an i.v. injection of isotype control antibody (100 μg) or anti-αL (100 μg, M17/4, UCSF Monoclonal Antibody Core) and anti-α4 (100 μg, PS/2) 24 h before initiation of injury and every 24 h thereafter until harvest. To quantify the number of proliferating hepatocytes, animals were given an i.p. injection of BrdU (100 mg/kg, Sigma) 2 h before euthanasia. For IL-4 treatment studies, mice were injected intraperitoneally for 5 consecutive days with 2 μg IL-4 (Peprotech) complexed with 10 μg anti-IL-4 antibody (BD Biosciences, BV-1B11). To evaluate the protective effects of IL-4 on CCl 4 -induced liver injury, mice were administered 2 μg IL-4 complexed with 10 μg anti-IL-4 antibody 1 d before and 2 d after injection of CCl 4 . Hepatic regenerative response were quantified 3 d after administration of CCl 4 . All animal care and procedures were performed in accordance with Stanford University's Administrative Panel on Laboratory Animal Care and the University of California San Francisco's Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee guidelines.Immunohistochemistry and Immunoblotting. For immunohistochemical studies, livers were fixed in neutral-buffered formalin and methacarn and embedded in paraffin. Tissues were sectioned at 5 μm, stained with H&amp;E or anti-BrdU (1:40; Dako M0744). To determine the percentage of BrdU + hepatocytes (labeling index), 2,000-2,500 nuclei were counted per animal in 10 random fields.</figDesc><table /><note><p>9918 | www.pnas.org/cgi/doi/10.1073/pnas.1304046110 Goh et al. right</p></note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>Downloaded from https://www.pnas.org by 147.161.165.28 on March 4, 2025 from IP address 147.161.165.28.</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><p>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. We thank members of the <rs type="institution">A.C. laboratory</rs> and <rs type="person">A. Loh</rs> for comments on the manuscript. This work was supported by Grants <rs type="grantNumber">DK076760</rs> and <rs type="grantNumber">DK081405</rs> and <rs type="funder">National Institutes of Health Director's Pioneer</rs> Award <rs type="grantNumber">DP1AR064158</rs> (to A.C.). Y.P.G. was supported by <rs type="funder">Agency for Science, Technology and Research National Science Scholarship</rs>, <rs type="grantName">Stanford Graduate Fellowship</rs> supported K.D.N., and N.C.H. was supported by a <rs type="funder">Wellcome Trust</rs> <rs type="grantName">Intermediate Clinical Fellowship</rs> (ref. <rs type="grantNumber">085187</rs>).</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_hP9Ez5s">
					<idno type="grant-number">DK076760</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_CYVUwyw">
					<idno type="grant-number">DK081405</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_Z5k3CPB">
					<idno type="grant-number">DP1AR064158</idno>
					<orgName type="grant-name">Stanford Graduate Fellowship</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_2afxsdn">
					<idno type="grant-number">085187</idno>
					<orgName type="grant-name">Intermediate Clinical Fellowship</orgName>
				</org>
			</listOrg>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liver regeneration after partial hepatectomy: critical analysis of mechanistic dilemmas</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Michalopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Am J Pathol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">176</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liver regeneration: From myth to mechanism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Taub</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="836" to="847" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental pathology of the liver. I. Restoration of the liver of the white rat following partial surgical removal</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Arch Pathol (Chic)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="186" to="202" />
			<date type="published" when="1931">1931</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Liver regeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Michalopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Defrances</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">276</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5309</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nuclear receptor-dependent bile acid signaling is required for normal liver regeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">312</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5771</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Advances in signaling in vertebrate regeneration as a prelude to regenerative medicine</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stoick-Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Moon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Weidinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Genes Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1315" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of Th2 immunity: a rapid repair response to tissue destructive pathogens</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS Pathog</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1002003</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Allergic host defences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Palm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Rosenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Medzhitov</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">484</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7395</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="465" to="472" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eosinophils: Changing perspectives in health and disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Rosenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Foster</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The eosinophil</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rothenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Hogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="147" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Type 2 innate signals stimulate fibro/adipogenic progenitors to facilitate muscle regeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Heredia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">153</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="376" to="388" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative activation is an innate response to injury that requires CD4+ T cells to be sustained during chronic infection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Loke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">179</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3926" to="3936" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nodular regenerative hyperplasia of the liver in idiopathic hypereosinophilic syndrome</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Axiotis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hurwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Leavitt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Di</forename><surname>Bisceglie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Clin Gastroenterol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="452" to="456" />
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Changes in the content of eosinophils, corticosterone and catecholamines during liver regeneration following resection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Malyshev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Treshchuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Popova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978">1978</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biull Eksp Biol Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="663" to="664" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eosinophils sustain adipose alternatively activated macrophages associated with glucose homeostasis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">332</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6026</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="243" to="247" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Targeted deletion of a high-affinity GATA-binding site in the GATA-1 promoter leads to selective loss of the eosinophil lineage in vivo</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Exp Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">195</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1387" to="1395" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A reproducible and well-tolerated method for 2/3 partial hepatectomy in mice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Willenbring</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Protoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1167" to="1170" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Galectin-3 regulates myofibroblast activation and hepatic fibrosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Henderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">103</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5060" to="5065" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Protective and pathogenic functions of macrophage subsets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Murray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="723" to="737" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Protective immune mechanisms in helminth infection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Anthony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Rutitzky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jr</forename><surname>Stadecker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="975" to="987" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An essential role for TH2-type responses in limiting acute tissue damage during experimental helminth infection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="260" to="266" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of type 2 immunity in vivo with a bicistronic IL-4 reporter</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mohrs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Shinkai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mohrs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Locksley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Immunity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="303" to="311" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A complement-IL-4 regulatory circuit controls liver regeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Deangelis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">188</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="648" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A two-step process for cytokine production revealed by IL-4 dual-reporter mice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Mohrs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Wakil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Killeen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Locksley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Mohrs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Immunity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="419" to="429" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interleukin-4-and interleukin-13-mediated host protection against intestinal nematode parasites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Finkelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Immunol Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">201</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative activation of macrophages: an immunologic functional perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Helming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="451" to="483" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systematic and integrative analysis of large gene lists using DAVID bioinformatics resources</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lempicki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Protoc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="57" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Forkhead Box m1b transcription factor is essential for hepatocyte DNA replication and mitosis during mouse liver regeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Kiyokawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Dennewitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Costa</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Natl Acad Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16881" to="16886" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative activation of macrophages</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat Rev Immunol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="35" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative macrophage activation is essential for survival during schistosomiasis and downmodulates T helper 1 responses and immunopathology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Herbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Immunity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="623" to="635" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternatively activated macrophages produce catecholamines to sustain adaptive thermogenesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">480</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7375</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="104" to="108" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disease tolerance as a defense strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Medzhitov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Soares</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">335</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6071</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="936" to="941" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Macrophage-specific PPARgamma controls alternative activation and improves insulin resistance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Odegaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">447</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7148</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1116" to="1120" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative M2 activation of Kupffer cells by PPARdelta ameliorates obesity-induced insulin resistance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Odegaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell Metab</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="496" to="507" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
