<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Yap is a novel regulator of C2C12 myogenesis</title>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Oliver Bird Rheumatism Programme</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder>
					<orgName type="full">Medical Research Council, UK</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability  status="unknown">
					<licence/>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2010-02-10">10 February 2010</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Watt</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Molecular Exercise Physiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Judson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Molecular Exercise Physiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Medlow</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Sports and Exercise Research Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Ulster</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Shore Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>BT37 0QB</postCode>
									<settlement>Newtonabby</settlement>
									<region>Country Antrim</region>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kenneth</forename><surname>Reid</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Molecular Exercise Physiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tobias</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Kurth</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Regenerative Medicine</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jatin</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Burniston</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Liverpool John Moores University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Henry Cotton Campus 15-21 Webster Street</addrLine>
									<postCode>L3 2ET</postCode>
									<settlement>Liverpool</settlement>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Aivaras</forename><surname>Ratkevicius</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Molecular Exercise Physiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Cosimo</forename><surname>De Bari</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Regenerative Medicine</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Wackerhage</surname></persName>
							<email>h.wackerhage@abdn.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Bone &amp; Musculoskeletal Research Programme</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Medical Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Molecular Exercise Physiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aberdeen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Health Sciences Building</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Aber- deen</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Foresterhill</addrLine>
									<postCode>AB25 2ZD</postCode>
									<settlement>Aberdeen</settlement>
									<country>Scotland United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Yap is a novel regulator of C2C12 myogenesis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="2010-02-10">10 February 2010</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">B2F9A45F78A214D161D32FB9C874E7B9</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.bbrc.2010.02.034</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received 5 February 2010</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.2-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2025-03-14T13:51+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>Skeletal muscle Myogenesis C2C12 Hippo pathway Yap</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The expression, regulation and function of mammalian Hippo pathway members in skeletal muscle is largely unknown. The aim of this study was thus to test the hypothesis that core members of the mammalian Hippo pathway are expressed in skeletal muscle and that the transcriptional co-factor Yap, a core member of the Hippo pathway, regulates C2C12 myogenesis. We found that the major components of the mammalian Hippo pathway including Yap are all expressed in skeletal muscles, C2C12 myoblasts and myotubes. In C2C12 myoblasts, Yap Ser127 phosphorylation is low and Yap localises to nuclei. Upon differentiation, Yap Ser127 phosphorylation increases %20-fold and Yap translocates from the nucleus to the cytosol. To test whether the observed increase of Yap Ser127 phosphorylation is required for differentiation we overexpressed hYAP1 S127A, a mutant that can not be phosphorylated at Ser127, in C2C12 myoblasts. We found that overexpression of hYAP S127A prevented myotube formation, whereas the overexpression of wildtype hYAP1 or empty vector had no effect. In addition, more hYAP1 S127A overexpressing cells progressed through the S phase of the cell cycle and the expression of MRFs (myogenin, Myf5), Mef2c and cell cycle regulators (p21, cyclin D1) was significantly changed when compared to wildtype hYAP1 and empty vector overexpressing cells. This data suggests that the phosphorylation of Yap at Ser127 leads to a changed expression of MRFs and cell cycle regulators and is required for C2C12 myoblasts to differentiate into myotubes.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>During myogenesis precursor cells first commit to the myogenic lineage in a process known as determination before withdrawing from the cell cycle and differentiating to form multinucleated muscle fibres <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Myogenic regulation also plays a role postnatally in satellite cells during repair from muscle injury and in response to resistance exercise <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Myogenesis is regulated by a plethora of transcription factors and signal transduction pathways. The myogenic regulatory factor (MRF) family of transcription factors (Myf5, MyoD, Mrf4 and myogenin) are major transcriptional regulators of myogenesis <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>. Previous studies using knock out mice have shown that MyoD, Mrf4 and Myf5 regulate myogenic determination, whereas myogenin, MyoD and Mrf4 regulate the terminal differentiation of myoblasts <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4]</ref>. The myocyte enhancer factor 2 (MEF2) family of transcription factors can also regulate myogenesis by physically interacting with and by inducing the expression of MRF and other muscle-specific genes <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The aforementioned transcription factors and other cell functions during myogenesis are additionally regulated by signalling pathways such as the mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK), mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), sonic hedgehog, Notch, transforming growth factor beta (TGFb Smad (from Sma and mothers against DPP homologue) and wingless (Wnt) signalling pathways <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">7]</ref>.</p><p>The Hippo signal transduction pathway is a pathway whose regulation and function has not yet been studied in skeletal muscle. It 0006-291X/$ -see front matter Ó 2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved. doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2010.02.034</p><p>Abbreviations: bHLH, helix-loop-helix transcription factors; cdk, cyclin dependent kinase; DMEM, Dulbecco's modified Eagle's medium; Frmd6, FIRM domain containing 6; IdU, iododeoxyuridine; LAP, liver associated protein; Lats1/2, large tumour suppressor kinase; MEF2, myocyte enhancer factor 2; MRF, myogenic regulatory factors; Mrf4, myogenic regulatory factor 4; Mst1/2, mammalian Ste20like kinase; mTOR, mammalian target of rapamycin; Myf5, myogenic factor 5; MyHC, myosin heavy chain; MyoD, myogenic determination factor D; Nf2, neurofibromatosis 2; Pax, paired box; p38, p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase; Smad, from Sma and mothers against DPP homologue; TGFb, transforming growth factor beta; Wnt, from Wg (wingless) and Int; Yap, yes-associated protein (hYAP indicates human YAP, whereas Yap indicates Yap in other species) controls events such as proliferation, apoptosis, differentiation, organ size and tumorigenesis in Drosophila melanogaster and some mammalian tissues <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref>. A kinase cascade forms the core of the Hippo pathway: Mammalian Ste20-like 1/2 kinase (Mst1/2) first phosphorylates large tumour suppressor 1/2 kinase (Lats1/2) which in turn phosphorylates the transcriptional co-activator Yes-associated protein (Yap) at five serine residues <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. The key residue Ser127 is part of a conserved 14-3-3 binding motif <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> and phosphorylation of Ser127 causes 14-3-3 proteins to sequester Yap in the cytosol <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref>, whereas unphosphorylated Yap localises to the nucleus <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>.</p><p>More recent studies have begun to characterise the function of Yap in vertebrates and mammals in vivo. Conditional overexpression of human YAP (hYAP) isoforms under the control of a liver-specific promoter led to a 4-5-fold increase in liver size due to increased proliferation <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15]</ref>. Overexpression of constitutively active hYAP S127A expanded multipotent progenitor cells in the crypt compartment of the intestine and these cells could not undergo terminal differentiation until hYAP1 S127A overexpression was stopped <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. In the chick neural tube Yap overexpression similarly stimulated proliferation but inhibited differentiation of neural progenitor cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>.</p><p>Taken together these results suggest that the Hippo pathway can regulate the proliferation and terminal differentiation of cells in several tissues and organs which is relevant for their development, repair and size. Little is known about the expression, regulation and function of Hippo pathway members in skeletal muscle cells. The aim of this study was thus to examine the expression of core members of the Hippo pathway in skeletal muscle and to investigate the regulation and function of the transcriptional cofactor Yap during C2C12 myogenesis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Materials and methods</head><p>Chemicals and materials. All chemicals and materials were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich, Poole, United Kingdom unless otherwise indicated.</p><p>C2C12 cell culture. C2C12 myoblasts (Health Protection Agency Culture Collections, Salisbury, United Kingdom) were cultured in growth medium (Dulbecco's modified Eagle's medium (DMEM) with 4 mM glutamine and 10% vol/vol foetal calf serum). At %90% confluency, medium was changed to differentiation medium (DMEM, 4 mM glutamine and 2% vol/vol horse serum) to induce differentiation. Cells were maintained in differentiation medium for up to 96 h.</p><p>Protein extraction and Western blotting. Gastrocnemius, tibialis anterior and soleus muscles were excised from C57BL/6 mice and suspended in lysis buffer (50 mM Tris-HCl, 1 mM EDTA, 1 mM EGTA, 1% vol/vol Triton X-100, pH 7.5) supplemented with protease inhibitor cocktail, 10 mM b-glycerophosphate, 50 mM NaF and 0.5 mM sodium orthovanadate. C2C12 cells were washed in ice-cold PBS and lysed in lysis buffer. Skeletal muscles and C2C12 lysates were homogenised on ice and then centrifuged at 13,000g for 10 min. The protein concentration was measured using a bicinchoninic acid assay kit (Thermo Fisher Scientific, Northumberland, United Kingdom). The supernatant was then diluted in 3Â Laemmli SDS buffer and heated for 5 min at 95 °C.</p><p>For Western blotting, protein extracts were separated on 10-12% SDS-PAGE gels and then transferred to PVDF membranes. Membranes were blocked with 5% vol/vol skimmed milk powder in Tris buffered saline supplemented with 0.1% Tween-20 and incubated overnight with primary antibodies, followed by HRPconjugated goat anti-rabbit or goat anti-mouse secondary antibodies (1:2000; Cell Signaling Technologies, Massachusetts, USA), before detection using enhanced chemiluminescence (ECL) detection reagent (Amersham Biosciences, Buckinghamshire, United Kingdom). Primary antibodies for the detection of phosphorylated Yap Ser127 (1:1000; #4911) and b-actin (1:1000; #4967) were from Cell Signaling Technologies and the antibody for total Yap (1:500; #sc-15407) was from Santa Cruz (California, USA).</p><p>RNA extraction, end point and real-time reverse transcriptase PCR. Total RNA was extracted from organs of a male, 4 month old C57BL/6 mouse or C2C12 cells using TRIzol according to the manufacturers protocol (Invitrogen, Paisley, UK) and purified using a RNeasy Ò minikit (Qiagen, Sussex, UK). Reverse transcription was performed using 2 lg of RNA with the Superscript II Ò reverse transcriptase kit (Invitrogen) and random primers (Invitrogen) according to the manufacturers recommendation.</p><p>End point PCR was performed over 35 cycles of denaturation (95 °C for 30 s), annealing (55-65 °C for 45 s) and extension (72 °C for 30 s), using oligonucleotides (Sigma-Aldrich) for Frmd6, Nf2, ww45, Mst1, Mst2, Mob1, Lats1, Lats2 and Yap (primer sequences are listed in the Supplementary data in Table <ref type="table">S1</ref>). Post PCR products were visualised using ethidium bromide electrophoresis. Quantitative RT-PCR was performed on a Roche Lightcycler 480 (Roche, Hertfordshire, UK). PCR primers (Sigma-Aldrich) and Taqman fluorogenic probes were designed for hYAP and mouse p21, CyclinD1, Myf5, myogenin, Mef2c, dysferlin, dystrophin and muscle creatine kinase (primer sequences are listed in the Supplementary data in Table <ref type="table">S2</ref>) using the Roche Universal Probe Library. Following an initial denaturation step of 95 °C for 5 min, quantitative RT-PCR was performed over 45 cycles of 95 °C for 10 s and 60 °C for 30 s. All quantification of mRNA was normalised to mouse Gapdh (Applied Biosystems, California, USA) as an internal control using multiplexing assays. Quantification was corrected for efficiency by use of a standard curve created by the serial dilution of cDNA.</p><p>Transfection of C2C12 cells with YAP plasmids. DNA plasmids that encode wildtype human YAP1 (hYAP1) or a mutant protein that can no longer be phosphorylated at Ser127 (hYAP1 S127A) were obtained from Addgene (www.addgene.org) deposited by the lab of Dr. Marius Sudol (Geisinger Clinic, USA). The hYAP1 isoform used contains one WW domain. C2C12 myoblasts were seeded at 150,000 per well of a six well plate and transfected using Lipofectamine 2000 (Invitrogen) following the manufacturer's instructions. Empty vector plasmids were used as negative controls. Upon confluency cells were differentiated as described for up to 96 h. treatment and time) and a Bonferroni post hoc analysis. Quantified results of the data presented in Figs. 3D and S1a, 2 in the Supplementary data were analysed using a one factorial ANOVA and a Bonferroni post hoc analysis. p &lt; 0.05 was considered significant for all analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>We first tested whether core members of the Hippo pathway are expressed in C2C12 myoblasts, myotubes and mouse skeletal muscles. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1A</ref> shows that core components of the mammalian Hippo pathway are ubiquitously expressed in all tissues studied at the mRNA level. Figs. 1B and 2A additionally show that the transcriptional co-factor Yap, a core member of the Hippo pathway, and Yap phosphorylated at Ser127 are detectable in mouse skeletal muscles, C2C12 myoblasts and myotubes as proteins.</p><p>After determining the expression of Hippo pathway members in skeletal muscle we examined the regulation and function of Yap. We first monitored the localisation and phosphorylation of Yap at Ser127 during myogenesis for which we used the C2C12 mouse myoblast cell line as an in vitro model (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>). During C2C12 myogenesis, myoblasts first proliferate to confluency, withdraw from the cell cycle and then differentiate into myotubes upon a shift to differentiation medium containing lower concentrations of mitogens. We found that Yap Ser127 phosphorylation is low in myoblasts but after 24 h in differentiation medium Ser127 phosphorylation is %20-fold increased and after 96 h it is %28-fold higher than in myoblasts, respectively (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2A</ref>, see also Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">S1a</ref> in the Supplementary data for a quantification). Changes in the phosphorylation of Yap during differentiation are accompanied by the gradual translocation of Yap from distinct loci in the nucleus of myoblasts to the cytoplasm of myotubes (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2B</ref>; see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S2b</ref> in the Supplementary data for additional images).</p><p>To test whether the observed increase of Yap Ser127 phosphorylation is required for C2C12 differentiation we overexpressed hYAP1 S127A in C2C12 myoblasts and induced differentiation by a change to differentiation medium. The hYAP1 S127A mutant can not be phosphorylated at residue Ser127 allowing us to increase the concentration of unphosphorylated Yap at a time when Ser127 phosphorylation of endogenous Yap would normally be increased %20-fold or more and when the concentration of unphosphorylated Yap would consequently be decreased. Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> shows that cells transfected with wildtype hYAP1 and empty vector differentiate as normal, forming multinucleated myotubes that are positive for myosin heavy chain. In contrast, hYAP1 S127A overexpressing cells do not form myotubes and are negative for myosin heavy chain (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3A</ref> and<ref type="figure">C</ref>). hYAP1 S127 overexpression also increases the percentage of IdU positive nuclei after 48 h of differentiation by %3-fold (15.1 ± 1.3%) compared to cells transfected with wildtype hYAP1 (5.2 ± 0.9%) and empty vector (5.3 ± 0.6%; Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3D</ref>; p &lt; 0.05). IdU incorporation into nuclei marks cells that have progressed through the S phase of the cell cycle suggesting that hYAP1 S127A overexpression increases the proportion of cells within the cell cycle. Furthermore, the expression of the terminal differentiation markers dysferlin, muscle creatine kinase, and dystrophin was significantly lower by 79 ± 4.0%, 52 ± 4.2% and 96 ± 1.6% in cells that were transfected with hYAP1 S127A compared to empty vector transfected cells, respectively (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S2</ref> for the full data set, Supplementary data; these results were obtained using quantitative RT-PCR). These findings suggest that phosphorylation of Yap at Ser127 is essential for cell cycle withdrawal, the expression of late differentiation markers and differentiation of C2C12 myoblasts into myotubes.</p><p>We next aimed to identify regulatory genes whose expression is directly or indirectly dependent on Yap phosphorylation. For this we analysed the expression of myogenic transcription factors Myf5, myogenin and Mef2c and the cell cycle regulators p21 and  cyclinD1 during 0-48 h of differentiation in C2C12 myoblasts transfected with hYAP1 S127A, wildtype hYAP and empty vector (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4</ref>; see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">S3</ref> in the Supplementary data for the levels of hYAP construct expression). We found that the expression of Myf5 and cyclinD1 remained significantly elevated upon induction of differentiation in cells that were overexpressing hYAP1 S127A compared to cells transfected with wildtype hYAP and empty vector (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4C</ref> and<ref type="figure">D</ref>). Furthermore, the expression of key myogenic differentiation transcription factors myogenin, Mef2c and the cell cycle inhibitor p21 were significantly decreased at all time points in cells transfected with hYAP S127A when compared to controls (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4A, B</ref> and<ref type="figure">E</ref>; note that there was no significant difference for myogenin between empty vector and hYAP1 S127A at 0 h).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>The organ-specific expression of members of the mammalian Hippo pathway has been previously demonstrated for individual genes such as Yap <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>. The data presented here (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>) extends these findings and provides a more detailed overview of the mRNA expression of the core mammalian Hippo pathway genes. All the major genes of the Hippo pathway are expressed in adult skeletal muscles with both a faster (tibialis anterior, gastronemius) and slower (soleus, diaphragm) phenotype as well as in C2C12 myoblasts and myotubes (Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> and<ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2A</ref>). The expression of the Hippo pathway in skeletal muscle suggests that the pathway may have a function in this tissue. As Yap has previously been reported to promote proliferation and inhibit differentiation of neural <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> and intestine progenitors <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> we decided to study Yap during C2C12 myogenesis in order to test whether it had a similar function in skeletal muscle.</p><p>At the onset of C2C12 differentiation Yap Ser127 phosphorylation increased %20-fold and Yap increasingly translocates from the nucleus to the cytosol (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>). The likely mechanism is that the Yap Ser127 residue is phosphorylated by Lats1/2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19]</ref> and that Ser127 phosphorylated Yap is then sequestered by 14-3-3 binding proteins in the cytosol <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Our data suggest that Yap Ser127 phosphorylation is an essential differentiation event because the overexpression of a hYAP1 S127A mutant, which can not be phosphorylated at residue 127, prevents myotube formation and the expression of late differentiation markers (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> and Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">S2</ref> in Supplementary data). The effect of overexpressing hYAP1 S127A is similar in C2C12 cells than in neural <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> and intestine progenitor cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> because hYAP1 S127A prevents differentiation in all three cell types. hYAP1 S127A overexpression also increases the percentage of proliferating myoblasts (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3D</ref>) which is again similar to the effect observed in both neural and intestine progenitors <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>. These data suggest that unphosphorylated Yap promotes the proliferation but inhibits the differentiation of progenitor cells in several tissues. Yap functions as a transcriptional co-activator and has been reported to bind to at least ten transcription factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Thus the observed Yap translocation to the cytosol (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2B</ref>) implies that Yap can at that stage no longer co-regulate nuclear transcription factors and the genes that depend on such regulation. To identify genes via which hYAP1 S127A overexpression might directly or indirectly prevent cell cycle withdrawal and differentiation, we measured the expression of known MRF and cell cycle regulators in hYAP1 S127A, wildtype hYAP1 or empty vector transfected cells from 0 to 48 h after the onset of differentiation. This time window represents a critical period where key cell cycle and myogenic regulators change their expression during C2C12 differentiation <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>.</p><p>We found that hYAP1 S127A overexpression significantly reduced the expression of myogenin and Mef2c compared to controls (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4A</ref> and<ref type="figure">B</ref>). This finding is consistent with an inhibition of differentiation because an upregulation of these genes is required for the differentiation of both C2C12 cells <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and skeletal muscle in mice <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21]</ref>. In contrast, hYAP1 S127A overexpression significantly increased Myf5 expression especially at 48 h (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4C</ref>). Myf5 is regulated in a cell cycle specific fashion in C2C12 myoblasts <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> and has been shown to promote myoblast proliferation <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. Thus the increase of Myf5 is consistent with the hypothesis that hYAP1 S127A prevents cell cycle withdrawal. The elevated expression of cyclin D1 and decreased expression of p21 in hYAP1 S127A overexpressing cells (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4D</ref> and<ref type="figure">E</ref>) is equally consistent with the hypothesis that hYAP1 S127A prevents cell cycle withdrawal because cyclin D1 promotes G1-S phase cell cycle progression, whereas p21 promotes cell cycle withdrawal <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>. Cyclin D1 expression is also dependent on Yap in neural and intestine progenitors <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref>, showing that Yap can regulate the same gene in different tissues. Taken together, these data suggest that the %20-fold increase in Yap Ser127 phosphorylation at the onset of differentiation affects the expression of MRF and cell cycle regulators in a way that allows differentiation to proceed. In contrast, if hYAP1 S127A is overexpressed cell cycle withdrawal and differentiation are inhibited.</p><p>To summarise, all of the identified members of the core mammalian Hippo pathway are expressed in skeletal muscle in vitro and in vivo. Yap is unphosphorylated and localises to the nucleus in C2C12 myoblasts. At the onset of differentiation Yap becomes phosphorylated at Ser127 and translocates from the nucleus to the cytoplasm. Ser127 phosphorylation is required for terminal differentiation of C2C12 cells because if the concentration of Yap that can not be phosphorylated at Ser127 is increased by overexpressing a hYAP1 S127A mutant then myoblasts withdraw less from the cell cycle and do not differentiate into myotubes (see Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">S4</ref> for a schematic drawing). We therefore identify Yap as a novel regulator of C2C12 myogenesis.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Core components of the mammalian Hippo pathway including Yap are ubiquitously expressed in a range of mouse tissues including skeletal muscle. (A) mRNA expression using RT-PCR of mammalian Hippo pathway members in a range of mouse tissues from a 4 month old C57BL/6 male mouse and in C2C12 myotubes. Firm domain containing protein 6 (Frmd6) and neurofibromatosis 2 (Nf2) are thought represent the mammalian homologues of Merlin and Expanded, two upstream Hippo pathway proteins identified in Drosophila melanogaster. ww45 and Mob1 are proteins that have been proposed to interact with the Mst1/2 and Lats1/2 kinases in mammals. The primers used to amplify Yap amplify all isoforms because they do not not flank the WW domains of Yap. (B) Yap and Yap that is phosphorylated at Ser127 protein compared to b-actin in three different mouse skeletal muscles. Image is representative of two further independent replicates.</figDesc><graphic coords="2,306.71,313.57,241.30,330.86" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. Yap Ser127 phosphorylation increases during C2C12 myogenesis and translocates from the nucleus to the cytoplasm. (A) Levels of Yap phosphorylated at Ser127, total Yap and b-actin throughout C2C12 myogenesis. Image is representative of two further independent replicates; the statistical analysis and quantification is shown in Fig. S1b. (B) Localisation of total Yap (red) in subconfluent C2C12 myoblasts (upper left image) cultured in growth medium for 24 h and in C2C12 myotubes (upper right image) after 96 h of differentiation. Isotype negative controls for each time point are also shown (lower images). Nuclei counterstained with DAPI (blue). White lines represent 20 lm. (For interpretation of colour mentioned in this figure, the reader is referred to the web version of this article.)</figDesc><graphic coords="3,147.40,345.66,310.45,358.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3. Overexpression of hYAP1 S127A impairs C2C12 differentiation. (A) Phase contrast images of cells that were transfected either with empty vector, wildtype hYAP1 or hYAP1 S127A and differentiated for 96 h. Images were taken at 200 times magnification, inserts show magnified detail (white bars are proportionally enlarged). Images representative of two further independent replicates. (B) Levels of Flag, total Yap and b-actin in the cells transfected with empty vector, wildtype hYAP1 or hYAP1 S127A and differentiated for 96 h. (C) Total myosin heavy chain (green) with nuclear DAPI counterstain (blue) in cells transfected with empty vector, wildtype hYAP1 or hYAP1 S127A and differentiated for 96 h. Isotype negative controls for each condition are also shown. White lines represent 100 lm.</figDesc><graphic coords="4,305.24,67.92,243.98,506.61" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(D) Representative images for cells that were either in or progressed through the S phase of the cell cycle as indicated by IdU labelling (red) after 48 h in differentiation medium. Nuclei were counterstained with DAPI (blue). Isotype negative controls for each condition are also shown. White lines represent 100 lm. (For interpretation of colour mentioned in this figure, the reader is referred to the web version of this article.)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig. 4. hYAP1 S127A changes the expression of the MRFs, MEFs and cell cycle regulators. (A) Myogenin expression; (B) Mef2c expression; (C) Myf5 expression; (D) Cyclin D1 expression; p21 expression (E). Data normalised to the value for the empty vector transfected cells at 0 h and are expressed as a fold change relative to this. These results were obtained using quantitative RT-PCR. * Significantly different from hYAP1 S127A transfected cells (p &lt; 0.05).</figDesc><graphic coords="5,144.57,67.92,313.69,371.91" type="bitmap" /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>K.I. Watt et al. / Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications 393 (2010) 619-624</p></note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_1"><p>K.I. Watt et al. / Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications 393 (2010) 619-624</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>We are indebted to <rs type="person">Dr. Marius Sudol</rs>, who created the DNA constructs used in this study and made them available via Addgene. We thank technicians <rs type="person">Denise Tosh</rs> and <rs type="person">Patricia Crombie</rs> for supporting these experiments. <rs type="person">Robert Judson</rs> was funded by the <rs type="funder">Oliver Bird Rheumatism Programme</rs>. <rs type="person">Prof. De Bari</rs> is a Fellow of the <rs type="funder">Medical Research Council, UK</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
			</listOrg>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Appendix A. Supplementary data</head><p>Supplementary data associated with this article can be found, in the online version, at doi:10.1016/j.bbrc.2010.02.034.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The formation of skeletal muscle: from somite to limb</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Buckingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Bajard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Daubas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hadchouel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Meilhac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Montarras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Rocancourt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Relaix</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Anat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">202</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="68" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The behaviour of satellite cells in response to exercise: what have we learned from human studies?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Kadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Charifi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Denis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lexell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Schjerling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Olsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kjaer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pflugers Arch</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">451</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="327" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Targeted inactivation of myogenic factor genes reveals their role during mouse myogenesis: a review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Arnold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Dev. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="345" to="353" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regulatory mechanisms that coordinate skeletal muscle differentiation and cell cycle withdrawal</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lassar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">X</forename><surname>Skapek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Novitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Cell Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="788" to="794" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combinatorial control of muscle development by basic helix-loop-helix and MADS-box transcription factors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Molkentin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9366" to="9373" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stress-activated protein kinase-2/p38 and a rapamycinsensitive pathway are required for C2C12 myogenesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Cuenda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Biol. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">274</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4341" to="4346" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distinct and dynamic myogenic populations in the vertebrate embryo</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Buckingham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Vincent</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Opin. Genet. Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="444" to="453" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Salvador-Warts-Hippo pathway -an emerging tumour-suppressor network</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Tapon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Rev. Cancer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="182" to="191" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hippo signaling in organ size control</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Genes Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="886" to="897" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tumor suppressor LATS1 is a negative regulator of oncogene YAP</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Hao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Chun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Cheung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Rashidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Biol. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">283</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5496" to="5509" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">and Yorkie: a conserved family of signal-responsive transcriptional coregulators in animal development and human disease</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Degerny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Yap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Taz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biochem. Cell Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Akt phosphorylates the Yes-associated protein, YAP, to induce interaction with 14-3-3 and attenuation of p73-mediated apoptosis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Totty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Irwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sudol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Downward</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mol. Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="11" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A coordinated phosphorylation by Lats and CK1 regulates YAP stability through SCF(beta-TRCP)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tumaneng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Guan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Genes Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Elucidation of a universal size-control mechanism in Drosophila and mammals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Feldmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Comerford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Gayyed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Anders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Maitra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">130</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1120" to="1133" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">YAP1 increases organ size and expands undifferentiated progenitor cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Camargo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gokhale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Johnnidis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jaenisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Brummelkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Curr. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2054" to="2060" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">YAP regulates neural progenitor cell number via the TEA domain transcription factor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Cao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Pfaff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Gage</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Genes Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3320" to="3334" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Characterization of the mammalian YAP (Yes-associated protein) gene and its role in defining a novel protein module, the WW domain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sudol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Bork</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Einbond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kastury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Druck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Negrini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Huebner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lehman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Biol. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">270</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14733" to="14741" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The transcriptional coactivator TAZ interacts differentially with transcriptional enhancer factor-1 (TEF-1) family members</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mahoney</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Yaffe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Farrance</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biochem. J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">388</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="225" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mst2 and Lats kinases regulate apoptotic function of Yes kinase-associated protein (YAP)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Oka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Mazack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sudol</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Biol. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">283</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27534" to="27546" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Expression profiling and identification of novel genes involved in myogenic differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Tomczak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Marinescu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Ramoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sanoudou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Montanaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Kunkel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kohane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Beggs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">FASEB J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="405" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regulation of skeletal muscle sarcomere integrity and postnatal muscle function by Mef2c</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Potthoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Arnold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcanally</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bassel-Duby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Olson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mol. Cell. Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="8143" to="8151" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The muscle regulatory factors MyoD and myf-5 undergo distinct cell cyclespecific expression in muscle cells</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kitzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Carnac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Vandromme</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Primig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Lamb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fernandez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Cell Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">142</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1447" to="1459" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MyoD induces myogenic differentiation through cooperation of its NH2-and COOH-terminal regions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ishibashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Perry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Asakura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Rudnicki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Cell Biol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">171</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="471" to="482" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Involvement of cdks and cyclins in muscle differentiation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>De Falco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Luca</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Eur. J. Histochem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
